<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<dataset id="wmttest2022">
  <collection id="biomedical-ref">
    <doc origlang="en" id="parallel">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Spontaneous hemoperitoneum in pregnancy is a rare complication resulting in high maternal and fetal morbidity and mortality.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Laparotomy revealed a hemoperitoneum resulting from a suspected ruptured varices on the uterine posterior surface.</seg>
          <seg id="3">A live newborn was delivered by cesarean-section, and hemorrhage was controlled with sutures and compression.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Clinicians should be aware of this diagnosis when a pregnant woman presents with abdominal pain, anemia or hypovolemic shock.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Early intervention will avoid poor outcomes for both the mother and the fetus.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Factors related to weight loss in obese patients undergoing bariatric surgery have always been exhaustively studied in an attempt to propose the best surgical technique with greater weight loss and long-term resolution of comorbidities.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Patients present anatomical variations regarding the length of the small intestine.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Some studies demonstrate weight changes in patients with different lengths of the intestinal loops in the Roux-en-Y bypass technique.</seg>
          <seg id="9">The present work carried out a study on the influence of body mass index, weight loss, and common loop length on long-term surgical outcomes.</seg>
          <seg id="10">This is a descriptive cross-sectional study by retrospective analysis of 112 medical records of patients undergoing open bariatric surgery using the gastric bypass technique at University Hospital - UFPR.</seg>
          <seg id="11">The data were correlated in statistical programs for this purpose.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Out of 112 patients, 83.03% were women, with mean age of 41.52 years.</seg>
          <seg id="13">The mean length of the total small bowel of the patients was 5.02 m. There was a directly proportional relationship between the length of the small intestine and weight loss (p=0.0428).</seg>
          <seg id="14">There is a wide range of variables related to weight loss in patients undergoing bariatric surgery, such as the technique used, the length of the loops in the Roux-en-Y gastric bypass, and the routine of nutritional and physical monitoring of the patient.</seg>
          <seg id="15">It is important to assess the technical details of the surgical procedure and to verify the weight loss by evaluating integrally the patient and other variables.</seg>
          <seg id="16">Eradicating modern slavery is a relevant scientific, social, and institutional challenge issue.</seg>
          <seg id="17">Indeed, efforts are being made globally to understand, map, and eradicate contemporary slavery as a target of the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals by 2030.</seg>
          <seg id="18">However, little attention has been given to the Occupational Health Surveillance (VISAT) in the strategies and struggle against exploiting relationships.</seg>
          <seg id="19">We initially highlight the link between CSL, occupational health, and occupational health surveillance (VISAT). We then present three VISAT challenges to addressing CSL: the challenging task of characterizing economic sectors and populations most affected; identifying determinants, risks, and effects on health; and strengthening occupational health practices and services to trigger specific actions regarding formation, information, and intervention in regions of high CSL prevalence.</seg>
          <seg id="20">We conclude that Occupational Health Surveillance can play an essential role in the emancipation of workers engaged in slavery relationships.</seg>
          <seg id="21">This study evaluated the role of social inequalities in complementary feeding patterns between and within countries in Latin America and the Caribbean.</seg>
          <seg id="22">This ecological study employed aggregate data from population-based surveys.</seg>
          <seg id="23">The differences in prevalences between the wealthiest and poorest income quintiles were calculated in absolute and relative terms.</seg>
          <seg id="24">Comparing the four indicators of complementary feeding, the ISSSF showed best performance, returning prevalence above 80% in 10 of the 11 countries evaluated.</seg>
          <seg id="25">The indicator showing worst performance was the MAD, with prevalence above 60% in only one of the eight countries evaluated.</seg>
          <seg id="26">In almost all countries, by all indicators, prevalences of complementary feeding were lower in the poorest population groups than in the wealthiest.</seg>
          <seg id="27">Alternative delivery models to maintain access to CR programs and to avoid physical inactivity should be considered.</seg>
          <seg id="28">The aim of this study was to assess physical activity (PA) levels after completing a home-based digital CR program.</seg>
          <seg id="29">A total of 116 cardiovascular disease (CVD) patients (62.6±8.9 years, 95 male) who had been attending a face-to-face CR program were recruited and assessed (baseline and at three months) on the following parameters: PA, sedentary behavior, adherence, cardiovascular and non-cardiovascular symptoms, feelings toward the pandemic, dietary habits, risk factor control, safety and adverse events.</seg>
          <seg id="30">The intervention consisted of a multidisciplinary digital CR program, including regular patient assessment, and exercise, educational and psychological group sessions.</seg>
          <seg id="31">Ninety-eight CVD patients successfully completed all the online assessments (15.5% drop-out rate).</seg>
          <seg id="32">A favorable main effect of time was an increase in moderate to vigorous PA and a decrease in sedentary time at three months.</seg>
          <seg id="33">Almost half of the participants completed at least one online exercise training session per week and attended at least one of the online educational sessions. No major adverse events were reported and only one minor event occurred. During the pandemic, levels of moderate to vigorous PA improved after three months of home-based CR in CVD patients with previous experience in a face-to-face CR model.</seg>
          <seg id="34">Diversified CR programs with a greater variety of content tailored to individual preferences are needed to meet the motivational and clinical requirements of CVD patients.</seg>
          <seg id="35">This research highlights housing as one of the dimensions of the lives of individuals who experience severe psychological suffering, which reverberates in their care and unique therapeutic plan.</seg>
          <seg id="36">This qualitative research was conducted with users of different services through semi-structured interviews submitted to the thematic content analysis.</seg>
          <seg id="37">This study identified how the conception of housing relates to protection, individuality, and affective memories that corroborate the construction of an expanded concrete life regarding living in freedom in the city, presenting plural housing located in different territories.</seg>
          <seg id="38">Taking ownership of spaces reveals the possibilities and challenges inherent to social exchanges and daily experiences.</seg>
          <seg id="39">Being and living in a house means having access to material and subjective goods, besides assuring care in freedom.</seg>
          <seg id="40">However, there are still limitations in the effective exercise of social participation.</seg>
          <seg id="41">Manual hyperinflation is used in neonatal and pediatric intensive care units to promote expiratory flow bias, but there is no consensus on the benefits of the technique.</seg>
          <seg id="42">Thus, a review that presents supporting evidence is necessary.</seg>
          <seg id="43">This study aims to review the literature on the manual hyperinflation maneuver in neonatal and pediatric intensive care units to analyze the evidence for this technique in terms of the forms of application (associated with other techniques or not), its safety, the performance of manual resuscitators and the influence of the physical therapist's experience, in addition to evaluating the methodological quality of the identified articles.</seg>
          <seg id="44">A search was performed in the following databases: Web of Science, ScienceDirect, PubMedⓇ, Scopus, CINAHL and SciELO.</seg>
          <seg id="45">Two researchers independently selected the articles.</seg>
          <seg id="46">Duplicate studies were assessed, evaluated by title and abstract and then read in full.</seg>
          <seg id="47">The quality of the articles was analyzed using the PEDro scale.</seg>
          <seg id="48">Six articles were included, two of which had high methodological quality.</seg>
          <seg id="49">The main results provided information on the contribution of the positive end-expiratory pressure valve to increasing lung volumes and the use of chest compressions to optimize expiratory flow bias, the negative influence of operator experience on the increase in peak inspiratory flow, the performance of different manual resuscitators when used with the technique and the safety of application in terms of maintaining hemodynamic stability and increasing peripheral oxygen saturation.</seg>
          <seg id="50">The available studies point to a positive effect of the manual hyperinflation maneuver in children who are admitted to intensive care units.</seg>
          <seg id="51">To assess the degree of correlation/agreement of maternal-fetal Doppler parameters between normal and growth-restricted fetuses (fetal growth restriction [FGR]).</seg>
          <seg id="52">The following maternal-fetal Doppler parameters were assessed: uterine artery (UAt), umbilical artery (UA), middle cerebral artery (MCA), cerebroplacental ratio (CPR), and umbilical-cerebral ratio (U/C).</seg>
          <seg id="53">The assessment of FGR was based on the Figueiras and Gratacós9 criteria. Spearman correlation coefficients were estimated to assess the correlation between resistance (RI) and pulsatility (PI) indices of Doppler parameters.</seg>
          <seg id="54">The agreement between two Doppler parameters was assessed by the Kappa coefficient.</seg>
          <seg id="55">In total, 502 Doppler examinations were included, and FGR was observed in 19 out of 274 fetuses.</seg>
          <seg id="56">A strong correlation was observed between RI and PI of UAt, UA, and MCA in all of the samples (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.001).</seg>
          <seg id="57">Of the 502 Doppler examinations, there was agreement between U/C and CPR percentiles for 480 (95.6%) and disagreement for 22 (4.4%), with Kappa coefficient of 0.26, thereby corresponding to weak agreement.</seg>
          <seg id="58">Of the 68 cases with estimated fetal weight ≤ 9&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; percentile (small for gestational age [SGA]), there was agreement between U/C &gt; 1.0 and CPR &lt; 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; percentile in 61 (88.4%) and disagreement in 7 (5.8%) with Kappa coefficient of 0.49, thereby corresponding to moderate agreement.</seg>
          <seg id="59">In SGA, U/C and CPR demonstrated moderate agreement.</seg>
          <seg id="60">Sickle cell disease (SCD) is the most common monogenic disease worldwide, with a variable prevalence in each continent.</seg>
          <seg id="61">A single nucleotide substitution leads to an amino-acid change in the β-globin chain, altering the normal structure ofhemoglobin, which is then called hemoglobin S inherited in homozygosity (HbSS) or double heterozygosity (HbSC, HbSβ), and leads to chronic hemolysis, vaso-occlusion, inflammation, and endothelium activation.</seg>
          <seg id="62">We performed a narrative review of the literature considering SCD and pregnancy, the main clinical and obstetrical complications, the specific antenatal care, and the follow-up for maternal and fetal surveillance.</seg>
          <seg id="63">Pregnant women with SCD are at a higher risk of developing clinical and obstetric complications such as pain episodes, pulmonary complications, infections, thromboembolic events, preeclampsia, and maternal death.</seg>
          <seg id="64">Their newborns are also at an increased risk of developing neonatal complications: fetal growth restriction, preterm birth, stillbirth.</seg>
          <seg id="65">Severe complications can occur in patients of any genotype.</seg>
          <seg id="66">We concluded that SCD is a high-risk condition that increases maternal and perinatal morbidity and mortality.</seg>
          <seg id="67">A multidisciplinary approach during pregnancy and the postpartum period is key to adequately diagnose and treat complications.</seg>
          <seg id="68">Cardiac, ventilatory and kidney management in the critical care setting has been optimized over the past decades.</seg>
          <seg id="69">Cognition and sedation represent one of the last remaning challenges.</seg>
          <seg id="70">As conventional sedation is suboptimal and as the sedation evoked by alpha-2 adrenergic agonists ('cooperative' sedation with dexmedetomidine, clonidine or guanfacine) represents a valuable alternative, this manuscript covers three practical topics for which evidence-based medicine is lacking: a) Switching from conventional to cooperative sedation ('switching'): the short answer is the abrupt withdrawal of conventional sedation, immediate implementation of alpha-2 agonist infusion and the use of 'rescue sedation' (midazolam bolus[es]) or 'breakthrough sedation' (haloperidol bolus[es]) to stabilize cooperative sedation.</seg>
          <seg id="71">b) Switching from conventional to cooperative sedation in unstable patients (e.g., refractory delirium tremens, septic shock, acute respiratory distress syndrome, etc. ): to avoid hypotension and bradycardia evoked by sympathetic deactivation, the short answer is to maintain the stroke volume through volume loading, vasopressors and inotropes.</seg>
          <seg id="72">c) To avoid these switches and associated difficulties, alpha-2 agonists may be considered first-line sedatives.</seg>
          <seg id="73">The short answer is to administer alpha-2 agonists slowly from admission or endotracheal intubation up to stabilized cooperative sedation.</seg>
          <seg id="74">The 'take home' message is as follows: a) alpha-2 agonists are jointly sympathetic deactivators and sedative agents; b) sympathetic deactivation implies maintaining the stroke volume and iterative assessment of volemia.</seg>
          <seg id="75">Evidence-based medicine should document our propositions.</seg>
          <seg id="76">This qualitative research aimed to investigate workers' theoretical conceptions regarding group work and analyze the driving and restrictive factors of group therapeutic practice in Psychosocial Care Centers (CAPS).</seg>
          <seg id="77">Sixty-six workers from CAPS and outpatient clinics from the Psychosocial Care Network from twenty-three municipalities in the State of Goiás participated in the study.</seg>
          <seg id="78">Data were collected through a structured questionnaire and a group interview audio-recorded and documented with photographs.</seg>
          <seg id="79">The concept of what the group is and is not emerged from the thematic analysis of the data.</seg>
          <seg id="80">The categories were organized into three analysis blocks concerning driving and restrictive forces: service-related, professional-related, and user-related.</seg>
          <seg id="81">Relational, structural, and therapeutic aspects and professional competence for group coordination are integrated in an antagonistic, complementary, and inseparable way to apprehend the studied reality.</seg>
          <seg id="82">We conclude that highlighting the restrictive aspects that must be recognized and improved and the drivers that must be maintained and enhanced can actively contribute to expanding the therapeutic capacity related to the use of group technology in mental health.</seg>
          <seg id="83">Ultra-processed foods are markers of unhealthy eating patterns, and their consumption is high among adolescents.</seg>
          <seg id="84">Characteristics of the school eating environment associate with student eating practices.</seg>
          <seg id="85">This study aims to investigate the association between the presence of school canteens and the availability of ultra-processed foods in school canteens with the consumption of these foods, inside the school, among adolescents of the 9th grade (14 years) of the public and private schools of the city of São Paulo, Brazil.</seg>
          <seg id="86">We conducted a cross-sectional study with SP-Proso data, in a sample of 2,680 adolescents.</seg>
          <seg id="87">We elaborated multilevel linear regression models to evaluate associations between the exposures: presence of school canteens and availability of ultra-processed foods with outcomes of consumption frequency of ultra-processed foods in the school.</seg>
          <seg id="88">We found an association between the presence of school canteens and the higher frequency of consumption of sausages (0.46; 95%CI: 0.24; 0.68), package snacks (0.50; 95%CI: 0.19; 0.80), goodies (0.82; 95%CI: 0.55; 1.09), and sugary drinks (0.34; 95%CI: 0.06; 0.62), as well as a score of consumption frequency of ultra-processed foods (2.37; 95%CI: 1.25; 3.48).</seg>
          <seg id="89">The availability of package snacks, goodies, and sugary drinks in school canteens increased the frequency of consumption of these foods.</seg>
          <seg id="90">We observed a dose-response effect between the diversity of ultra-processed foods in canteens and the frequency of consumption of these foods.</seg>
          <seg id="91">A school food environment with greater availability of ultra-processed products is associated with their higher consumption in school, indicating the need to regulate the sale of food within these institutions.</seg>
          <seg id="92">Descriptive, cross-sectional, quantitative, and qualitative study.</seg>
          <seg id="93">The procedures consisted of five stages: translation of the material; evaluation and response to questionnaire one regarding translation; determining the validity of the content; readability assessment; availability of material online and evaluation of content aimed at quality and visual identity (questionnaire two).</seg>
          <seg id="94">The translation of the notebook showed validity agreement rates greater than 90%.</seg>
          <seg id="95">Readability rated the material easy to read.</seg>
          <seg id="96">Most respondents agreed positively about the content and consistency of the translated material, videos, illustrative images, and captions.</seg>
          <seg id="97">The material was also considered necessary by the majority of the evaluators.</seg>
          <seg id="98">All audiologists reported using the instrument in clinical practice.</seg>
          <seg id="99">The translated toll is of great relevance. It gathers practical information to create a notebook of experiences and guidance on using the material as an additional resource to stimulate the auditory skills of children with hearing impairment.</seg>
          <seg id="100">The purpose of this study was to compare the frequency of the occurrence of high-risk human papillomavirus (HPV) and abnormal anal cytology in immunocompetent women with and without HPV-induced genital lesions.</seg>
          <seg id="101">Fifty-seven immunocompetent women with and without genital intraepithelial lesions were assessed; they were divided into two groups: group 1 was comprised of women with HPV-associated genital lesions (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 26), and group 2 was comprised of those without HPV-associated genital lesions (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 31).</seg>
          <seg id="102">Samples for liquid-based cytology and high-risk DNA-HPV polymerase chain reaction real-time tests were collected from the cervix and anus.</seg>
          <seg id="103">All cases were evaluated using high-resolution anoscopy; biopsies were performed when required.</seg>
          <seg id="104">The Fisher exact and chi-squared tests were applied for consolidated data in the contingency table, and the Student &lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt;-test and Mann-Whitney U-test for independent variables.</seg>
          <seg id="105">Anal high-risk HPV infections were more frequent in group 1 (odds ratio [OR], 4.95; 95% confidence interval [CI], 1.34-18.3; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.012), along with concomitant high-risk HPV infections in the uterine cervix and the anus (OR 18.8; 95% CI, 2.20-160; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.001).</seg>
          <seg id="106">The incidence of high-risk cervical HPV infection was associated with high-risk anal HPV infection (OR, 4.95; 95% CI, 1.34-18.3; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.012).</seg>
          <seg id="107">There was no statistical difference concerning abnormal anal cytology or anoscopy between the groups, and no anal intraepithelial lesion was found in either group.</seg>
          <seg id="108">To assess the levels of physical activity and exercise practice, and examine the associated maternal characteristics; as well as the anxiety levels of high-risk pregnant women.</seg>
          <seg id="109">Pregnant women of 18 to 40-years-old, with a single fetus, and with gestational age up to 38 weeks were included.</seg>
          <seg id="110">The level of physical activity and exercise practice of the study's participants were investigated using the Pregnancy Physical Activity Questionnaire (PPAQ).</seg>
          <seg id="111">Maternal sociodemographic, anthropometric, and medical data were investigated using a specific form.</seg>
          <seg id="112">For anxiety levels, the short version of the State-Trait Anxiety Inventory (STAI) was applied.</seg>
          <seg id="113">We used the Student &lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt;-test, chi-square test, odds ratio (OR) with 95% confidence interval (95% CI) and multiple logistic regression.</seg>
          <seg id="114">The significance level was 5%.</seg>
          <seg id="115">Among the 109 pregnant women included, 82 (75.2%) were classified as sedentary/little active.</seg>
          <seg id="116">The higher energy expenditure were for domestic activities (133.81 ± 81.84 METs), followed by work-related activities (40.77 ± 84.71 METs).</seg>
          <seg id="117">Only 19.3% women exercised during pregnancy (4.76 ± 12.47 METs), with slow walking being the most reported exercise.</seg>
          <seg id="118">A higher level of education was the most important factor associated with women being moderately or vigorously active (OR = 29.8; 95% CI 4.9-117.8).</seg>
          <seg id="119">Nulliparity (OR = 3.1; 95% CI 1.0-9.1), low levels of anxiety (OR = 3.6; 95% CI 1.2-10.7), and unemployment (OR = 4.8; 95% CI 1.1-19.6) were associated with the practice of exercise during pregnancy.</seg>
          <seg id="120">Recognizing factors that hinder the adoption of a more physically active lifestyle is essential for an individualized guidance regarding exercise during pregnancy.</seg>
          <seg id="121">This study aimed to evaluate the left ventricular (LV) and left atrial (LA) functions with strain echocardiography (SE) in patients with acromegaly.</seg>
          <seg id="122">This study included 50 acromegaly patients with active disease and 50 healthy controls with similar age, gender, and body surface area.</seg>
          <seg id="123">In addition to routine echocardiography examinations, LV-GLS and LAS measurements were performed with SE.</seg>
          <seg id="124">LAS and LV-GLS values were significantly lower in patients with acromegaly (p&lt;0.05 for all).</seg>
          <seg id="125">In bivariate analysis, systolic blood pressure, N-terminal prohormone of brain natriuretic peptide, Insulin-like growth factor-1, LA diastolic diameter, and LVMI levels were found to be positively correlated with both LAS and LV-GLS (p &lt;0.05).</seg>
          <seg id="126">IGF-1 level was strongly correlated with LAS and LV-GLS (p&lt;0.001 and β=0.5 vs. p&lt;0.001 and β=0.626, respectively); 48% of patients with acromegaly have reduced LV-GLS (&lt;20%).</seg>
          <seg id="127">Left ventricular mass-index (LVMI) independently determines the presence of reduced LV-GLS and each 1g/m2increase in LVMI level increases the likelihood of reduced LV-GLS by 6%.</seg>
          <seg id="128">Although LV ejection fraction is normal in patients with acromegaly, LAS and LV-GLS values were significantly reduced.</seg>
          <seg id="129">Apart from LVMI increase, another finding of cardiac involvement may be LAS and LV-GLS decrease.</seg>
          <seg id="130">Therefore, in addition to routine echocardiography, LAS and LV-GLS may be useful to evaluate early signs of cardiac involvement before the occurrence of irreversible cardiac changes.</seg>
          <seg id="131">Genetic testing aims to identify patients at risk for inherited cancer susceptibility.</seg>
          <seg id="132">In the last decade, there was a significant increase in the request of broader panels of genes as multi-gene panel testing became widely available.</seg>
          <seg id="133">The aim of this study was to translate the WOSI into European Portuguese and analyze its validity and reliability in a population with shoulder instability.</seg>
          <seg id="134">Internal consistency and test-retest analyses were conducted to determine the level of reliability of the scale.</seg>
          <seg id="135">Regarding the construct validity, the correlation between the WOSI-PT and QuickDASH was high and negative (-0.79).</seg>
          <seg id="136">The correlations between WOSI-PT and SF-12 were positive, respectively, moderate with physical (0.66) and low with mental (0.34) health.</seg>
          <seg id="137">The search covered the scientific databases MEDLINE, Lilacs, Ibecs, Cinahl, SciELO, Cochrane, Scopus, Web of Science and gray literature.</seg>
          <seg id="138">The Quality Assessment of Diagnostic Accuracy Studies was used to assess the methodological quality and risk of study bias.</seg>
          <seg id="139">The statistical heterogeneity of the likelihood (LR) and diagnostic odds ratios were evaluated using forest plots and Cochran's Q statistic, and a crosshair summary Receiver Operating Characteristic plot using the multiple cutoffs model was calculated.</seg>
          <seg id="140">We initially retrieved 3,522 references from the databases; among these, 12 studies including 1,757 subjects were selected for the qualitative analysis.</seg>
          <seg id="141">Many studies presented an unclear risk of bias in the 'patient selection' and 'flow and time' criteria.</seg>
          <seg id="142">Among the 12 included studies, seven presented 'high risk' and five 'unclear risk' for the item 'reference standard.' The diagnostic performance of the cough peak flow for the extubation outcome was low to moderate when we considered the results from all included studies, with a +LR of 1.360 (95%CI 1.240 - 1.530), -LR of 0.218 (95%CI 0.159 - 0.293) and a diagnostic odds ratio of 6.450 (95%CI 4.490 - 9.090).</seg>
          <seg id="143">A subgroup analysis including only the studies with a cutoff between 55 and 65 L/minute showed a slightly better, although still moderate, performance.</seg>
          <seg id="144">A cough peak flow assessment considering a cutoff between 55 and 65L/minute may be useful as a complementary measurement prior to extubation.</seg>
          <seg id="145">Additional well-designed studies are necessary to identify the best method and equipment to record the cough peak flow as well as the best cutoff.</seg>
          <seg id="146">The aim of this study is to describe obstetric complications and the rate of vertical transmission in pregnant women with SARS-CoV-2 infection.</seg>
          <seg id="147">Epidemiological, pregnancy and childbirth data were collected.</seg>
          <seg id="148">The most frequent maternal comorbidity was obesity.</seg>
          <seg id="149">The rates of preterm birth and small-to-gestational-age were 12.1% and 9.9%, respectively.</seg>
          <seg id="150">In the third trimester, 2.9% of pregnant women required respiratory support.</seg>
          <seg id="151">There were eight cases (1.5%) of fetal death, including two cases of vertical transmission.</seg>
          <seg id="152">There were five cases of postpartum respiratory degradation, but no maternal deaths were recorded.</seg>
          <seg id="153">The caesarean section rate was higher in the first than in the second wave (68.5% vs 31.5%).</seg>
          <seg id="154">RT-PCR SARS-CoV-2 positivity among newborns was 1.3%.</seg>
          <seg id="155">To describe the efficacy and safety of protective embolization during prostatic artery embolization, as well as to discuss its clinical relevance.</seg>
          <seg id="156">This was a retrospective, observational, single-center study including 39 patients who underwent prostatic artery embolization to treat lower urinary tract symptoms related to benign prostatic hyperplasia between June 2008 and March 2018.</seg>
          <seg id="157">Follow-up evaluations, performed at 3 and 12 months after the procedure, included determination of the International Prostate Symptom Score, a quality of life score, and prostate-specific antigen levels, as well as ultrasound, magnetic resonance imaging, and uroflowmetry.</seg>
          <seg id="158">Protective embolization was performed in 45 arteries: in the middle rectal artery in 19 (42.2%); in the accessory internal pudendal artery in 11 (24.4%); in an internal pudendal artery anastomosis in 10 (22.2%); in the superior vesical artery in four (8.9%); and in the obturator artery in one (2.2%).</seg>
          <seg id="159">There was one case of nontarget embolization leading to a penile ulcer, which was attributed to reflux of microspheres to an unprotected artery.</seg>
          <seg id="160">There were no complications related to the protected branches.</seg>
          <seg id="161">All of the patients showed significant improvement in all of the outcomes studied (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.05), and none reported worsening of sexual function during follow-up.</seg>
          <seg id="162">Protective embolization can reduce nontarget embolization during prostatic artery embolization without affecting the results of the procedure.</seg>
          <seg id="163">In addition, no adverse events other than those expected or previously reported were observed.</seg>
          <seg id="164">Therefore, protective embolization of pudendal region is safe.</seg>
          <seg id="165">To describe current clinical practices related to the use of high-flow nasal cannula therapy by Brazilian pediatric intensivists and compare them with those in other countries.</seg>
          <seg id="166">A questionnaire was administered to pediatric intensivists in North and South America, Asia, Europe, and Australia/New Zealand for the main study.</seg>
          <seg id="167">We compared the Brazilian cohort with cohorts in the United States of America, Canada, the United Kingdom, and India.</seg>
          <seg id="168">Overall, 501 physicians responded, 127 of which were in Brazil.</seg>
          <seg id="169">Only 63.8% of respondents in Brazil had a high-flow nasal cannula available, in contrast to 100% of respondents in the United Kingdom, Canada, and the United States.</seg>
          <seg id="170">The attending physician was responsible for the decision to start a high-flow nasal cannula according to 61.2% respondents in Brazil, 95.5% in the United Kingdom, 96.6% in the United States, 96.8% in Canada, and 84.7% in India. A total of 62% of respondents in Brazil, 96.3% in the United Kingdom, 96.6% in the United States, 96.8% in Canada, and 84.7% in India reported that the attending physician was responsible for the decision to wean or modify the high-flow nasal cannula settings.</seg>
          <seg id="171">When high-flow nasal cannula therapy failed due to respiratory distress/failure, 82% of respondents in Brazil would consider a trial of noninvasive ventilation before endotracheal intubation, compared to 93% in the United Kingdom, 88% in the United States, 91.5% in Canada, and 76.8% in India.</seg>
          <seg id="172">More Brazilian intensivists (6.5%) than intensivists in the United Kingdom, United States, and India (1.6% for all) affirmed using sedatives frequently with high-flow nasal cannulas.</seg>
          <seg id="173">The availability of high-flow nasal cannulas in Brazil is still not widespread.</seg>
          <seg id="174">There are some divergences in clinical practices between Brazilian intensivists and their colleagues abroad, mainly in processes and decision-making about starting and weaning high-flow nasal cannula therapy.</seg>
          <seg id="175">To analyze the quantity of cervical smears, also designated Papanicolaou tests, between 2006 and 2015 in all the Federal units of Brazil, as well as to verify the quantity of exams collected outside the recommended age range and the economic impact of such excess.</seg>
          <seg id="176">The quantity of exams collected outside the recommended age range was verified, and, so, the economic impact generated was noted.</seg>
          <seg id="177">Between 2006 and 2015, 87,425,549 Papanicolaou tests were collected in Brazil.</seg>
          <seg id="178">Of these, 20,215,052 tests were collected outside the age range recommended by the Brazilian Ministry of Health; this number corresponded to 23.12% of all exams.</seg>
          <seg id="179">From such data, considering that each Pap smear collected by SUS generates a cost of BRL 7.30 to the government, according to the information in the &lt;i&gt;Tabela SUS&lt;/i&gt; dated September 2018, there was a total charge of BRL 147,569,880 for tests collected outside the protocol.</seg>
          <seg id="180">In Brazil, according to the Ministry of Health's protocol about the recommended practices on collecting Pap smears, whose newest edition dates of 2016, it is recommended that Pap smears are collected in women from a specific age range, in whom the potential diagnosing advantages overcome the onus of overdiagnosis or of a lesion with great regression potential.</seg>
          <seg id="181">However, such protocols have not been correctly followed, promoting more than 20 million tests in excess, and an exorbitant cost for the Brazilian public health system.</seg>
          <seg id="182">It is relevant to take measures to correctly use the official protocol, reducing the patients risks, as well as the economic impact for SUS.</seg>
          <seg id="183">Advances in endoscopy and open-access systems led to an increase in endoscopic procedures.</seg>
          <seg id="184">However, overuse of endoscopy has been consistently reported.</seg>
          <seg id="185">This study aims to assess the appropriateness of esophagogastroduodenoscopy (EGD) and colonoscopy referral in the private and public setting.</seg>
          <seg id="186">Appropriateness of endoscopy was defined according to the American Society for Gastrointestinal Endoscopy guidelines (for EGD) and the European Panel on Appropriateness of Gastrointestinal Endoscopy II (for colonoscopy).</seg>
          <seg id="187">Regarding EGD: 215 patients enrolled (43.7% were males) with a mean age of 61.0 ± 15.1 years; 54.0% (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 116) were in public hospitals.</seg>
          <seg id="188">Referral by a gastroenterologist was made for 34.9% (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 75).</seg>
          <seg id="189">Appropriate indications were made for 62.3% (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 134): 42.4% in private versus 79.3% in public endoscopy units (odds ratio [OR] 5.20; 95% confidence interval [CI] 2.85-9.49; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.01).</seg>
          <seg id="190">Rate of appropriate EGD was 74.7% for gastroenterologist referral and 56.1% for other specialties (OR 2.31; 95% CI 1.24-4.28; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.01).</seg>
          <seg id="191">Diagnostic yield for relevant findings was 47.9%.</seg>
          <seg id="192">Referral by a gastroenterologist was made for 20.6% (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 59).</seg>
          <seg id="193">Appropriate indications were made for 70.0% (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 201): 53.0% in private vs. 88.4% in public endoscopy units (OR 6.75; 95% CI 3.66-12.47; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.01).</seg>
          <seg id="194">A significant percentage of endoscopies, mainly in the private setting, were performed without an appropriate indication. This influenced the diagnostic yield.</seg>
          <seg id="195">The use of adequate criteria is fundamental for the rational use of an open-access system.</seg>
          <seg id="196">Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy (HCM) can cause obstruction in the left ventricular outflow tract (LVOT), and be responsible for the onset of limiting symptoms, such as tiredness.</seg>
          <seg id="197">When such symptoms are refractory to pharmacological treatment, interventionist alternative therapies can be useful, such as septal ablation through the infusion of alcohol in the coronary artery or through myectomy.</seg>
          <seg id="198">Recently, the use of a radiofrequency (RF) catheter for endocardial septal ablation guided by electroanatomic mapping has proven to be efficient, despite the high incidence of complete atrioventricular block.</seg>
          <seg id="199">An alternative would be the application of RF at the beginning point of the septal gradient guided by the transesophageal echocardiography (TEE).</seg>
          <seg id="200">The echocardiography is an imaging method with high accuracy to determine septal anatomy.</seg>
          <seg id="201">To assess the long term effect of septal ablation for the relief of ventricular-arterial gradient, using TEE to help place the catheter in the area of larger septal obstruction.</seg>
          <seg id="202">Besides, to assess the effects of ablation on the functional class and echocardiographic parameters.</seg>
          <seg id="203">Twelve asymptomatic patients, with LVOT obstruction, refractory to pharmacological therapy, underwent endocardial septal ablation with 8mm-tip catheters, whose placement was oriented in the region of larger obstruction, assisted by the TEE.</seg>
          <seg id="204">After each application, the gradient was reassessed and a new application was performed according to the clinical criterion.</seg>
          <seg id="205">The effects of RF applications were assessed both for the gradient at rest and for that provoked by the Valsalva maneuver, and considering the gradient.</seg>
          <seg id="206">The differences were significant when p-value was lower than or equal to 0.05.</seg>
          <seg id="207">It was possible to observe that the mean reduction of the maximum gradients was from 96.8±34.7 mmHg to 62.7±25.4 mmHg three months after the procedure (p=0.0036).</seg>
          <seg id="208">After one year, the mean of maximum gradient was 36.1±23.8 mmHg (p=0.0001).</seg>
          <seg id="209">The procedure was well tolerated, without records of complete atrioventricular block nor severe complications.</seg>
          <seg id="210">The TEE-guided septal ablation was efficient and safe, and the results were maintained during the clinical follow-up period.</seg>
          <seg id="211">It is a reasonable option for the interventionist treatment of LVOT obstruction in HCM.</seg>
          <seg id="212">It is important which medicine to use as a first-line treatment to close the duct.</seg>
          <seg id="213">The aim of this study is to compare the effectiveness and side effects of intravenous (IV) forms of ibuprofen and paracetamol and to contribute to the literature investigating the first drug selected in the medical treatment of patent ductus arteriosus (PDA).</seg>
          <seg id="214">Our study was conducted between January 2017 and December 2019.</seg>
          <seg id="215">Premature infants with birth weight (BW) ≤1500 g and gestational age (GA) ≤32 weeks were included in the study.</seg>
          <seg id="216">In the study period, all infants with hemodynamically significant patent ductus arteriosus (hsPDA) were given rescue intravenous (IV) ibuprofen as a primary medical treatment or IV paracetamol treatment if there were contraindications for ibuprofen.</seg>
          <seg id="217">The patients were divided into two groups: patients receiving IV ibuprofen and patients receiving IV paracetamol.</seg>
          <seg id="218">Of these patients, 101 were given IV paracetamol and 169 were given IV ibuprofen.</seg>
          <seg id="219">The success rate of PDA closure with first-course treatment was 74.3% in the IV paracetamol group and 72.8% in the IV ibuprofen group (p=0.212).</seg>
          <seg id="220">Our results show that IV paracetamol is as effective as IV ibuprofen in the first-line treatment of hsPDA, and can become the preferred treatment for the management of hsPDA.</seg>
          <seg id="221">Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) is considered a public health problem, mainly in severely obese patients.</seg>
          <seg id="222">The aim of the present study was to investigate different biochemical-based scores available and determine which one could best serve as an NAFLD predicting tool in a severely obese population.</seg>
          <seg id="223">This was a cross-sectional study involving severely obese patients.</seg>
          <seg id="224">All patients were evaluated with serum laboratory parameters for 1 week before biopsy, and all patients were treated with intraoperative liver biopsy, during bariatric surgery.</seg>
          <seg id="225">A total of 143 severely obese patients were included.</seg>
          <seg id="226">APRI showed high specificity of 82% and low sensitivity of 54%.</seg>
          <seg id="227">In contrast, HOMA-IR showed high sensitivity of 84% and low specificity of 48%.</seg>
          <seg id="228">NAFLDS, FIB-4, AST/ALT, and HSI have no utility for the evaluation of severe steatosis in severely obese patients.</seg>
          <seg id="229">Diabetes and insulin-resistance-related biochemical assessments, such as HOMA-IR, can be used as good screening tools for severe steatosis in these patients.</seg>
          <seg id="230">APRI score is the most specific biochemical diagnostic tool for steatosis in severely obese patients and can help clinicians to decide the need for bariatric or metabolic surgery.</seg>
          <seg id="231">Endoscopic treatment for esophageal variceal has been used as the main intervention in patients with portal hypertension secondary to schistosomiasis, but with significant rates of recurrence of esophageal variceal and rebleeding.</seg>
          <seg id="232">The long-term results of exclusive endoscopic treatment are poorly studied as the relationship of the splenic dimensions in this context.</seg>
          <seg id="233">The aim of this study was to identify, through ultrasonography, whether the splenic index and the longitudinal (craniocaudal) dimension of the spleen are the predictors of rebleeding and variceal recurrence in late follow-up of patients with nonoperated schistosomiasis, after endoscopic eradication of esophageal variceal.</seg>
          <seg id="234">This is a retrospective and observational study analyzing the medical records of patients diagnosed with hepatosplenic schistosomiasis.</seg>
          <seg id="235">The receiver operating characteristic curve was used to determine the best cutoff point for the mean splenic index as a predictor of recurrence and bleeding.</seg>
          <seg id="236">A follow-up of 54 patients were analyzed during the period from 2002 to 2018.</seg>
          <seg id="237">The mean follow-up time was 8 years.</seg>
          <seg id="238">The splenic index with value &gt;144 was proved to be a sensitive test for rebleeding.</seg>
          <seg id="239">In the analysis of the longitudinal dimension, the spleen length of &gt;20 cm showed a statistically significant test for recurrence of variceal and a length &gt;19 cm presented as a very sensitive and statistically significant test for rebleeding.</seg>
          <seg id="240">Splenic index and craniocaudal dimension analysis, obtained by ultrasonography, can predict recurrence of varicose veins and rebleeding after exclusive endoscopic treatment.</seg>
          <seg id="241">The aim of this study was to assess the prevalence of the different neuropsychiatric diagnoses in hospitalized patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection assessed by Liaison Psychiatry.</seg>
          <seg id="242">We reviewed the electronic health records from all inpatients with a positive SARS-CoV-2 RT-PCR test that were assessed by the Liaison Psychiatry Unit (LPU) between February and December 2020.</seg>
          <seg id="243">We reviewed relevant sociodemographic and clinical data, including 15 neuropsychiatric symptoms.</seg>
          <seg id="244">The prevalence of psychiatric disorders was our main outcome.</seg>
          <seg id="245">Delirium was the most frequent diagnosis in our sample (43.5%), followed by major depressive disorder (21.7%).</seg>
          <seg id="246">Patients with delirium were more likely to suffer from COVID-19 symptoms (delirium: 19/20, 95%; no delirium: 14/26, 53.8%; p = 0.02), and to have a longer time interval between a positive SARS-CoV-2 RT-PCR test and an evaluation by the LPU (delirium: median = 16.5 days, IQR = 16; no delirium: median = 8 days, IQR = 16.3; p = 0.045).</seg>
          <seg id="247">Agitation (52.2%) and cognitive symptoms (47.8%) were the most reported neuropsychiatric symptoms.</seg>
          <seg id="248">This finding is in line with recent literature concerning hospitalized COVID-19 patients The higher frequency of COVID-19 symptoms found in the delirium group suggests a possible association between symptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection and delirium onset.</seg>
          <seg id="249">Five-hundred and thirty-three (0.4%) women with AGC cytology were identified and, of these, 69.41% (370/533) were properly referred for colposcopy and a new cytology.</seg>
          <seg id="250">On biopsy of the women with a second AGC cytology, 43.4% (10/23) had normal histology, 43.4% (10/23) had squamous lesions, 8.7% (2/23) had invasive adenocarcinoma, and 1.2% (1/23) had an inconclusive report.</seg>
          <seg id="251">All of the women with high-grade squamous intraepithelial lesion (HSIL) or invasive adenocarcinoma (respectively 5 and 2 patients), after a 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; AGC cytology were 25 years old or older.</seg>
          <seg id="252">Most of the AGC cytology cases occurred in adult women between the ages of 25 and 54.</seg>
          <seg id="253">Although most of the patients had normal histology after follow-up, several of them presented with squamous intraepithelial lesions or invasive adenocarcinoma.</seg>
          <seg id="254">The Brazilian Psychiatric Reform (BPR) process proposes a break with the asylum paradigm in several dimensions.</seg>
          <seg id="255">Thinking about care spaces and the right to the city are important flags for this issue.</seg>
          <seg id="256">Bearing that in mind, a theoretical-conceptual framework was constructed, aiming to discuss and systematize the relationship between the architecture of care spaces geared toward madness and the production of subjectivities and relationships.</seg>
          <seg id="257">Thus, based on archeo-genealogy, a dialogue was organized between concepts and authors that approach space and architecture as devices for the production of subjectivities and relationships, such as total institutions and self-mortification (Erving Goffman) and space-behavioral syndrome (Mirian de Carvalho), as well as experiences such as those by Maura Lopes Cançado and Lima Barreto.</seg>
          <seg id="258">It is also the aim of this study to discuss and draw, through the lens of different fields of knowledge, an ideal city that will aid in facing the asylum paradigm and strengthening the BPR process: the open city, that which includes difference.</seg>
          <seg id="259">Locating the importance of discussing the architectures, spaces, and the city built for the BPR process, this article proposes to build and add a new dimension of analysis of such a process to those that already exist: the spatial dimension.</seg>
          <seg id="260">The patients were followed up for a mean time of 132 months since the first surgery.</seg>
          <seg id="261">After the NSM, 5 (20.8%) patients were diagnosed with local recurrence and only 1 (4.2%) patient died.</seg>
          <seg id="262">The patients presented 4.8% (2) of partial and 2.4% (1) of total nipple necrosis.</seg>
          <seg id="263">In this long-term follow-up since the first surgery, we observed low rates of complication and good survival, although associated with high local recurrence in patients diagnosed with IBTR undergoing NSM as salvage surgery.</seg>
          <seg id="264">We demonstrated that NSM may be considered after IBTR for patients who did not want to undergo total mastectomy.</seg>
          <seg id="265">The statistical analysis was performed using the Student &lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt;-test, and values of &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.05 were considered statistically significant.</seg>
          <seg id="266">The serum levels of malondialdehyde were increased (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.0001), and the total antioxidant capacity was reduced in the PE group (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.034), indicating oxidative stress.</seg>
          <seg id="267">In the PE group, the mean arterial pressure was significantly higher (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.0001), but the serum levels of NO did not show a statistically significant reduction (&lt;i&gt;p &lt;/i&gt;= 0.20).</seg>
          <seg id="268">The gene expression profiling of NOS3 and NOS2 revealed a down regulation in the PE group by 8.49 and 51.05 times respectively.</seg>
          <seg id="269">Nitric oxide may play a role in this mechanism, but interactions with other vasoactive /biological substances cannot be overlooked, as the gene expression of NOS3 and NOS2 has been reduced.</seg>
          <seg id="270">To identify current evidence on the use of topiramate for refractory status epilepticus.</seg>
          <seg id="271">We reviewed the literature to investigate the efficacy of topiramate in the treatment of refractory status epilepticus.</seg>
          <seg id="272">The search terms used were 'status epilepticus', 'refractory', 'treatment' and 'topiramate'.</seg>
          <seg id="273">No restrictions were used.</seg>
          <seg id="274">The search yielded 487 articles that reported using topiramate as a treatment for refractory status epilepticus and its outcomes.</seg>
          <seg id="275">Case reports, review articles, and animal experiments were excluded.</seg>
          <seg id="276">After excluding duplicates and applying inclusion and exclusion criteria, nine studies were included for analyses.</seg>
          <seg id="277">Descriptive and qualitative analyses were performed, and the results were as follows: response rates (defined as termination in-hospital until 72 hours after the administration of topiramate) varied from 27% to 100%.</seg>
          <seg id="278">The mortality rate varied from 5.9% to 68%.</seg>
          <seg id="279">Positive functional long-term outcomes, defined as discharge, back to baseline or rehabilitation, were documented by seven studies, and the rates ranged between 4% and 55%.</seg>
          <seg id="280">Most studies reported no or mild adverse effects.</seg>
          <seg id="281">Topiramate was effective in terminating refractory status epilepticus, presented relatively low mortality and was well tolerated.</seg>
          <seg id="282">Therefore, topiramate could be a good option as a third-line therapy for refractory status epilepticus, but further studies are necessary.</seg>
          <seg id="283">It has been shown that interleukin-35 (IL-35) subunits are strongly expressed in atherosclerotic plaques in humans.</seg>
          <seg id="284">Therefore, it is considered to play a role in atherosclerosis.</seg>
          <seg id="285">In this study, IL-35 levels were compared with the control group in patients with stable coronary artery disease (CAD), and the association between IL-35 levels and the lesion type, lesion severity and extension was investigated with the Gensini score (GS) and the Syntax score (SS) in the patient group.</seg>
          <seg id="286">Sixty patients (18 female and 42 male) with CAD diagnosed by coronary angiography, who presented with typical chest pain and positive noninvasive cardiac stress test, and 46 patients (18 female and 28 male) with normal coronary lumenogram, were included in this study.</seg>
          <seg id="287">Gensini and Syntax scores were calculated in the patient group, and these values were compared with IL-35 levels.</seg>
          <seg id="288">Non-normally distributed variables were analyzed by the Mann-Whitney U test, whereas normally distributed parameters were assessed by Student's t-test.</seg>
          <seg id="289">The difference between categorical variables were evaluated by the Chi-square or Fisher test.</seg>
          <seg id="290">P-values&lt;0.05 were considered as statistically significant.</seg>
          <seg id="291">No significant differences were observed between patients and the control group in terms of demographic characteristics and laboratory findings.</seg>
          <seg id="292">Compared to the control group, IL-35 levels of the CAD group were considerably lower (36.9±63.9 ng/ml vs. 33.2±13.2 ng/ml, p&lt;0.008).</seg>
          <seg id="293">Although not statistically significant, IL-35 levels were higher in patients with low SS than among those with high SS (33.2±13.7 vs. 31.8±8.9, p=0.51).</seg>
          <seg id="294">The IL-35 values of the patients with high GS were significantly lower than in patients with low GS (35±17.4 vs. 30.7±8.6, p=0.043).</seg>
          <seg id="295">It has been shown that IL-35 levels can be a new biomarker for stable CAD, and IL-35 is associated with the extension of CAD.</seg>
          <seg id="296">It is essential to maintain the alveolar bone ridge to ensure the success of implant therapy.</seg>
          <seg id="297">Platelet-rich fibrin (PRF) may benefit bone repair, but its quantitative microscopic results are still inconclusive.</seg>
          <seg id="298">The aim of this study was to histomorphometrically analyze human dental alveoli after extraction treated with autologous fibrin, biphasic calcium phosphate or sticky bone.</seg>
          <seg id="299">The sample consisted of healthy adult volunteer patients, with clinical and tomographic indication for single post-extraction graft of upper premolars for maintenance of the alveolar ridge and subsequent implantation.</seg>
          <seg id="300">The 10 remaining patients in the study were divided into three groups according to the type of filling used in the dental socket: autologous PRF plug covered by a PRF membrane (G1), PRF associated with an alloplastic graft based on hydroxyapatite with beta tricalcium phosphate covered by a collagen membrane (G2) or alloplastic graft based on beta tricalcium phosphate covered by collagen membrane (control).</seg>
          <seg id="301">After 8 months, bone biopsies were performed at the grafted sites and the patients underwent implant-prosthetic rehabilitation.</seg>
          <seg id="302">Paraffin-embedded tissue blocks were routinely processed and sectionsfrom different depths were mounted in 3 slides and stained with HE.</seg>
          <seg id="303">The histomorphometric evaluation analyzed 30 photomicrographs per block, quantifying the percentage presence of newly formed bone, connective tissue and remaining biomaterial using the ImageJ software. Parametric data enabled intergroup comparisons using ANOVA and Tukey's post-hoc test for multiple comparison with statistical significance of 5% (p&lt;0.05), with normality of the 3 groups by the Jarque-Bera test (p&gt;0.05).</seg>
          <seg id="304">There was a higher mean of newly formed bone in G1 (68.83%) compared to G2 (35.69%) and control (16.28%).</seg>
          <seg id="305">There was greater presence of connective tissue in the control (61.56%).</seg>
          <seg id="306">Remaining biomaterial was higher in G2 (15.75%), but did not differ statistically from the control.</seg>
          <seg id="307">Bone regeneration obtained with PRF alone or sticky bone suggests the efficacy of these therapies, encouraging the clinical use of this blood concentrate in dental procedures.</seg>
          <seg id="308">To describe the quality of life (QoL) of Brazilian speech therapists and relate it to sociodemographic and professiographic aspects, and to their role in the COVID-19 pandemic.</seg>
          <seg id="309">Population-based, cross-sectional epidemiological study.</seg>
          <seg id="310">The research involved speech therapists from Brazil, who were invited to answer, online, the WHOQOL-bref form about their health and QoL, in addition to sociodemographic and professional questions.</seg>
          <seg id="311">609 speech therapists aged between 21 and 65 years, average age of 34 years, participated in the study.</seg>
          <seg id="312">Lower scores in the physical domain of QoL were given by female speech therapists, providing outpatient care, who did not work in private clinics, acted indirectly in the pandemic, were absent from work due to psycho-emotional aspects; in the psychological domain, they were female, without a partner, working in a private clinic or elsewhere and acted directly or indirectly in the pandemic; in the social relations domain, they had no partner, worked in outpatient care, but not in private clinics; and in the environment domain, lower scores were in black and brown race/color, without a partner, attending home care, but not in a private clinic or management/administrative or other.</seg>
          <seg id="313">Brazilian speech therapists had the lowest QoL scores in the psychological and environmental domains; their QoL is related to factors such as sex, color/race, presence of a partner, council region, service environments, direct action with COVID-19 patients and COVID-19 diagnosis.</seg>
          <seg id="314">Brain injury caused by extracorporeal circulation during cardiovascular surgical procedures has been a recurring complication since the implementation of extracorporeal circulation five decades ago.</seg>
          <seg id="315">There is no unique cause of brain injury due to the use of extracorporeal circulation, but it is known that brain injury affects about 70% of patients who undergo this procedure.</seg>
          <seg id="316">Intracranial pressure assessment is one method that can guide the management of patients undergoing procedures associated with neurological disturbances.</seg>
          <seg id="317">This study describes two cases of patients who underwent cardiovascular surgery with extracorporeal circulation in whom clinical protocols for neuroprotection in the postoperative phase were guided by intracranial pressure waveform findings obtained with a novel noninvasive intracranial pressure monitoring method.</seg>
          <seg id="318">Women have metabolic, immunological, and genetic variables that ensure more protection from coronavirus infection.</seg>
          <seg id="319">However, the indication of treatment for several pathologies and contraception is determined by hormones that have adverse effects and raise doubts about their use during the COVID-19 pandemic.</seg>
          <seg id="320">Therefore, the present study searches women specificities and the relation between female sexual hormones and COVID-19, and reports the main recommendations in this background.</seg>
          <seg id="321">To this end, a review of the literature was conducted in the main databases, auxiliary data sources, and official websites.</seg>
          <seg id="322">Therefore, considering the hypercoagulability status of COVID-19, the debate about the use of contraceptives due to the relative risk of thromboembolic effects that they impose arises.</seg>
          <seg id="323">However, the current available evidence, as well as the recommendations of main health organs around the world, demonstrate that the use of hormonal contraceptives must be maintained during the pandemic.</seg>
          <seg id="324">Salvage surgery (SS) is defined as surgical resection after the failure of the first treatment with curative intent.</seg>
          <seg id="325">This is a retrospective study of patients with gastric cancer (GC) operated on between 2009 and 2020.</seg>
          <seg id="326">Notably, 40 patients were recommended for salvage gastrectomy with curative-intent treatment.</seg>
          <seg id="327">For analysis purpose, patients were divided into two groups: 23 patients after endoscopic resection and 17 patients after gastrectomy.</seg>
          <seg id="328">In the first group, all patients underwent R0 resection, their average hospital length of stay (LOS) was 15.7 days, and 2 (8.6%) patients had major complications.</seg>
          <seg id="329">During the average follow-up of 37.2 months, there was only one recurrence.</seg>
          <seg id="330">The median overall survival (OS) was 46 months.</seg>
          <seg id="331">In the postgastrectomy group, 9 (52.9%) patients were rescued with curative intent, the average hospital LOS was 12.2 days, and 3 (17.6%) had major complications.</seg>
          <seg id="332">Median OS and disease-free survival were 24 and 16.5 months, respectively.</seg>
          <seg id="333">SS in GC offers the possibility of long-term disease control and increased survival rate with an acceptable complication rate.</seg>
          <seg id="334">To verify the association between family resources, sociodemographic aspects, and school performance in middle school students.</seg>
          <seg id="335">Observational, analytical, cross-sectional study with a probabilistic sample stratified by sex, age, and grade in school.</seg>
          <seg id="336">A total of 124 adolescents of both sexes, aged 11 to 14 years, enrolled in a private middle school participated in the study.</seg>
          <seg id="337">We sent to their parents/guardians an online form with the Home Environment Resources Scale (HER), Brazilian Economic Classification Criteria (CCEB), and sociodemographic questions.</seg>
          <seg id="338">The school performance was furnished by the institution.</seg>
          <seg id="339">We used frequency distribution analysis of categorical variables and measures of central tendency and dispersion of the continuous ones.</seg>
          <seg id="340">We used the Mann-Whitney, Kruskal-Wallis, and Spearman correlation coefficient tests and set the significance level at p ≤ 0.05.</seg>
          <seg id="341">Most of the sample was 11 years old, females, sixth graders, with very good school performance, belonging to social class A, and whose householder had a bachelor's degree.</seg>
          <seg id="342">Age and grade in school were associated with interaction with the parents, 'family-school connection', and total HER score.</seg>
          <seg id="343">The 'proximal processes' had a moderate positive correlation with outings and toys.</seg>
          <seg id="344">There was a moderate positive correlation between total HER score and 'predictable activities that indicate stability'.</seg>
          <seg id="345">The 'proximal processes' had a strong positive correlation with 'family-school connection'.</seg>
          <seg id="346">There was a weak positive correlation between books available at home and school performance.</seg>
          <seg id="347">The family resources were related to the adolescents' school performance.</seg>
          <seg id="348">This study aims to know the current scenario of speech audiology therapy activities at NHS in Brazil, identifying its obstacles and perspectives, as well as verifying the adequacy of national NHS Programs to the pre-established quality indicators.</seg>
          <seg id="349">Analytical observational study, carried out with speech therapists in the exercise of NHS in Brazil, between August 2018 and August 2019, through a structured online questionnaire.</seg>
          <seg id="350">Descriptive and correlational analyzes of the data were performed using the SPSS version 22.0 program.</seg>
          <seg id="351">The effective practice of NHS was not entirely consistent with official protocols.</seg>
          <seg id="352">48.5% of speech therapists stated that NHS interruption at some point in the workplace, especially due to the need to repair the equipment (64.7%).</seg>
          <seg id="353">As for the flow records and care-related data, which include quality indicators there was greater control over the total number of neonates who underwent NHS (87.9%) and less control over false-positive results (21.2%).</seg>
          <seg id="354">81.8% of speech-language-hearing therapists said they were available to use a system for recording and controlling NHS data.</seg>
          <seg id="355">Although professionals' practices are generally consistent with official protocols, the non-linearity of the process and the lack of data control are important obstacles to the quality of NHS services.</seg>
          <seg id="356">Most of the national NHS programs presented do not meet the pre-established quality indicators.</seg>
          <seg id="357">It is considered that the computerization of records can benefit professionals and enhance the implementation of NHS provided for in Brazilian laws and public policies.</seg>
          <seg id="358">This study described changes in meal frequency over a 5-year period among adolescents living in the Rio de Janeiro metropolitan region.</seg>
          <seg id="359">The data used were from two cross-sectional, population-based studies conducted by home visits.</seg>
          <seg id="360">In 2005 the final sample was 1089 households with 511 adolescents (aged 12 to 18 years) and in 2010, 1121 households with 314 adolescents.</seg>
          <seg id="361">Meal frequency was obtained through self-administered questionnaire and the adolescents were assessed for appropriate weight by BMI cut-off points, by sex and age group.</seg>
          <seg id="362">Increasingly, traditional daily lunch was replaced by snacks (from 3.7% to 13.7%) and traditional dinner was eaten (62.9% to 72.0%).</seg>
          <seg id="363">Overweight adolescents ate breakfast less often than those not overweight (in 2005, 68.3% and 79.3%, p=0.02 and, in 2010, 59.5% and 77.4%, p=0.03).</seg>
          <seg id="364">Traditional daily lunch was increasingly replaced by snacks and consumption of traditional dinner increased over the 5-year period.</seg>
          <seg id="365">Also, eating breakfast every day was associated with BMI classification at both study times: those who were overweight consumed breakfast less frequently.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
      <ref lang="pt" translator="A">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">O hemoperitoneu espontâneo na gravidez é uma complicação rara, associado a morbimortalidade materna e fetal elevadas.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Na laparotomia identificou-se um hemoperitoneu com aparente origem num vaso varicoso da face posterior do útero.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Fez-se cesariana, resultando um nado-vivo. A hemorragia foi controlada com pontos hemostáticos e compressão.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Os médicos devem considerar este diagnóstico perante uma grávida com queixas de dor abdominal, anemia aguda ou sinais de choque hipovolémico.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Uma intervenção precoce prevenirá maus desfechos maternos e fetais.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Os fatores relacionados à perda de peso nos pacientes obesos submetidos à cirurgia bariátrica sempre foram exaustivamente estudados na tentativa de propor a melhor técnica cirúrgica com maior perda de peso e resolução as comorbidades à longo prazo.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Os pacientes apresentam variações anatômicas no que tange o comprimento do intestino delgado.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Há estudos que demonstram alterações de peso nos pacientes que apresentam diferentes comprimentos das alças intestinais na técnica do by-pass em Y de Roux.</seg>
          <seg id="9">O presente trabalho realizou um estudo entre a influência do IMC, a perda de peso e o comprimento da alça comum nos resultados cirúrgicos à longo prazo.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Estudo transversal descritivo pela análise retrospectiva de 112 prontuários de pacientes submetidos à cirurgia bariátrica aberta pela técnica do bypass gástrico no Hospital de Clínicas -UFPR.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Os dados foram correlacionados em programas estatísticos para este fim.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Dos 112 pacientes, 83,03% eram do sexo feminino, média de idade de 41,52 anos.</seg>
          <seg id="13">O comprimento médio do intestino delgado total dos pacientes foi de 5,02 metros. Houve uma relação diretamente proporcional entre o comprimento do intestino delgado e a perda de peso (p=0,0428).</seg>
          <seg id="14">Há uma ampla gama de variáveis relacionadas à perda de peso nos pacientes submetidos à cirurgia bariátrica, tais como a técnica utilizada, o comprimento das alças no by-pass gástrico em Y de Roux e a rotina de acompanhamento nutricional e físico do paciente.</seg>
          <seg id="15">É importante considerar os detalhes técnicos do procedimento cirúrgico, e verificar a perda de peso avaliando-se o paciente como um todo e outras variáveis.</seg>
          <seg id="16">A erradicação das formas contemporâneas de escravidão é uma relevante questão científica, social e institucional.</seg>
          <seg id="17">De fato, esforços globais têm sido feitos para compreender, mapear e eliminar a escravidão contemporânea, como um dos objetivos do Desenvolvimento Sustentável das Nações Unidas até 2030.</seg>
          <seg id="18">Entretanto, pouca atenção tem sido dada para o lugar da vigilância em saúde do trabalhador (VISAT) nas estratégias e lutas pela erradicação dessas relações de exploração.</seg>
          <seg id="19">Inicialmente, destacamos as relações entre trabalho escravo, saúde do/a trabalhador/a e a vigilância em saúde e, em seguida, apresentamos três desafios da vigilância para o enfretamento do TEC: o desafio de caracterizar setores econômicos, regiões e populações afetadas; o de identificar determinantes, riscos e efeitos à saúde; e o de fortalecer práticas e serviços de saúde do trabalhador para desencadear ações de formação, informação e intervenção em regiões de maior presença de TEC.</seg>
          <seg id="20">Conclui-se que a vigilância em saúde do trabalhador pode trazer contribuições significativas para emancipação de trabalhadores em contextos de trabalho escravo.</seg>
          <seg id="21">Este artigo tem como objetivo avaliar o papel das desigualdades sociais nos padrões de alimentação complementar nos países da América Latina e do Caribe.</seg>
          <seg id="22">Trata-se de um estudo ecológico que utilizou dados agregados de inquéritos de base populacional.</seg>
          <seg id="23">As diferenças da prevalência dos indicadores entre os quintis de riqueza mais ricos e mais pobres foram calculadas de forma absoluta e relativa.</seg>
          <seg id="24">Comparando os quatro indicadores de alimentação complementar, o IASSP teve o melhor desempenho, com 10 países, entre os 11 avaliados, apresentando prevalência acima de 80%.</seg>
          <seg id="25">O indicador com pior desempenho foi o AMA, com apenas um país, entre os oito avaliados, com prevalências acima de 60%.</seg>
          <seg id="26">Na quase totalidade dos países, a população mais pobre possuía prevalências de indicadores de alimentação complementar menores que os mais ricos.</seg>
          <seg id="27">Modelos alternativos para que os doentes tenham acesso a um programa de RC evitando a inatividade física devem ser considerados.</seg>
          <seg id="28">O objetivo deste estudo foi avaliar os níveis de atividade física (AF) de um programa digital de RC em casa.</seg>
          <seg id="29">Foram recrutados e avaliados (inicialmente e aos três meses) 116 doentes cardiovasculares (CV) (62,6±8,9 anos, 95 homens) que frequentavam um programa presencial de RC, nos seguintes parâmetros: AF, comportamento sedentário, adesão, sintomas CV e não CV, sentimentos face à pandemia, hábitos alimentares, fatores de risco, segurança e eventos adversos.</seg>
          <seg id="30">A intervenção consistiu num programa digital multidisciplinar de RC, inclusive acompanhamento regular, sessões de exercício, de ensino e de psicologia em grupo.</seg>
          <seg id="31">Completaram com sucesso todas as avaliações &lt;i&gt;online&lt;/i&gt; (15,5% &lt;i&gt;drop-out&lt;/i&gt;) 98 pessoas com doença CV.</seg>
          <seg id="32">Houve um efeito favorável no aumento da AF moderada a vigorosa e diminuição do tempo sedentário aos três meses.</seg>
          <seg id="33">Quase metade da amostra fez, pelo menos, mais de uma sessão de exercício físico &lt;i&gt;online&lt;/i&gt; por semana e assistiu a pelo menos uma das sessões educacionais &lt;i&gt;online&lt;/i&gt;. Não se verificaram eventos &lt;i&gt;major&lt;/i&gt; e registou-se apenas um &lt;i&gt;minor&lt;/i&gt;. Em tempo de pandemia, os níveis de AF moderada a vigorosa melhoraram após três meses em doentes CV que frequentavam previamente um modelo presencial de RC.</seg>
          <seg id="34">São necessários mais programas de RC com maior variedade de conteúdos adaptados à preferência individual para dar resposta às necessidades motivacionais e clínicas dos doentes CV.</seg>
          <seg id="35">Esta pesquisa destaca a moradia como uma das dimensões da vida de indivíduos que vivenciam sofrimentos psíquicos graves, que reverbera em seu cuidado e plano terapêutico singular.</seg>
          <seg id="36">Pesquisa qualitativa realizada com usuários de diferentes serviços por meio de entrevistas semiestruturadas submetidas a análise de conteúdo temática.</seg>
          <seg id="37">O estudo identificou que a noção de casa remete a proteção, individualidade e memórias afetivas que corroboram a construção de uma vida concreta ampliada no viver em liberdade na cidade, apresentando moradias plurais, localizadas em territórios distintos.</seg>
          <seg id="38">As formas de apropriação dos espaços demonstraram as possibilidades e os desafios próprios das trocas sociais e vivências cotidianas.</seg>
          <seg id="39">Estar e habitar uma casa representa ter acesso a bens materiais e subjetivos, assim como a garantia do cuidado em liberdade.</seg>
          <seg id="40">Entretanto, ainda existem limitações no exercício da efetiva participação social.</seg>
          <seg id="41">A hiperinsuflação manual é utilizada em unidades de terapia intensiva neonatal e pediátrica para promover um flow bias expiratório, porém não há consenso sobre os benefícios da técnica.</seg>
          <seg id="42">Assim faz-se necessária uma revisão que apresente suas evidências.</seg>
          <seg id="43">Este estudo objetiva revisar a literatura sobre a manobra de hiperinsuflação manual em unidades de terapia intensiva neonatal e pediátrica, para analisar as evidências dessa técnica em relação às formas de aplicação (associadas ou não a outras técnicas), sua segurança, o desempenho dos ressuscitadores manuais e a influência da experiência do fisioterapeuta, além de avaliar a qualidade metodológica dos artigos encontrados.</seg>
          <seg id="44">Realizou-se uma busca nas bases de dados: Web of Science, ScienceDirect, PubMedⓇ, Scopus, CINAHL e SciELO.</seg>
          <seg id="45">Dois pesquisadores selecionaram os artigos de forma independente.</seg>
          <seg id="46">Verificaram-se os estudos duplicados, avaliados por títulos, resumos e, então, leitura na íntegra.</seg>
          <seg id="47">Analisou-se a qualidade dos artigos pela escala PEDro.</seg>
          <seg id="48">Foram incluídos seis artigos, sendo dois com alta qualidade metodológica.</seg>
          <seg id="49">Os principais resultados trouxeram informações sobre a contribuição da válvula de pressão positiva expiratória final no aumento dos volumes pulmonares e a utilização das compressões torácicas para otimizar o flow bias expiratório, a influência negativa da experiência do operador no aumento do pico de fluxo inspiratório, o desempenho de diferentes ressuscitadores manuais durante a realização da técnica e a segurança na aplicação, com manutenção da estabilidade hemodinâmica e aumento da saturação periférica de oxigênio.</seg>
          <seg id="50">Os estudos disponíveis apontam para um efeito positivo da manobra de hiperinsuflação manual realizada em crianças internadas em unidades de terapia intensiva.</seg>
          <seg id="51">Avaliar o grau de correlação/concordância dos parâmetros Doppler materno-fetal entre fetos normais e com restrição do crescimento (restrição de crescimento fetal [RCF]).</seg>
          <seg id="52">Os seguintes parâmetros Doppler materno-fetal foram avaliados: artéria uterina (AUt), artéria umbilical (AU), artéria cerebral média (ACM), razão cérebro-placentária (RCP) e razão umbilical-cerebral (U/C).</seg>
          <seg id="53">A avaliação da RCF baseou-se nos critérios de Figueiras e Gratacós.9 Os coeficientes de correlação de Spearman foram estimados para avaliar a correlação entre os índices de resistência (IR) e pulsatilidade (IP) dos parâmetros Doppler.</seg>
          <seg id="54">A concordância entre dois parâmetros do Doppler foi avaliada pelo coeficiente Kappa.</seg>
          <seg id="55">No total, 502 exames Doppler foram incluídos e RCF foi observado em 19 de 274 fetos.</seg>
          <seg id="56">Observou-se forte correlação entre IR e IP da AUt, AU e ACM em todas as amostras (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0,001).</seg>
          <seg id="57">Dos 502 exames Doppler, houve concordância entre os percentis U/C e RCP para 480 (95,6%) e discordância para 22 (4,4%), com coeficiente Kappa de 0,26, correspondendo a concordância fraca.</seg>
          <seg id="58">Dos 68 casos com peso fetal estimado ≤ 9° (pequeno para a idade gestacional [PIG]), houve concordância entre U/C &gt; 1,0 e RC&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 5&lt;sup&gt;o&lt;/sup&gt; percentil em 61 (88,4%) e discordância em 7 (5,8%) com coeficiente Kappa de 0,49, correspondendo a concordância moderada.</seg>
          <seg id="59">Nos PIG, U/C e RCP demonstraram concordância moderada.</seg>
          <seg id="60">Doença falciforme (DF) é a condição genética mais comum no mundo, com uma prevalência variável nos continentes.</seg>
          <seg id="61">A substituição de um nucleotídeo muda um aminoácido na cadeia da β globina, e altera a estrutura normal da hemoglobina, que é então chamada de hemoglobina S, e pode ser herdada em homozigose (HbSS) ou heterozigose (HbSC, HbSβ), e leva a hemólise crônica, vaso-oclusão, inflamação, e ativação endotelial.</seg>
          <seg id="62">Realizou-se uma revisão narrativa da literatura considerando doença falciforme e gestação, as complicações clínicas e obstétricas, o cuidado antenatal específico, e o seguimento para monitoramento materno e fetal.</seg>
          <seg id="63">Gestantes com DF têm maior risco de desenvolver complicações clínicas e obstétricas, como crises dolorosas, complicações pulmonares, infecções, eventos tromboembólicos, pré-eclâmpsia, e morte materna.</seg>
          <seg id="64">E seus recém-nascidos correm maior risco de desenvovler complicações neonatais: restrição de crescimento fetal, prematuridade e óbito fetal/neonatal.</seg>
          <seg id="65">Complicações graves podem ocorrer em qualquer genótipo da doença.</seg>
          <seg id="66">Concluiu-se que DF é uma condição de alto risco que aumenta a morbimortalidade materna e perinatal.</seg>
          <seg id="67">Um seguimento com abordagem multidisciplinar na gestação e puerpério é fundamental para o diagnóstico e o tratamento das complicações.</seg>
          <seg id="68">O manejo cardíaco, ventilatório e renal no ambiente de terapia intensiva tem melhorado nas últimas décadas.</seg>
          <seg id="69">Cognição e sedação representam dois dos últimos desafios a vencer.</seg>
          <seg id="70">Como a sedação convencional não é ideal, e a sedação evocada por agonistas adrenérgicos alfa-2 (sedação “cooperativa” com dexmedetomidina, clonidina ou guanfacina) representa uma alternativa valiosa, este artigo abrange três tópicos práticos para os quais há lacunas na medicina baseada em evidência. O primeiro deles é a mudança de sedação convencional para sedação cooperativa (“mudança”): a resposta curta consiste em retirada abrupta de sedação convencional, implantação imediata de infusão de um agonista alfa-2 e uso de “sedação de resgate” (bolos de midazolam) ou “sedação agressiva” (haloperidol em bolos) para estabilizar a sedação cooperativa.</seg>
          <seg id="71">O segundo tópico é a mudança de sedação convencional para sedação cooperativa em pacientes instáveis (por exemplo: delirium tremens refratário, choque séptico, síndrome do desconforto respiratório agudo etc.), pois, para evitar a hipotensão e a bradicardia provocadas por desativadores simpáticos, a resposta curta é manter o volume sistólico por administração de volume, vasopressores e inotrópicos.</seg>
          <seg id="72">Por fim, para evitar essas mudanças e dificuldades associadas, os agonistas alfa-2 podem ser sedativos de primeira linha.</seg>
          <seg id="73">A resposta curta é administrar agonistas alfa-2 lentamente desde a admissão ou intubação endotraqueal, até estabilização da sedação cooperativa.</seg>
          <seg id="74">Dessa forma, conclui-se que os agonistas alfa-2 são, ao mesmo tempo, agentes desativadores simpáticos e sedativos, bem como a desativação simpática implica na manutenção do volume sistólico e na avaliação persistente da volemia.</seg>
          <seg id="75">A medicina baseada em evidência deve documentar esta proposta.</seg>
          <seg id="76">O objetivo desta pesquisa qualitativa foi investigar as concepções teóricas dos trabalhadores sobre o grupo bem como analisar os fatores impulsores e restritivos da prática terapêutica grupal nos Centros de Atenção Psicossocial (CAPS).</seg>
          <seg id="77">Participaram do estudo 66 trabalhadores de CAPS e ambulatórios da Rede de Atenção Psicossocial (RAPS) de 23 municípios do estado de Goiás.</seg>
          <seg id="78">A coleta de dados se deu por meio de questionário estruturado e entrevista grupal registrada em gravação de áudio e fotografias.</seg>
          <seg id="79">Da análise temática dos dados emergiram o conceito do que o grupo é e do que o grupo não é.</seg>
          <seg id="80">Tanto no eixo das forças impulsoras, quanto das forças restritivas, as categorias foram organizadas em três blocos de análise: aspectos relacionados ao serviço, aos profissionais e aos usuários.</seg>
          <seg id="81">Aspectos relacionais, estruturais, terapêuticos e a competência profissional para a coordenação de grupo se integram de modo antagônico, complementar e indissociável para apreensão da realidade estudada.</seg>
          <seg id="82">Conclui-se que evidenciar os aspectos restritivos que precisam ser reconhecidos e aprimorados bem como os impulsores que precisam ser mantidos e potencializados pode contribuir ativamente para ampliar a capacidade terapêutica do uso da tecnologia grupal no contexto da saúde mental.</seg>
          <seg id="83">Alimentos ultraprocessados são marcadores de padrões alimentares não saudáveis e seu consumo é elevado entre os adolescentes.</seg>
          <seg id="84">Características do ambiente alimentar escolar se associam a práticas alimentares de estudantes.</seg>
          <seg id="85">O objetivo do estudo foi investigar a associação entre a presença de cantinas e a disponibilidade de alimentos ultraprocessados nas cantinas com o consumo destes alimentos, dentro da escola, entre adolescentes do 9º ano do Ensino Fundamental das redes pública e particular do Município de São Paulo, Brasil.</seg>
          <seg id="86">Foi realizado um estudo transversal com dados do SP-Proso, em amostra de 2.680 adolescentes.</seg>
          <seg id="87">Foram feitos modelos de regressão linear multinível para avaliar as associações entre as exposições presença de cantinas nas escolas e disponibilidade de alimentos ultraprocessados com desfechos de frequência de consumo de ultraprocessados na escola.</seg>
          <seg id="88">A presença de cantinas esteve associada à maior frequência de consumo de embutidos (0,46; IC95%: 0,24; 0,68), salgadinhos de pacote (0,50; IC95%: 0,19; 0,80), guloseimas (0,82; IC95%: 0,55; 1,09) e bebidas açucaradas (0,34; IC95%: 0,06; 0,62), bem como um escore de frequência de consumo de ultraprocessados (2,37; IC95%: 1,25; 3,48).</seg>
          <seg id="89">A disponibilidade de salgadinhos de pacote, guloseimas e bebidas açucaradas nas cantinas aumentou a frequência de consumo desses alimentos.</seg>
          <seg id="90">Foi observado um efeito dose/resposta entre a diversidade de ultraprocessados nas cantinas e a frequência de consumo destes alimentos.</seg>
          <seg id="91">Um ambiente alimentar escolar com maior disponibilidade de ultraprocessados está associado ao maior consumo dos mesmos na escola, o que aponta para a necessidade de regulamentar o comércio de alimentos dentro destas instituições.</seg>
          <seg id="92">Estudo descritivo, transversal, de caráter quantitativo e qualitativo.</seg>
          <seg id="93">Os procedimentos contaram com cinco etapas, sendo: tradução do material; avaliação e resposta ao questionário 1 referente à tradução; determinação da validade do conteúdo; avaliação da legibilidade; disponibilização do material online e avaliação do conteúdo voltado à qualidade e a identidade visual (questionário 2).</seg>
          <seg id="94">A tradução do material apresentou taxas de concordância de validade maiores que 90%.</seg>
          <seg id="95">A legibilidade classificou o material com nível fácil de leitura.</seg>
          <seg id="96">A maior parte dos respondentes concordaram positivamente com os aspectos relacionados ao conteúdo e coerência do material traduzido, vídeos, imagens ilustrativas e legendas.</seg>
          <seg id="97">O material também foi considerado importante pela maioria dos avaliadores.</seg>
          <seg id="98">Todos os fonoaudiólogos referiram fazer uso do instrumento na prática clínica.</seg>
          <seg id="99">O material traduzido referente à ferramenta é de grande relevância, pois reúne informações práticas voltadas à criação de um caderno de experiências, bem como orientações quanto ao uso do instrumento como recurso adicional para a estimulação do desenvolvimento das habilidades auditivas e de linguagem de crianças com deficiência auditiva.</seg>
          <seg id="100">O objetivo deste estudo foi comparar a frequência de papilomavírus humano (HPV) de alto risco e citologia anal anormal em mulheres imunocompetentes com e sem lesões genitais induzidas por HPV.</seg>
          <seg id="101">Cinquenta e sete mulheres imunocompetentes com e sem lesões intraepiteliais genitais foram avaliadas. Foram divididas em dois grupos: grupo 1, composto por mulheres com lesões genitais associadas ao HPV (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 26) e grupo 2, composto por mulheres sem lesões genitais associadas ao HPV (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 31).</seg>
          <seg id="102">Amostras para citologia em meio líquido e testes de reação em cadeia da polimerase em tempo real para DNA-HPV de alto risco foram coletadas do colo do útero e do ânus.</seg>
          <seg id="103">Todos os casos foram avaliados por anuscopia de alta resolução; sendo realizada biópsia quando necessária.</seg>
          <seg id="104">Os testes exatos de Fisher e qui-quadrado foram aplicados para dados consolidados na tabela de contingência; o teste t de Student e o teste U de Mann-Whitney foram aplicados para variáveis independentes.</seg>
          <seg id="105">As infecções anais por HPV de alto risco foram mais frequentes no grupo 1 (razão de chances [RC], 4,95; intervalo de confiança [IC] de 95%, 1,34–18,3; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0,012), assim como infecções concomitantes por HPV de alto risco em colo uterino e ânus (RC 18,8; IC de 95%, 2,20–160; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0,001).</seg>
          <seg id="106">A incidência de infecção de HPV cervical de alto risco foi associada à infecção de HPV anal de alto risco (RC, 4,95; IC de 95%, 1,34–18,3; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0,012).</seg>
          <seg id="107">Não houve diferença estatística em relação à citologia anal anormal ou anuscopia entre os grupos, e não houve caso de lesão intraepitelial anal em nenhum dos grupos.</seg>
          <seg id="108">Analisar o nível de atividade física e a prática de exercício físico, examinar as características maternas associadas, assim como níveis de ansiedade de gestantes de alto risco.</seg>
          <seg id="109">Foram incluídas gestantes com idade entre de 18 e 40 anos; feto único e com idade gestacional (IG) até 38 semanas.</seg>
          <seg id="110">O nível de atividade física e prática de exercício físico das participantes do estudo foram investigados usando o Questionário de Atividade Física na Gestação (QAFG).</seg>
          <seg id="111">Os dados sociodemográficos, antropométricos e médicos maternais foram investigados usando um formulário específico.</seg>
          <seg id="112">Para níveis de ansiedade, a versão curta do Inventário de Ansiedade Traço-Estado (STAI) foi aplicado.</seg>
          <seg id="113">Usamos o teste t de Student, teste qui-quadrado, razão de chances (OR) com um intervalo de confiança de 95% (IC 95%) e regressão logística multinomial.</seg>
          <seg id="114">O nível de significância considerado foi 5%.</seg>
          <seg id="115">Das 109 gestantes incluídas no estudo, 82 (75,2%) foi classificada como sedentária/pouco ativa.</seg>
          <seg id="116">Os maiores gastos energéticos foram em atividades domésticas (133.81 ± 81.84 METs), seguidas pelas atividades ocupacionais (40.77 ± 84.71 METs).</seg>
          <seg id="117">Apenas 19.3% praticaram exercício físico durante a gravidez (4.76 ± 12.47 METs), sendo a caminhada lenta a atividade mais relatada.</seg>
          <seg id="118">Maior grau de escolaridade foi o fator mais importante associado a gestante ser moderadamente ou vigorosamente ativa (OR = 29,8; IC 95% 4,9–117,8) .</seg>
          <seg id="119">Nuliparidade (OR = 3,1; IC 95% 1,0–9,1), baixos níveis de ansiedade (OR = 3,6; IC 95% 1,2–10,7) e não trabalhar na gestação (OR = 4,8; IC 95% 1.1–19,6) foram associados à prática de exercício físico durante a gestação.</seg>
          <seg id="120">Reconhecer os fatores que dificultam a adoção de um estilo de vida mais ativo fisicamente é fundamental para a orientação adequada e individualizada acerca da prática de exercício físico durante a gestação.</seg>
          <seg id="121">O objetivo deste estudo foi avaliar as funções do ventrículo esquerdo (VE) e do átrio esquerdo (AE) por ecocardiograma strain (ES) em pacientes com acromegalia.</seg>
          <seg id="122">Este estudo incluiu 50 pacientes com acromegalia na forma ativa da doença e 50 controles saudáveis com idade, sexo e área de superfície corporal similares.</seg>
          <seg id="123">Além dos ecocardiogramas de rotina, medições de SLG-VE e SAE foram realizadas com o ES.</seg>
          <seg id="124">Os valores dos SAE e SLG-VE foram significativamente mais baixos em pacientes com acromegalia (p&lt;0,05 para todos).</seg>
          <seg id="125">Na análise bivariada, a pressão arterial sistólica, o pró-hormônio N-terminal do peptídeo natriurético cerebral, o fator de crescimento semelhante à insulina tipo 1, e detectou-se que os níveis de IMVE tinham correlação positiva com SAE e SLG-VE (p&lt;0,05).</seg>
          <seg id="126">O nível de IGF-1 tinha forte correlação com SAE e SLG-VE (p&lt;0,001 e β=0,5 vs. p&lt;0,001 e β=0,626, respectivamente); 48% dos pacientes com acromegalia têm SLG-VE reduzido (&lt;20%).</seg>
          <seg id="127">O índice de massa do ventrículo esquerdo (IMVE) determina independentemente a presença de SLG-VE reduzido, e cada 1g/m2 de aumento no nível de IMVE aumenta a probabilidade de redução de SLG-VE em 6%.</seg>
          <seg id="128">Embora a fração de ejeção de VE seja normal em pacientes com acromegalia, os valores de SAE e SLG-VE são significativamente mais baixos.</seg>
          <seg id="129">Além do aumento em IMVE, outro achado do envolvimento cardíaco pode ser a redução de SAE e SLG-VE.</seg>
          <seg id="130">Portanto, além do ecocardiograma de rotina, SAE e SLG-VE podem ser úteis para avaliar os sinais iniciais de envolvimento cardíaco antes da ocorrência de alterações cardíacas irreversíveis.</seg>
          <seg id="131">O estudo genético tem como objetivo identificar indivíduos em risco de cancro hereditário.</seg>
          <seg id="132">Na última década, verificou-se um aumento significativo do número de genes analisados devido ao surgimento de painéis de sequenciação multi-gene.</seg>
          <seg id="133">O objetivo deste estudo foi traduzir o WOSI para português e analisar a sua validade e fiabilidade para a população portuguesa com instabilidade do ombro.</seg>
          <seg id="134">Foram efetuadas as análises de consistência interna e teste-reteste para determinar o seu nível de fiabilidade.</seg>
          <seg id="135">Relativamente à validade de constructo, a correlação entre o WOSI-PT e a QuickDASH foi alta e negativa (-0,79).</seg>
          <seg id="136">A correlação entre o WOSI-PT e o SF-12 foi positiva e moderada para a componente física (0,66) e positiva e baixa para a componente de saúde mental (0,34).</seg>
          <seg id="137">A busca cobriu as bases de dados científicos MEDLINE, Lilacs, Ibecs, Cinahl, SciELO, Cochrane, Scopus, Web of Science e literatura cinzenta.</seg>
          <seg id="138">Utilizaram-se os critérios Quality Assessment of Diagnostic Accuracy Studies para avaliar a qualidade da metodologia e o risco de viés dos estudos.</seg>
          <seg id="139">A heterogeneidade estatística da razão de verossimilhança (LR) e razão de chance diagnóstica (RCD) do diagnóstico foram avaliadas com utilização de gráficos em floresta, teste Q de Cochran e um gráfico crosshair summary Receiver Operating Characteristic, utilizando um modelo com múltiplos pontos de corte.</seg>
          <seg id="140">Inicialmente obteve-se, nas bases de dados, um total de 3.522 referências; dentre estas, selecionaram-se para análise qualitativa 12 estudos que incluíram 1.757 participantes.</seg>
          <seg id="141">Muitos estudos apresentavam um risco de viés incerto em termos da seleção de pacientes e do fluxo e tempo.</seg>
          <seg id="142">Dentre os 12 estudos incluídos, sete tinham alto risco e cinco risco incerto para o item padrão de referência. O desempenho diagnóstico do pico de fluxo da tosse para o resultado da extubação foi baixo a moderado quando se consideram os resultados de todos os estudos incluídos, com +LR de 1,360 (IC95% 1,240 - 1,530), -LR de 0,218 (IC95% 0,159 - 0,293) e razão de chance diagnóstica de 6,450 (IC95% 4,490 - 9,090).</seg>
          <seg id="143">Uma análise de subgrupos que incluiu somente estudos com valores de corte entre 55 e 65 L/minuto demonstrou desempenho ligeiramente melhor, porém ainda moderado.</seg>
          <seg id="144">A avaliação do pico de fluxo da tosse, considerando valor de corte entre 55 e 65 L/minuto, pode ser útil como medida complementar antes da extubação.</seg>
          <seg id="145">São necessários estudos com melhor delineamento para elucidar o melhor método e equipamento para registrar o pico de fluxo da tosse, assim como o melhor ponto de corte.</seg>
          <seg id="146">O objetivo deste estudo é descrever as complicações obstétricas e a taxa de transmissão vertical em grávidas com infeção a SARS-CoV-2.</seg>
          <seg id="147">Foram recolhidos dados epidemiológicos, da gravidez e do parto.</seg>
          <seg id="148">A comorbilidade materna mais frequente foi a obesidade.</seg>
          <seg id="149">A taxa de parto pré-termo e de leves para a idade gestacional foi de 12,1% e 9,9%, respectivamente.</seg>
          <seg id="150">No terceiro trimestre, 2,9% das grávidas necessitaram de suporte respiratório.</seg>
          <seg id="151">Verificou-se uma taxa de 1,5% de morte fetal, incluindo dois casos de transmissão vertical.</seg>
          <seg id="152">Houve cinco casos de degradação respiratória no pós-parto, mas sem mortes maternas registadas.</seg>
          <seg id="153">A taxa de cesarianas foi mais elevada na primeira do que na segunda vaga (68,5% vs 31,5%).</seg>
          <seg id="154">A positividade do RT-PCR SARS-CoV-2 entre os recém-nascidos foi de 1,3%.</seg>
          <seg id="155">Descrever a eficácia e a segurança da embolização de proteção na embolização de artérias prostáticas e discutir sua relevância clínica.</seg>
          <seg id="156">Estudo retrospectivo, observacional, de um único centro, que inclui 39 pacientes submetidos a embolização de artérias prostáticas para tratamento de sintomas do trato urinário inferior relacionados a hiperplasia benigna da próstata, de junho de 2008 a março de 2018.</seg>
          <seg id="157">O acompanhamento foi realizado em 3 meses e 12 meses, incluindo International Prostate Symptom Score, escore de qualidade de vida, antígeno prostático específico, ultrassom, ressonância magnética e urofluxometria.</seg>
          <seg id="158">Embolização de proteção foi realizada em 45 artérias: artérias retais médias em 19 (42,2%); artérias pudendas internas acessórias em 11 (24,4%); anastomoses com ramos da artéria pudenda interna em 10 (22,2%); artérias vesicais superiores em quatro (8,9%); e artéria obturatória em uma (2,2%).</seg>
          <seg id="159">Houve um caso de embolização não alvo que provocou uma úlcera peniana, atribuída a refluxo de partículas para uma artéria não protegida.</seg>
          <seg id="160">Não houve complicações relacionadas com os ramos protegidos.</seg>
          <seg id="161">Os pacientes apresentaram melhora significativa em todos os resultados estudados (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0,05) e não relataram piora da função sexual durante o acompanhamento.</seg>
          <seg id="162">Embolização de proteção pode ser realizada para diminuir embolização não alvo sem interferir nos resultados da embolização de artérias prostáticas.</seg>
          <seg id="163">Além disso, não foi observado nenhum evento adverso diferente dos já esperados ou previamente publicados.</seg>
          <seg id="164">A embolização de proteção na região pudenda é segura.</seg>
          <seg id="165">Descrever as práticas clínicas atuais relacionadas à utilização de cânula nasal de alto fluxo por intensivistas pediátricos brasileiros e compará-las com as de outros países.</seg>
          <seg id="166">Para o estudo principal, foi administrado um questionário a intensivistas pediátricos em países das Américas do Norte e do Sul, Ásia, Europa e Austrália/Nova Zelândia.</seg>
          <seg id="167">Comparou-se a coorte brasileira com coortes dos Estados Unidos, Canadá, Reino Unido e Índia.</seg>
          <seg id="168">Responderam ao questionário 501 médicos, dos quais 127 eram do Brasil.</seg>
          <seg id="169">Apenas 63,8% dos participantes brasileiros tinham disponibilidade de cânula nasal de alto fluxo, em contraste com 100% dos participantes no Reino Unido, no Canadá e nos Estados Unidos.</seg>
          <seg id="170">Coube ao médico responsável a decisão de iniciar a utilização de uma cânula nasal de alto fluxo segundo responderam 61,2% dos brasileiros, 95,5% dos localizados no Reino Unido, 96,6% dos participantes dos Estados Unidos, 96,8% dos médicos canadenses e 84,7% dos participantes da Índia; 62% dos participantes do Brasil, 96,3% do Reino Unido, 96,6% dos Estados Unidos, 96,8% do Canadá e 84,7% da Índia relataram que o médico responsável era quem definia o desmame ou modificava as regulagens da cânula nasal de alto fluxo.</seg>
          <seg id="171">Quando ocorreu falha da cânula nasal de alto fluxo por desconforto respiratório ou insuficiência respiratória, 82% dos participantes do Brasil considerariam uma tentativa com ventilação não invasiva antes da intubação endotraqueal, em comparação com 93% do Reino Unido, 88% dos Estados Unidos, 91,5% do Canadá e 76,8% da Índia.</seg>
          <seg id="172">Mais intensivistas brasileiros (6,5%) do que do Reino Unido, Estados Unidos e Índia (1,6% para todos) afirmaram utilizar sedativos com frequência concomitantemente à cânula nasal de alto fluxo.</seg>
          <seg id="173">A disponibilidade de cânulas nasais de alto fluxo no Brasil ainda não é difundida.</seg>
          <seg id="174">Há algumas divergências nas práticas clínicas entre intensivistas brasileiros e seus colegas estrangeiros, principalmente nos processos e nas tomadas de decisão relacionados a iniciar e desmamar o tratamento com cânula nasal de alto fluxo.</seg>
          <seg id="175">Analisar a quantidade de exames cérvico-vaginais, também chamados de Teste de Papanicolau, entre os anos de 2006 e 2015 em todos os estados brasileiros, bem como verificar o número de exames realizados fora da faixa etária indicada, e o impacto econômico desse excesso.</seg>
          <seg id="176">Foi verificada a quantidade de exames fora da idade recomendada, e, assim, foi observado o impacto econômico gerado.</seg>
          <seg id="177">Entre 2006 e 2015, 87.425.549 exames de Papanicolau foram realizados no Brasil.</seg>
          <seg id="178">Deste montante, 20.215.052 testes foram realizados fora da faixa-etária preconizada pelo Ministério da Saúde do Brasil, o que equivale a 23,12% do total.</seg>
          <seg id="179">A partir desse número, considerando que cada exame cérvico -vaginal realizado pelo SUS gera um custo de R$ 7,30 para o governo, de acordo com informações na Tabela SUS datada de setembro de 2018, foram gastos R$ 147.569.880 em exames realizados sem indicação.</seg>
          <seg id="180">CONCLUSãO:  No Brasil, no protocolo do Ministério da Saúde sobre as práticas adequadas em coleta de exames cérvico-vaginais, sendo sua edição mais recente de 2016, a recomendação é realizar o teste de Papanicolau em mulheres dentro de uma faixa-etária específica, na qual a chance de se diagnosticar uma lesão supera o ônus de um sobrediagnóstico ou uma lesão com grande potencial de regressão.</seg>
          <seg id="181">Entretanto, essa recomendação não tem sido seguida corretamente, gerando mais de 20 milhões de exames excedentes e um custo monetário exorbitante para o sistema público de saúde.</seg>
          <seg id="182">É importante que medidas sejam tomadas para que o protocolo seja empregado corretamente a fim de reduzir riscos para a paciente, bem como a redução de gastos desnecessários para o SUS.</seg>
          <seg id="183">O avanço em endoscopia digestiva e a existência de sistemas open-acess levaram a um aumento quantitativo de endoscopias.</seg>
          <seg id="184">Porém, a sobreutilização da endoscopia tem sido reportada na literatura.</seg>
          <seg id="185">Este estudo tem como objetivo aferir prospectivamente as indicações para endoscopia digestiva alta (EDA) e endoscopia digestiva baixa (EDB) em unidades de saúde públicas e privadas.</seg>
          <seg id="186">Adequabilidade da indicação definida pelas recomendações da American Society for Gastrointestinal Endoscopy (EDA) e do European Panel on Appropriateness of Gastrointestinal Endoscopy II (EDB).</seg>
          <seg id="187">&lt;i&gt;EDA:&lt;/i&gt; Incluídos 215 doentes (masculino – 43.7%; idade média – 61.0 ± 15.11 anos), 54.0% (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 116) em unidades hospitalares públicas.</seg>
          <seg id="188">Referenciação por gastrenterologista em 34.9% (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 75).</seg>
          <seg id="189">Indicação considerada adequada em 62.3% (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 134): 42.4% em unidades privadas versus 79.3% em unidades públicas (odds ratio [OR] 5.20, 95% confidence interval [CI] 2.85–9.49, &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.01).</seg>
          <seg id="190">Indicação adequada em 74.7% com referenciação por gastrenterologista versus 56.1% por não-gastrenterologista (OR 2.31, 95% CI 1.24–4.28; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.01).</seg>
          <seg id="191">Identificados achados endoscópicos relevantes em 47.9%.</seg>
          <seg id="192">Referenciação por gastrenterologista em 20.6% (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 59).</seg>
          <seg id="193">A indicação foi considerada adequada em 70.0% (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 201): 53.0% em unidade privada versus 88.4% em unidade pública (OR 6.75, 95% CI 3.66–12.47; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.01).</seg>
          <seg id="194">Neste estudo, uma percentagem significativa dos procedimentos endoscópicos foi realizada sem indicação apropriada, especialmente no sector privado, o que influenciou a rentabilidade diagnóstica.</seg>
          <seg id="195">A prescrição tendo por base critérios definidos é fundamental para o uso racional de um sistema de acesso livre.</seg>
          <seg id="196">A cardiomiopatia hipertrófica (CMH) pode causar obstrução da via de saída do ventrículo esquerdo (VSVE) e ser responsável pelo surgimento de sintomas limitantes, como cansaço físico.</seg>
          <seg id="197">Quando tais sintomas são refratários ao tratamento farmacológico, os tratamentos alternativos intervencionistas podem ser úteis, como a ablação septal por meio da infusão de álcool na artéria coronária ou por meio da miectomia cirúrgica.</seg>
          <seg id="198">Recentemente, o uso de cateter de radiofrequência (RF) para ablação do septo endocárdico guiado por mapeamento eletroanatômico mostrou-se eficaz apesar da elevada incidência de bloqueio atrioventricular total.</seg>
          <seg id="199">Uma alternativa seria a aplicação de radiofrequência no ponto de início do gradiente septal guiada pelo ecocardiograma transesofágico (ETE).</seg>
          <seg id="200">O ecocardiograma é um método de imagem com elevada acurácia para determinação da anatomia septal.</seg>
          <seg id="201">Avaliar o efeito em longo prazo da ablação septal para alívio do gradiente ventrículo-arterial, utilizando o ETE para auxiliar no posicionamento do cateter na área de maior obstrução septal.</seg>
          <seg id="202">Avaliar também os efeitos da ablação na classe funcional e parâmetros ecocardiográficos.</seg>
          <seg id="203">Doze pacientes sintomáticos com obstrução da VSVE, refratários à terapia farmacológica, foram submetidos à ablação endocárdica septal com cateteres com ponta de 8 mm, cujo posicionamento foi orientado na região de maior obstrução com auxílio do ETE.</seg>
          <seg id="204">Após cada aplicação, o gradiente era reavaliado e nova aplicação era realizada de acordo com critério clínico.</seg>
          <seg id="205">Foram avaliados os efeitos das aplicações de RF tanto para o gradiente em repouso como para o provocado por meio da manobra de Valsalva, e considerado o gradiente.</seg>
          <seg id="206">As diferenças foram significativas quando o valor de p foi menor ou igual a 0,05.</seg>
          <seg id="207">Observou-se que a redução da média dos gradientes máximos obtidos foi de 96,8±34,7 mmHg para 62,7±25,4 mmHg ao final de três meses do procedimento (p=0,0036).</seg>
          <seg id="208">Após um ano, a média dos gradientes máximos obtidos foi de 36,1±23,8 mmHg (p=0,0001).</seg>
          <seg id="209">O procedimento foi bem tolerado e não houve registro de bloqueio atrioventricular total e nem complicações graves.</seg>
          <seg id="210">A ablação septal guiada pelo ETE foi eficaz e segura, com resultados mantidos durante o período de seguimento clínico.</seg>
          <seg id="211">É uma opção razoável para o tratamento intervencionista da obstrução da VSVE em CMH.</seg>
          <seg id="212">É importante saber qual medicamento usar como tratamento de primeira linha para fechar o duto.</seg>
          <seg id="213">O objetivo deste estudo é comparar a eficácia e os efeitos colaterais das formas intravenosas (IV) de ibuprofeno e paracetamol e contribuir para a literatura investigando o primeiro medicamento selecionado no tratamento clínico da persistência do canal arterial (PCA).</seg>
          <seg id="214">Nosso estudo foi realizado entre janeiro de 2017 e dezembro de 2019.</seg>
          <seg id="215">Foram incluídos no estudo bebês prematuros com peso ao nascer (PN) ≤1500 g e idade gestacional (IG) ≤32 semanas.</seg>
          <seg id="216">No período do estudo, todos os bebês com persistência do canal arterial hemodinamicamente significativa (hsPCA) receberam ibuprofeno intravenoso (IV) como resgate como tratamento clínico primário ou tratamento com paracetamol IV se houvesse contraindicações para o ibuprofeno.</seg>
          <seg id="217">Os pacientes foram divididos em dois grupos: pacientes que receberam ibuprofeno IV e pacientes que receberam paracetamol IV.</seg>
          <seg id="218">Desses pacientes, 101 receberam paracetamol IV e 169 receberam ibuprofeno IV.</seg>
          <seg id="219">A taxa de sucesso do fechamento da PCA com o primeiro curso do tratamento foi de 74,3% no grupo de paracetamol IV e 72,8% no grupo de ibuprofeno IV (p=0,212).</seg>
          <seg id="220">Nossos resultados mostram que o paracetamol IV é tão eficaz quanto o ibuprofeno IV no tratamento de primeira linha de hsPCA, podendo se tornar o tratamento preferencial para o controle de hsPCA.</seg>
          <seg id="221">A doença hepática gordurosa não-alcoólica já é considerada um problema de saúde pública, principalmente em pacientes com obesidade severa.</seg>
          <seg id="222">O objetivo do presente estudo foi investigar os diferentes escores de bioquímiosa disponíveis e determinar qual deles poderia servir melhor como uma ferramenta de avaliação da NAFLD em uma população de obesos.</seg>
          <seg id="223">Este é um estudo transversal de pacientes obesos.</seg>
          <seg id="224">Todos os pacientes foram avaliados com parâmetros laboratoriais séricos 1 semana antes da biópsia e todos os pacientes foram submetidos a biópsia hepática intra-operatória, durante a cirurgia bariátrica.</seg>
          <seg id="225">Cento e quarenta e três pacientes obesos foram incluídos.</seg>
          <seg id="226">APRI mostrou alta especificidade (82%) e baixa sensibilidade (54%).</seg>
          <seg id="227">Em contraste, o HOMA-IR apresentou alta sensibilidade (84%) e baixa especificidade (48%).</seg>
          <seg id="228">O NALFDS, FIB-4, AST / ALT e HSI não têm utilidade para avaliação de esteatose grave em pacientes com obesidade severa.</seg>
          <seg id="229">Diabetes e avaliação bioquímica relacionada à resistência à insulina, como o HOMA-IR, podem ser empregados como boas ferramentas de rastreamento para esteatose grave em tais pacientes.</seg>
          <seg id="230">O escore APRI é a ferramenta diagnóstica bioquímica mais específica para esteatose em pacientes com obesidade severa e pode ser empregado, por equipes médicas, para auxiliar na indicação de cirurgia bariátrica ou metabólica.</seg>
          <seg id="231">O tratamento endoscópico das varizes esofágicas tem sido utilizado como principal intervenção em pacientes com hipertensão portal secundária à esquistossomose, mas com taxas significativas de recorrência de varizes esofágicas e ressangramento.</seg>
          <seg id="232">Os resultados em longo prazo do tratamento endoscópico exclusivo são pouco estudados quanto à relação das dimensões esplênicas neste contexto.</seg>
          <seg id="233">Avaliar, por meio da ultrassonografia, o índice esplênico e a dimensão longitudinal (craniocaudal) do baço como preditores de ressangramento e recorrência de varizes no seguimento tardio de pacientes esquistossomóticos não operados, após erradicação endoscópica das varizes esofágicas.</seg>
          <seg id="234">Estudo observacional retrospectivo por meio da análise de prontuários de pacientes com diagnóstico de esquistossomose hepatoesplênica.</seg>
          <seg id="235">A curva ROC foi usada para determinar o melhor ponto de corte para o índice esplênico médio como preditor de recorrência e sangramento.</seg>
          <seg id="236">Foram analisados 54 pacientes, durante o período de 2002 a 2018.</seg>
          <seg id="237">O tempo médio de seguimento foi de 8 anos.</seg>
          <seg id="238">O índice esplênico provou ser um teste sensível em valores acima de 144 como preditor de ressangramento.</seg>
          <seg id="239">Na análise da dimensão longitudinal, o valor acima de 20 cm apresentou teste estatisticamente significativo para recorrência de varizes e valor acima de 19 cm apresentou-se como teste muito sensível e estatisticamente significativo para ressangramento.</seg>
          <seg id="240">A análise do índice esplênico e da dimensão craniocaudal, obtidos por ultrassonografia, podem predizer recorrência de varizes e ressangramento após erradicação endoscópica exclusiva.</seg>
          <seg id="241">O objetivo deste estudo foi determinar a prevalência de diferentes diagnósticos neuropsiquiátricos em doentes hospitalizados com infeção SARS-CoV-2 avaliados pela Psiquiatria de Ligação.</seg>
          <seg id="242">Revimos os processos clínicos dos pacientes internados com um resultado RT-PCR positivo para SARS-CoV-2 avaliados pela Unidade de Psiquiatria de Ligação (UPL) entre fevereiro e dezembro de 2020.</seg>
          <seg id="243">Incluímos dados sociodemográficos e clínicos, incluindo quinze sintomas neuropsiquiátricos.</seg>
          <seg id="244">A incidência de diferentes diagnósticos psiquiátricos foi o nosso outcome primário.</seg>
          <seg id="245">Delirium foi o diagnóstico mais frequente na nossa amostra (43,5%), seguido de perturbação depressiva major (21,7%).</seg>
          <seg id="246">Doentes com delirium tiveram uma prevalência maior de sintomas de COVID-19 (delirium: 19/20, 95%; sem delirium: 14/26, 53,8%; p = 0,02), bem como um intervalo de tempo mais longo entre um teste RT-PCR SARS-CoV-2 positivo e observação pela UPL (delirium: mediana = 16,5, AIQ = 16; sem delirium: mediana = 8, AIQ = 16,3; p = 0,045).</seg>
          <seg id="247">Agitação (52,2%) e sintomas cognitivos (47,8%) foram os sintomas neuropsiquiátricos mais relatados.</seg>
          <seg id="248">Este resultado está de acordo com literatura recente relativamente a doentes internados com COVID-19. A maior frequência de sintomas COVID-19 no grupo com delirium sugere uma possível associação entre infecção sintomática por SARS-CoV-2 e o desenvolvimento desta síndrome.</seg>
          <seg id="249">Quinhentas e trinta e três mulheres com citologia de AGC foram identificadas e destas, 69.41% (370) foram encaminhadas para colposcopia e nova citologia.</seg>
          <seg id="250">Na biopsia das mulheres com a 2ª citologia de AGC, 43.4% (10/23) tinham histologia normal, 43.4% (10/23) tinha lesões escamosas, 8.7% (2/23) tinha adenocarcinoma invasor e 1.2% (1/23) tinha laudo inconclusivo.</seg>
          <seg id="251">Todas as mulheres com lesões intraepiteliais escamosas de alto grau (HSIL, na sigla em inglês) ou adenocarcinoma invasor (respectivamente 5 e 2 pacientes), após a 2ª citologia com AGC, tinham 25 anos de idade ou mais.</seg>
          <seg id="252">Muitos casos de citologia com AGC apareceram em mulheres adultas, entre 25 e 54 anos de idade.</seg>
          <seg id="253">Embora a maioria das pacientes tiveram histologia normal após seguimento, várias apresentaram lesões intraepiteliais escamosas ou glandulares invasoras.</seg>
          <seg id="254">O processo de Reforma Psiquiátrica Brasileira (RPB) propõe o rompimento com o paradigma manicomial em diversas dimensões.</seg>
          <seg id="255">Pensar nos espaços de cuidado e no direito à cidade constituem bandeiras importantes para tal.</seg>
          <seg id="256">Dessa forma, construímos um arcabouço teórico-conceitual objetivando discutir e sistematizar a relação da arquitetura dos espaços de cuidado destinados à loucura e à produção de subjetividades e relações.</seg>
          <seg id="257">Assim, a partir da arqueogenealogia, organizamos um diálogo entre conceitos e autores que abordem o espaço e a arquitetura como dispositivos de produção de subjetividades e relações, tais como, instituições totais e mortificação do eu (Erving Goffman) e síndrome espaço-comportamental (Mirian de Carvalho), e experiências como as de Maura Lopes Cançado e Lima Barreto.</seg>
          <seg id="258">Objetivamos, ainda, discutir e desenhar, pelas lentes de campos diversos de saber, um ideal de cidade que nos ajude a enfrentar o paradigma manicomial e fortalecer o processo de RPB: a cidade aberta, aquela que inclui a diferença.</seg>
          <seg id="259">Ao localizarmos a importância da discussão das arquiteturas, dos espaços e da cidade que construímos para o processo de RPB, propomos, como resultado deste artigo, construir e adicionar uma nova dimensão de análise de tal processo às já existentes: a dimensão espacial.</seg>
          <seg id="260">As pacientes foram acompanhadas por um período médio de 132 meses a partir da primeira cirurgia.</seg>
          <seg id="261">Após a NSM, 5 (20,8%) pacientes foram diagnosticadas com recorrência local, e apenas 1 paciente foi a óbito.</seg>
          <seg id="262">As pacientes apresentaram 4,8% de necrose parcial e 2,4% de necrose total do mamilo.</seg>
          <seg id="263">CONCLUSãO:  Em um longo período de acompanhamento desde a primeira cirurgia, foram observadas baixas taxas de complicação pós-operatória e boa sobrevida, porém, associadas com uma alta taxa de recorrência local em pacientes submetidas a NSM para tratamento de recidiva local após cirurgia conservadora.</seg>
          <seg id="264">Neste estudo, demonstrou-se que a NSM pode ser considerada uma opção cirúrgica para pacientes que não querem se submeter a mastectomia total.</seg>
          <seg id="265">A análise estatística foi feita utilizando-se o teste &lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt; de Student, e valores de &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0,05 foram considerados estatisticamente significativos.</seg>
          <seg id="266">Os níveis séricos de malondialdeído sérico estavam aumentados (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0,0001), e a capacidade antioxidante total, reduzida no grupo PE (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0,034), o que indicava estresse oxidativo.</seg>
          <seg id="267">No grupo PE, a pressão arterial média era significativamente maior (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0,0001), mas os níveis séricos de NO não demostraram redução estatisticamente significativa (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0,20).</seg>
          <seg id="268">O perfil de expressão genética da NOS3 e da NOS2 revelou uma regulação negativa no grupo PE de 8,49 e 51,05 vezes, respectivamente.</seg>
          <seg id="269">O NO pode desempenhar um papel neste mecanismo, mas as interações com outras substâncias vasoativas/biológicas não podem ser negligenciadas, uma vez que a expressão genética da NOS3 e da NOS2 foi reduzida.</seg>
          <seg id="270">Identificar evidências atuais sobre topiramato para o estado de mal epiléptico refratário.</seg>
          <seg id="271">Foi revisada a literatura para investigar a eficácia do topiramato no tratamento de estado de mal epiléptico refratário.</seg>
          <seg id="272">Os termos de busca utilizados foram: “status epilepticus”, “refractory”, “treatment” e “topiramate”.</seg>
          <seg id="273">Não se empregaram restrições.</seg>
          <seg id="274">A busca identificou 487 artigos que descreviam o uso de topiramato para tratamento de estado de mal epiléptico refratário e seus resultados.</seg>
          <seg id="275">Relatos de caso, revisões e experimentos em animais foram excluídos.</seg>
          <seg id="276">Após exclusão de duplicatas e aplicação dos critérios de inclusão e exclusão, restaram nove estudos.</seg>
          <seg id="277">Realizaram-se análises descritivas e qualitativas, com os seguintes resultados: as taxas de resposta, definidas como término de crises até 72 horas após administração de topiramato, variaram entre 27% e 100%.</seg>
          <seg id="278">A mortalidade variou de 5,9% a 68%.</seg>
          <seg id="279">Desfechos funcionais positivos, definidos como alta hospitalar, volta à funcionalidade basal ou reabilitação, foram documentados por sete estudos, e as taxas variaram entre 4% e 55%.</seg>
          <seg id="280">A maioria dos estudos reportou apenas efeitos colaterais leves ou ausentes.</seg>
          <seg id="281">Topiramato foi efetivo em abortar estado de mal epiléptico refratário, apresentando baixa mortalidade e boa tolerabilidade.</seg>
          <seg id="282">Portanto, topiramato poderia ser uma boa opção como terceira linha para estado de mal epiléptico refratário, porém mais estudos são necessários.</seg>
          <seg id="283">Foi demonstrado que as subunidades de interleucina-35 (IL-35) estão fortemente expressas nas placas ateroscleróticas em humanos.</seg>
          <seg id="284">Assim, considera-se que elas têm um papel na aterosclerose.</seg>
          <seg id="285">Neste estudo, os níveis de IL-35 foram comparados com o grupo controle em pacientes com doença arterial coronariana (DAC) estável, e a associação entre os níveis de IL-35 e o tipo, gravidade e extensão da lesão foram investigadas com o escore Gensini (GS) e o escore Syntax (SS) no grupo de pacientes.</seg>
          <seg id="286">Sessenta pacientes (18 mulheres e 42 homens) com DAC, diagnosticados por meio da angiografia coronária, que apresentaram dor no peito típica e teste de esforço não invasivo positivo, e 46 pacientes (18 mulheres e 28 homens) com luminograma normal, foram incluídos no estudo.</seg>
          <seg id="287">Tanto o GS quanto o SS foram calculados para o grupo de pacientes, e esses valores foram comparados com os níveis de IL-35.</seg>
          <seg id="288">Variáveis com distribuição não normal foram avaliadas com o teste U de Mann-Whitney, enquanto os parâmetros com distribuição normal foram analisados com o teste t de Student.</seg>
          <seg id="289">A diferença entre as variáveis categóricas foi avaliada pelo teste de qui-quadrado ou de Fisher.</seg>
          <seg id="290">Os valores de p&lt;0,05 foram considerados como estatisticamente sinificativos.</seg>
          <seg id="291">Não foram observadas diferenças significativas entre pacientes e o grupo controle em termos de características demográficas e achados laboratoriais.</seg>
          <seg id="292">Em comparação ao grupo controle, os níveis de IL-35 no grupo com DAC foram consideravalmente menores (36,9±63,9 ng/ml vs. 33,2±13,2 ng/ml, p&lt;0,008).</seg>
          <seg id="293">Embora não tenha sido estatisticamente significativo, os níveis de IL-35 foram maiores em pacientes com SS mais baixo do que nos com SS mais alto (33,2±13,7 vs. 31,8±8,9, p=0,51).</seg>
          <seg id="294">Os valores de IL-35 em pacientes com GS alto foram significativamente mais baixos do que em pacientes com GS baixo (35±17,4 vs. 30,7±8,6, p=0,043).</seg>
          <seg id="295">Demonstrou-se que os níveis de IL-35 podem ser um novo biomarcador para a DAC estável, e que a IL-35 está associada à extensão da DAC.</seg>
          <seg id="296">A manutenção do rebordo ósseo alveolar é prerrogativa para o sucesso da terapia com implantes.</seg>
          <seg id="297">A fibrina rica em plaquetas (PRF) poderia beneficiar o reparo ósseo, mas seus resultados microscópicos quantitativos são ainda inconclusivos.</seg>
          <seg id="298">O objetivo deste trabalho foi analisar histomorfometricamente alvéolos dentários humanos pós-extração tratados com fibrina autóloga, fosfato de cálcio bifásico ou sua associação.</seg>
          <seg id="299">A amostra consistiu de pacientes adultos voluntários saudáveis, com indicação clínica e tomográfica de enxerto unitário pós-exodontia de pré-molares superiores para manutenção de rebordo alveolar e posterior implante.</seg>
          <seg id="300">Os 10 pacientes remanescentes no estudo foram divididos em 3 grupos de acordo com o tipo de preenchimento usado no alvéolo dentário: plug de PRF autóloga recoberto por membrana de PRF (G1), PRF associada a enxerto aloplástico de hidroxiapatita com beta fosfato tricálcio recoberto por membrana de colágeno (G2) ou enxerto aloplástico de beta fosfato tricálcio recoberto por membrana de colágeno (controle).</seg>
          <seg id="301">Após 8 meses, foram realizadas biópsias ósseas nos locais enxertados e os pacientes seguiram a reabilitação implanto-protético.</seg>
          <seg id="302">Blocos histológicos incluídos em parafina foram microtomizados para gerar 3 lâminas de secções em diferentes profundidades, que foram coradas em HE.</seg>
          <seg id="303">A avaliação histomorfométrica analisou 30 fotomicrografias por bloco, quantificando a presença percentual de osso neoformado, tecido conjuntivo e biomaterial remanescente pelo programa ImageJ. Os dados paramétricos permitiram comparações intergrupos usando ANOVA e pós-teste de comparações múltiplas de Tukey com significância estatística de 5% (p&lt;0,05), havendo normalidade dos 3 grupos pelo teste Jarque-Bera (p&gt;0,05).</seg>
          <seg id="304">Houve maior média de osso neoformado em G1 (68,83%) em comparação a G2 (35,69%) e controle (16,28%).</seg>
          <seg id="305">Houve maior presença de tecido conjuntivo no controle (61,56 %).</seg>
          <seg id="306">Biomaterial remanescente foi maior em G2 (15,75%), mas não diferiu estatisticamente para o controle.</seg>
          <seg id="307">A regeneração óssea obtida com PRF isolada ou em associação sugere a eficácia destas terapias, encorajando o uso clínico deste concentrado sanguíneo em procedimentos odontológicos.</seg>
          <seg id="308">Descrever a qualidade de vida (QV) do fonoaudiólogo brasileiro e relacionar com aspectos sociodemográficos, profissiográficos e relativos à atuação na pandemia de COVID-19.</seg>
          <seg id="309">Estudo epidemiológico de base populacional, transversal.</seg>
          <seg id="310">A pesquisa envolveu fonoaudiólogos do Brasil, que foram convidados a responder, on-line, o formulário WHOQOL-bref sobre a sua saúde e QV, além de questões sociodemográficas e profissiográficas.</seg>
          <seg id="311">Participaram 609 fonoaudiólogos na faixa etária entre 21 e 65 anos e média de 34 anos.</seg>
          <seg id="312">Menores pontuações no domínio físico da QV foram dadas por fonoaudiólogos do sexo feminino, que faziam atendimento ambulatorial, não trabalhavam em clínica particular, atuavam de forma indireta na pandemia, se afastaram do trabalho e cujo motivo de afastamento foram aspectos psicoemocionais; no domínio psicológico, sexo feminino, ausência de companheiro, que trabalhavam em clínica particular ou outro local e que atuaram de forma direta ou indireta na pandemia; no domínio relações sociais, ausência de companheiro, em atendimento ambulatorial, mas não em clínicas particulares; e no domínio meio ambiente, menores escores na raça/cor preta e parda, nos com ausência de companheiro, que faziam atendimento domiciliar, mas não em clínica particular ou gestão/administrativo ou outro.</seg>
          <seg id="313">O fonoaudiólogo brasileiro apresentou mais baixos escores de QV nos domínios psicológico e meio ambiente e verificou-se que a sua QV está relacionada a fatores como sexo, cor/raça, presença de companheiro, região do conselho, ambientes de atendimento, atuação direta com pacientes de COVID e diagnóstico de COVID-19.</seg>
          <seg id="314">Desde a instituição da circulação extracorpórea, há cinco décadas, a lesão cerebral decorrente desse procedimento durante cirurgias cardiovasculares tem sido uma complicação frequente.</seg>
          <seg id="315">Não existe uma causa única de lesão cerebral pelo uso de circulação extracorpórea, porém se sabe que acomete cerca de 70% dos pacientes submetidos a esse procedimento.</seg>
          <seg id="316">A avaliação da pressão intracraniana é um dos métodos que podem orientar os cuidados com os pacientes submetidos a procedimentos associados com distúrbios neurológicos.</seg>
          <seg id="317">Este artigo descreve dois casos de pacientes submetidos à cirurgia cardiovascular com circulação extracorpórea, para os quais os procedimentos de neuroproteção na fase pós-operatória foram guiados pelos achados relacionados ao formato das ondas de pressão intracraniana, obtidos por meio de um método não invasivo de monitoramento.</seg>
          <seg id="318">As mulheres possuem variáveis metabólicas, imunológicas e genéticas que conferem maior proteção à infecção pelo coronavírus.</seg>
          <seg id="319">Todavia, a indicação de tratamento para certas patologias e para a contracepção é determinada por hormônios que possuem efeitos adversos e levantam dúvidas quanto ao seu uso durante a pandemia da COVID-19.</seg>
          <seg id="320">Desta forma, o presente estudo busca investigar as especificidades da mulher e a relação dos hormônios sexuais femininos com a COVID-19, assim como relatar as principais recomendações neste contexto.</seg>
          <seg id="321">Para isso, realizou-se uma revisão da literatura nas principais bases de dados, fontes auxiliares de dados e sites oficiais.</seg>
          <seg id="322">Portanto, considerando o estado hipercoagulável da COVID-19, surge o debate quanto à utilização de contraceptivos pelo seu risco relativo de efeitos tromboembólicos.</seg>
          <seg id="323">No entanto, as atuais evidências disponíveis, assim como as recomendações dos principais órgãos de saúde do mundo, demonstraram que o uso de contraceptivos hormonais deve ser mantido durante a pandemia.</seg>
          <seg id="324">A cirurgia de resgate é definida como a ressecção cirúrgica após falha de primeiro tratamento com intuito curativo.</seg>
          <seg id="325">Análise retrospectiva dos pacientes com câncer gástrico operados entre 2009 e 2020.</seg>
          <seg id="326">40 pacientes foram submetidos à tentativa de gastrectomia de resgate com intuito curativo.</seg>
          <seg id="327">Para análise, foram divididos em dois grupos: 23 pacientes após ressecção endoscópica e 17 após gastrectomia.</seg>
          <seg id="328">No primeiro grupo, todos tiveram ressecção com margens livres, a média de internação foi 15,7 dias e 2 (8,6%) tiveram complicações maiores.</seg>
          <seg id="329">No seguimento médio de 37,2 meses, houve apenas 1 recidiva.</seg>
          <seg id="330">A sobrevida global média foi 46 meses.</seg>
          <seg id="331">No grupo pós-gastrectomia 9 (52,9%) foram resgatados com intenção curativa, a média de internação foi 12,2 dias e 3 (17,6%) apresentaram complicações maiores.</seg>
          <seg id="332">A sobrevida global média e a sobrevida livre de doença foram respectivamente: 24 e 16,5 meses.</seg>
          <seg id="333">A cirurgia de resgate no câncer gástrico oferece nova possibilidade de controle da doença a longo prazo e/ou aumento de sobrevida, tendo taxa de complicações aceitáveis.</seg>
          <seg id="334">Verificar a associação entre recursos do ambiente familiar, aspectos sociodemográficos e desempenho escolar de estudantes do Ensino Fundamental.</seg>
          <seg id="335">Estudo observacional analítico transversal, com amostra probabilística estratificada por sexo, idade e ano escolar.</seg>
          <seg id="336">Participaram 124 adolescentes, de ambos os sexos, entre 11 e 14 anos, matriculados no Ensino Fundamental II de uma instituição particular.</seg>
          <seg id="337">Os responsáveis receberam um formulário online contendo: Inventário dos Recursos do Ambiente Familiar (RAF), Critério de Classificação Econômica Brasil (CCEB) e questões sociodemográficas.</seg>
          <seg id="338">O desempenho escolar foi fornecido pela instituição.</seg>
          <seg id="339">Realizou-se distribuição de frequência das variáveis categóricas e medidas de tendência central e de dispersão para as contínuas.</seg>
          <seg id="340">Utilizou-se os testes Mann-Whitney, Kruskal-Wallis e coeficiente de correlação de Spearman, sendo considerados significantes os que apresentaram valor de p≤0,05.</seg>
          <seg id="341">A maioria da amostra possuía 11 anos, do sexo feminino, cursava o 6º ano do Ensino Fundamental, obteve desempenho escolar muito bom, apresentava classificação A e declarou que a/o chefe de família possuía Ensino Superior completo.</seg>
          <seg id="342">Houve associação entre idade e ano escolar com a interação com os pais, ligação família-escola e RAF total.</seg>
          <seg id="343">Os processos proximais demonstraram correlação positiva de magnitude moderada com passeios e brinquedos.</seg>
          <seg id="344">Houve correlação positiva moderada entre total do RAF e atividades previsíveis que sinalizam estabilidade.</seg>
          <seg id="345">Os processos proximais se correlacionaram de maneira positiva forte com a ligação família-escola.</seg>
          <seg id="346">Ter livros em casa revelou correlação positiva fraca com o desempenho escolar.</seg>
          <seg id="347">Os recursos do ambiente familiar apresentaram relação com o desempenho escolar dos adolescentes.</seg>
          <seg id="348">Este estudo visa conhecer o cenário atual da atuação fonoaudiológica em serviços de TAN no Brasil, identificando seus obstáculos e perspectivas, bem como verificar a adequação dos Programas de TAN nacionais aos indicadores de qualidade pré-estabelecidos.</seg>
          <seg id="349">Estudo observacional analítico, realizado com fonoaudiólogos no exercício da TAN no Brasil, entre agosto de 2018 e agosto de 2019, por meio de um questionário online estruturado.</seg>
          <seg id="350">Foram realizadas análises descritivas e correlacionais dos dados no programa SPSS versão 22.0.</seg>
          <seg id="351">A prática efetiva da TAN entre os profissionais não foi condizente, na sua totalidade, com os protocolos oficiais.</seg>
          <seg id="352">48,5% dos fonoaudiólogos afirmaram interrupção da TAN em algum momento nos locais de trabalho, principalmente pela necessidade de reparo do equipamento (64,7%).</seg>
          <seg id="353">Quanto aos registros do fluxo e dados de atendimento, que contemplam os indicadores de qualidade, houve maior controle do número total de neonatos que realizaram a TAN (87,9%) e menor controle quanto aos resultados falsos positivos (21,2%).</seg>
          <seg id="354">81,8% dos fonoaudiólogos afirmaram ter disponibilidade para utilizar um sistema para registro e controle de dados da TAN.</seg>
          <seg id="355">Apesar de as práticas dos profissionais estarem em geral condizentes com protocolos oficiais, a não linearidade do processo e a falta de controle dos dados constituem obstáculos importantes para a qualidade dos serviços de TAN.</seg>
          <seg id="356">A maioria dos programas de TAN nacionais apresentados não cumprem os indicadores de qualidade pré-estabelecidos.</seg>
          <seg id="357">Considera-se que a informatização dos registros poderá beneficiar os profissionais e potencializar a implementação da TAN como prevista na legislação e políticas públicas nacionais.</seg>
          <seg id="358">O objetivo deste estudo foi descrever as mudanças na frequência do consumo de refeições de adolescentes residentes na região metropolitana do Rio de Janeiro, em período de 5 anos.</seg>
          <seg id="359">Utilizaram-se dados de dois estudos transversais, de base populacional, que foram realizados por meio de visitas domiciliares.</seg>
          <seg id="360">Em 2005, a amostra final foi de 1089 domicílios com 511 adolescentes (de 12 a 18 anos), e em 2010 de 1121 domicílios com 314 adolescentes.</seg>
          <seg id="361">A frequência do consumo de refeições foi obtida por meio de questionário autopreenchido e a avaliação da adequação de peso dos adolescentes foi realizada com base nos pontos de corte do IMC por sexo e faixa etária.</seg>
          <seg id="362">Houve aumento da substituição diária do almoço tradicional por lanche (3,7% para 13,7%) e no consumo do jantar tradicional (62,9% para 72,0%).</seg>
          <seg id="363">Os adolescentes com sobrepeso consumiram o desjejum com menor frequência do que aqueles sem sobrepeso (2005: 68,3% vs 79,3% p=0,02, 2010: 59,5% vs 77,4% p=0,03).</seg>
          <seg id="364">Conclui-se que houve aumento da substituição diária do almoço tradicional por lanche e no consumo do jantar tradicional no período de 5 anos.</seg>
          <seg id="365">Ademais, a prática do desjejum diário se associou com a classificação de IMC nos dois momentos do estudo, de modo que aqueles com sobrepeso consomem o desjejum com menor frequência.</seg>
        </p>
      </ref>
    </doc>
  </collection>
  <collection id="biomedical">
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc38">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Manual hyperinflation is used in neonatal and pediatric intensive care units to promote expiratory flow bias, but there is no consensus on the benefits of the technique.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Thus, a review that presents supporting evidence is necessary.</seg>
          <seg id="3">This study aims to review the literature on the manual hyperinflation maneuver in neonatal and pediatric intensive care units to analyze the evidence for this technique in terms of the forms of application (associated with other techniques or not), its safety, the performance of manual resuscitators and the influence of the physical therapist's experience, in addition to evaluating the methodological quality of the identified articles.</seg>
          <seg id="4">A search was performed in the following databases: Web of Science, ScienceDirect, PubMedⓇ, Scopus, CINAHL and SciELO.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Two researchers independently selected the articles.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Duplicate studies were assessed, evaluated by title and abstract and then read in full.</seg>
          <seg id="7">The quality of the articles was analyzed using the PEDro scale.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Six articles were included, two of which had high methodological quality.</seg>
          <seg id="9">The main results provided information on the contribution of the positive end-expiratory pressure valve to increasing lung volumes and the use of chest compressions to optimize expiratory flow bias, the negative influence of operator experience on the increase in peak inspiratory flow, the performance of different manual resuscitators when used with the technique and the safety of application in terms of maintaining hemodynamic stability and increasing peripheral oxygen saturation.</seg>
          <seg id="10">The available studies point to a positive effect of the manual hyperinflation maneuver in children who are admitted to intensive care units.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Registration PROSPERO: CRD42018108056.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc33">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">This study aims to know the current scenario of speech audiology therapy activities at NHS in Brazil, identifying its obstacles and perspectives, as well as verifying the adequacy of national NHS Programs to the pre-established quality indicators.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Analytical observational study, carried out with speech therapists in the exercise of NHS in Brazil, between August 2018 and August 2019, through a structured online questionnaire.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Descriptive and correlational analyzes of the data were performed using the SPSS version 22.0 program.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The effective practice of NHS was not entirely consistent with official protocols.</seg>
          <seg id="5">48.5% of speech therapists stated that NHS interruption at some point in the workplace, especially due to the need to repair the equipment (64.7%).</seg>
          <seg id="6">As for the flow records and care-related data, which include quality indicators there was greater control over the total number of neonates who underwent NHS (87.9%) and less control over false-positive results (21.2%).</seg>
          <seg id="7">81.8% of speech-language-hearing therapists said they were available to use a system for recording and controlling NHS data.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Although professionals' practices are generally consistent with official protocols, the non-linearity of the process and the lack of data control are important obstacles to the quality of NHS services.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Most of the national NHS programs presented do not meet the pre-established quality indicators.</seg>
          <seg id="10">It is considered that the computerization of records can benefit professionals and enhance the implementation of NHS provided for in Brazilian laws and public policies.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc46">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">To analyze the quantity of cervical smears, also designated Papanicolaou tests, between 2006 and 2015 in all the Federal units of Brazil, as well as to verify the quantity of exams collected outside the recommended age range and the economic impact of such excess.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The data was collected from the Ministry of Health's database called &lt;i&gt;Sistema de Informação do Câncer do Colo de Útero&lt;/i&gt; (SISCOLO), which contains all the test results collected nationwide by the Unified Health System (SUS, in the Portuguese acronym).</seg>
          <seg id="3">From that, the number of exams and the age range of the women who underwent them were analyzed; besides, these numbers were stratified according to the state of where the exam was performed.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The quantity of exams collected outside the recommended age range was verified, and, so, the economic impact generated was noted.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Between 2006 and 2015, 87,425,549 Papanicolaou tests were collected in Brazil.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Of these, 20,215,052 tests were collected outside the age range recommended by the Brazilian Ministry of Health; this number corresponded to 23.12% of all exams.</seg>
          <seg id="7">From such data, considering that each Pap smear collected by SUS generates a cost of BRL 7.30 to the government, according to the information in the &lt;i&gt;Tabela SUS&lt;/i&gt; dated September 2018, there was a total charge of BRL 147,569,880 for tests collected outside the protocol.</seg>
          <seg id="8">In Brazil, according to the Ministry of Health's protocol about the recommended practices on collecting Pap smears, whose newest edition dates of 2016, it is recommended that Pap smears are collected in women from a specific age range, in whom the potential diagnosing advantages overcome the onus of overdiagnosis or of a lesion with great regression potential.</seg>
          <seg id="9">However, such protocols have not been correctly followed, promoting more than 20 million tests in excess, and an exorbitant cost for the Brazilian public health system.</seg>
          <seg id="10">It is relevant to take measures to correctly use the official protocol, reducing the patients risks, as well as the economic impact for SUS.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc34">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">This study described changes in meal frequency over a 5-year period among adolescents living in the Rio de Janeiro metropolitan region.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The data used were from two cross-sectional, population-based studies conducted by home visits.</seg>
          <seg id="3">In 2005 the final sample was 1089 households with 511 adolescents (aged 12 to 18 years) and in 2010, 1121 households with 314 adolescents.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Meal frequency was obtained through self-administered questionnaire and the adolescents were assessed for appropriate weight by BMI cut-off points, by sex and age group.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Increasingly, traditional daily lunch was replaced by snacks (from 3.7% to 13.7%) and traditional dinner was eaten (62.9% to 72.0%).</seg>
          <seg id="6">Overweight adolescents ate breakfast less often than those not overweight (in 2005, 68.3% and 79.3%, p=0.02 and, in 2010, 59.5% and 77.4%, p=0.03).</seg>
          <seg id="7">Traditional daily lunch was increasingly replaced by snacks and consumption of traditional dinner increased over the 5-year period.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Also, eating breakfast every day was associated with BMI classification at both study times: those who were overweight consumed breakfast less frequently.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc20">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Genetic testing aims to identify patients at risk for inherited cancer susceptibility.</seg>
          <seg id="2">In the last decade, there was a significant increase in the request of broader panels of genes as multi-gene panel testing became widely available.</seg>
          <seg id="3">However, physicians may be faced with genetic findings for which there is lack of management evidence, despite some progress in understanding their clinical relevance.</seg>
          <seg id="4">In this short review, we discuss the advantages and the drawbacks related to multi-gene panel testing in the setting of a Gastrointestinal Familial Cancer Risk clinic. We also summarize the available recommendations on management of pathogenic variant carriers.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc2">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy (HCM) can cause obstruction in the left ventricular outflow tract (LVOT), and be responsible for the onset of limiting symptoms, such as tiredness.</seg>
          <seg id="2">When such symptoms are refractory to pharmacological treatment, interventionist alternative therapies can be useful, such as septal ablation through the infusion of alcohol in the coronary artery or through myectomy.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Recently, the use of a radiofrequency (RF) catheter for endocardial septal ablation guided by electroanatomic mapping has proven to be efficient, despite the high incidence of complete atrioventricular block.</seg>
          <seg id="4">An alternative would be the application of RF at the beginning point of the septal gradient guided by the transesophageal echocardiography (TEE).</seg>
          <seg id="5">The echocardiography is an imaging method with high accuracy to determine septal anatomy.</seg>
          <seg id="6">To assess the long term effect of septal ablation for the relief of ventricular-arterial gradient, using TEE to help place the catheter in the area of larger septal obstruction.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Besides, to assess the effects of ablation on the functional class and echocardiographic parameters.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Twelve asymptomatic patients, with LVOT obstruction, refractory to pharmacological therapy, underwent endocardial septal ablation with 8mm-tip catheters, whose placement was oriented in the region of larger obstruction, assisted by the TEE.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Temperature-controlled and staggered RF applications were performed.</seg>
          <seg id="10">After each application, the gradient was reassessed and a new application was performed according to the clinical criterion.</seg>
          <seg id="11">The effects of RF applications were assessed both for the gradient at rest and for that provoked by the Valsalva maneuver, and considering the gradient.</seg>
          <seg id="12">The differences were significant when p-value was lower than or equal to 0.05.</seg>
          <seg id="13">It was possible to observe that the mean reduction of the maximum gradients was from 96.8±34.7 mmHg to 62.7±25.4 mmHg three months after the procedure (p=0.0036).</seg>
          <seg id="14">After one year, the mean of maximum gradient was 36.1±23.8 mmHg (p=0.0001).</seg>
          <seg id="15">The procedure was well tolerated, without records of complete atrioventricular block nor severe complications.</seg>
          <seg id="16">The TEE-guided septal ablation was efficient and safe, and the results were maintained during the clinical follow-up period.</seg>
          <seg id="17">It is a reasonable option for the interventionist treatment of LVOT obstruction in HCM.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc28">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Women have metabolic, immunological, and genetic variables that ensure more protection from coronavirus infection.</seg>
          <seg id="2">However, the indication of treatment for several pathologies and contraception is determined by hormones that have adverse effects and raise doubts about their use during the COVID-19 pandemic.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Therefore, the present study searches women specificities and the relation between female sexual hormones and COVID-19, and reports the main recommendations in this background.</seg>
          <seg id="4">To this end, a review of the literature was conducted in the main databases, auxiliary data sources, and official websites.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Therefore, considering the hypercoagulability status of COVID-19, the debate about the use of contraceptives due to the relative risk of thromboembolic effects that they impose arises.</seg>
          <seg id="6">However, the current available evidence, as well as the recommendations of main health organs around the world, demonstrate that the use of hormonal contraceptives must be maintained during the pandemic.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc39">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">It is important which medicine to use as a first-line treatment to close the duct.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The aim of this study is to compare the effectiveness and side effects of intravenous (IV) forms of ibuprofen and paracetamol and to contribute to the literature investigating the first drug selected in the medical treatment of patent ductus arteriosus (PDA).</seg>
          <seg id="3">Our study was conducted between January 2017 and December 2019.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Premature infants with birth weight (BW) ≤1500 g and gestational age (GA) ≤32 weeks were included in the study.</seg>
          <seg id="5">In the study period, all infants with hemodynamically significant patent ductus arteriosus (hsPDA) were given rescue intravenous (IV) ibuprofen as a primary medical treatment or IV paracetamol treatment if there were contraindications for ibuprofen.</seg>
          <seg id="6">The patients were divided into two groups: patients receiving IV ibuprofen and patients receiving IV paracetamol.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Of these patients, 101 were given IV paracetamol and 169 were given IV ibuprofen.</seg>
          <seg id="8">The success rate of PDA closure with first-course treatment was 74.3% in the IV paracetamol group and 72.8% in the IV ibuprofen group (p=0.212).</seg>
          <seg id="9">Our results show that IV paracetamol is as effective as IV ibuprofen in the first-line treatment of hsPDA, and can become the preferred treatment for the management of hsPDA.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc30">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) is considered a public health problem, mainly in severely obese patients.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The aim of the present study was to investigate different biochemical-based scores available and determine which one could best serve as an NAFLD predicting tool in a severely obese population.</seg>
          <seg id="3">This was a cross-sectional study involving severely obese patients.</seg>
          <seg id="4">All patients were evaluated with serum laboratory parameters for 1 week before biopsy, and all patients were treated with intraoperative liver biopsy, during bariatric surgery.</seg>
          <seg id="5">A total of 143 severely obese patients were included.</seg>
          <seg id="6">The median body mass index (BMI) was 48 kg/m2 (35-65). Diabetes mellitus was present in 36%, and steatosis was present in 93% (severe steatosis in 20%).</seg>
          <seg id="7">Only aspartate transaminase (AST) to platelet ratio index (APRI=0.65 (95% CI: 0.55-0.8) and homeostatic model assessment for insulin resistance (HOMA-IR=0.7 (95% CI: 0.58-0.82) showed significant capacity for the prediction of severe steatosis.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Hepatic steatosis index (HSI), NAFLD fibrosis score (NAFLDS), alanine aminotransferase (ALT)/AST, and fibrosis-4 (FIB-4) were not able to correctly predict severe steatosis on liver biopsy.</seg>
          <seg id="9">APRI showed high specificity of 82% and low sensitivity of 54%.</seg>
          <seg id="10">In contrast, HOMA-IR showed high sensitivity of 84% and low specificity of 48%.</seg>
          <seg id="11">NAFLDS, FIB-4, AST/ALT, and HSI have no utility for the evaluation of severe steatosis in severely obese patients.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Diabetes and insulin-resistance-related biochemical assessments, such as HOMA-IR, can be used as good screening tools for severe steatosis in these patients.</seg>
          <seg id="13">APRI score is the most specific biochemical diagnostic tool for steatosis in severely obese patients and can help clinicians to decide the need for bariatric or metabolic surgery.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc27">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Increased risk for thromboembolic events from combination of a gynecologic malignancy with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection: a case report</seg>
          <seg id="2">Purpose: During the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 pandemic, several patient groups are at particular risk.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Mortality is higher among cancer patients and may be increased further by thromboembolic events, which are more common in coronavirus 2019 patients according to recent publications.</seg>
          <seg id="4">We discuss the association of gynecologic malignancies, Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2, and thromboembolism by reporting a case study and summarizing available literature.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Case report: A 71-year-old Caucasian patient with ovarian cancer receiving first-line chemotherapy was diagnosed with deep vein thrombosis and pulmonary embolism.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Routine screening revealed infection with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 in absence of specific symptoms.</seg>
          <seg id="7">After uneventful recovery, oncologic treatment could be continued a few weeks later.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Methods: We performed a systematic review of the literature on PubMed following Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic reviews and Meta-Analyses guidelines.</seg>
          <seg id="9">The search included articles ahead of print, published between 1 December 2019 and 1 June 2020.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Cross-searches were conducted on all relevant articles.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Results: We identified five articles meeting the defined criteria, including two retrospective studies, a review, a position paper, as well as a letter to the editor.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Conclusion: Cancer patients infected with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 have a relatively poor outcome, which may partially be due to a higher rate of thromboembolic events.</seg>
          <seg id="13">Thromboprophylaxis is recommended, and scoring systems are helpful in early detection.</seg>
          <seg id="14">In cancer patients with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2, individual risk for thromboembolic events should be taken into account when considering interruption versus continuation of antitumoral therapy.</seg>
          <seg id="15">However, further data and studies are required.</seg>
          <seg id="16">A 71-year-old Caucasian woman, gravida 2/para 2, presented with pain in her lower left leg accompanied by progressive dyspnea in April 2020.</seg>
          <seg id="17">She had already received dabigatran prescribed by her general practitioner for suspected deep vein thrombosis (DVT) one day prior to her admittance.</seg>
          <seg id="18">The patient was undergoing multimodal treatment at our clinic for HGSOC FIGO IIIC.</seg>
          <seg id="19">Up to that point, she had received debulking surgery with macroscopic complete tumor resection in February 2020, including bilateral adnexectomy, hysterectomy, peritonectomy, infragastric omentectomy, pelvic and paraaortic lymphadenectomy, partial liver resection, and rectosigmoid resection.</seg>
          <seg id="20">Secondary wound closure could be achieved after treatment of wound dehiscence in March 2020.</seg>
          <seg id="21">First-line chemotherapy was initiated with carboplatin AUC 5 and paclitaxel 175 mg/m2 every 3 weeks.</seg>
          <seg id="22">After completion of the first course, we switched to weekly application of carboplatin AUC 2 and paclitaxel 80 mg/m2 to improve tolerability.</seg>
          <seg id="23">Three weekly courses of chemotherapy were administered without complications.</seg>
          <seg id="24">Initiation of bevacizumab was postponed due to delayed wound healing.</seg>
          <seg id="25">The patient reported a general feeling of weakness since surgery but was otherwise in a good state of health.</seg>
          <seg id="26">Her medical history included papillary thyroid cancer, successfully treated in 2008 by total thyroidectomy, and catheter ablation of the AV node because of atrioventricular nodal reentry tachycardia in 2015.</seg>
          <seg id="27">No other relevant cardiovascular or pulmonal diseases were known.</seg>
          <seg id="28">She had an uneventful gynecological and obstetrical history.</seg>
          <seg id="29">BRCA testing was negative, and there was no family history of gynecologic malignancies.</seg>
          <seg id="30">The patient did not smoke or drink alcohol regularly.</seg>
          <seg id="31">She was taking L-thyroxin, pantoprazole, and vitamin D as regular medication.</seg>
          <seg id="32">At current presentation, she was routinely asked for symptoms and risk factors for COVID-19 and negated symptoms such as fever, cough, headaches, loss of taste or smell, or recent international travel.</seg>
          <seg id="33">Her only contacts were close relatives as well as her general practitioner.</seg>
          <seg id="34">Clinical examination showed normal clinical conditions as well as normal vital functions (blood pressure 123/75 mmHg, temperature 36.9 °C, heart rate 87 /minute, oxygen saturation 98 %) but a slightly elevated respiratory rate (22 /minute).</seg>
          <seg id="35">Besides chronic anemia (hemoglobin 9.0 g/dl) and elevated infection parameters (C-reactive protein 8.1 mg/dl, ferritin 470 ng/ml), blood testing showed no relevant changes; especially, renal and hepatic function were normal.</seg>
          <seg id="36">Sonography revealed a mild urinary stasis on the left side.</seg>
          <seg id="37">For further diagnosis, we referred the patient to the angiology department of our clinic, where DVT of the left lower leg as well as a thrombophlebitis of the right great saphenous vein and venous thrombosis of the right gastrocnemius muscle vein were confirmed via color Duplex sonography.</seg>
          <seg id="38">We ordered chest computed tomography due to complaints of progressive dyspnea, revealing segmental PE in one central lung artery as well as in several subsegmental arteries (Fig. 1a).</seg>
          <seg id="39">No infiltrates, especially no changes typical for COVID-19, were seen (Fig. 1b).</seg>
          <seg id="40">We performed a nasopharyngeal swab as a routine screening test for SARS-CoV-2 upon hospitalization.</seg>
          <seg id="41">Surprisingly, it revealed infection with SARS-CoV-2 via reverse-transcription polymerase chain reaction (PCR) testing on the following day.</seg>
          <seg id="42">The woman was therefore isolated and transferred to the infectiology department of our clinic, where she was treated for ten more days.</seg>
          <seg id="43">As the patient was in a stable cardiopulmonal condition with no signs of right heart overload in echocardiography, conservative treatment with low-molecular-weight heparins (LMWH) at a therapeutic dosage and compression stockings was continued.</seg>
          <seg id="44">Respiratory parameters were sufficient with no need for oxygen therapy or further medication at any time.</seg>
          <seg id="45">An incidental urinary tract infection with Klebsiella pneumonia was sufficiently treated with cefpodoxim 400 mg per day for 10 days.</seg>
          <seg id="46">A repeat PCR test before discharge was negative.</seg>
          <seg id="47">The patient was quarantined at home for 14 more days.</seg>
          <seg id="48">Anticoagulant treatment was continued with apixaban for 6 months.</seg>
          <seg id="49">No further thromboembolic events occurred meanwhile.</seg>
          <seg id="50">With a therapeutic gap of 5 weeks, we continued chemotherapy with the weekly regimen.</seg>
          <seg id="51">For the next 2 courses, dose reduction to 75% was performed; full doses of carboplatin AUC 2 and paclitaxel 80 mg/m2 were resumed thereafter and well tolerated.</seg>
          <seg id="52">A lymphocele of the left lower abdomen which had caused progressive urinary stasis was drained complication-free 5 months later.</seg>
          <seg id="53">As bevacizumab was contraindicated because of prior VTE, oncologic maintenance therapy with niraparib 200 mg per day followed afterwards.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc19">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">The purpose of this study was to compare the frequency of the occurrence of high-risk human papillomavirus (HPV) and abnormal anal cytology in immunocompetent women with and without HPV-induced genital lesions.</seg>
          <seg id="2">This analytical cross-sectional, observational study was conducted between July 2017 and December 2018 in a specialized outpatient clinic of a tertiary hospital in Fortaleza, CE.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Fifty-seven immunocompetent women with and without genital intraepithelial lesions were assessed; they were divided into two groups: group 1 was comprised of women with HPV-associated genital lesions (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 26), and group 2 was comprised of those without HPV-associated genital lesions (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 31).</seg>
          <seg id="4">Samples for liquid-based cytology and high-risk DNA-HPV polymerase chain reaction real-time tests were collected from the cervix and anus.</seg>
          <seg id="5">All cases were evaluated using high-resolution anoscopy; biopsies were performed when required.</seg>
          <seg id="6">The Fisher exact and chi-squared tests were applied for consolidated data in the contingency table, and the Student &lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt;-test and Mann-Whitney U-test for independent variables.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Anal high-risk HPV infections were more frequent in group 1 (odds ratio [OR], 4.95; 95% confidence interval [CI], 1.34-18.3; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.012), along with concomitant high-risk HPV infections in the uterine cervix and the anus (OR 18.8; 95% CI, 2.20-160; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.001).</seg>
          <seg id="8">The incidence of high-risk cervical HPV infection was associated with high-risk anal HPV infection (OR, 4.95; 95% CI, 1.34-18.3; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.012).</seg>
          <seg id="9">There was no statistical difference concerning abnormal anal cytology or anoscopy between the groups, and no anal intraepithelial lesion was found in either group.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Immunocompetent women with HPV-associated genital lesions and high-risk cervical HPV were more likely to have high-risk anal HPV.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc31">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Center-based cardiac rehabilitation (CR) programs have been forced to close due to COVID-19.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Alternative delivery models to maintain access to CR programs and to avoid physical inactivity should be considered.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The aim of this study was to assess physical activity (PA) levels after completing a home-based digital CR program.</seg>
          <seg id="4">A total of 116 cardiovascular disease (CVD) patients (62.6±8.9 years, 95 male) who had been attending a face-to-face CR program were recruited and assessed (baseline and at three months) on the following parameters: PA, sedentary behavior, adherence, cardiovascular and non-cardiovascular symptoms, feelings toward the pandemic, dietary habits, risk factor control, safety and adverse events.</seg>
          <seg id="5">The intervention consisted of a multidisciplinary digital CR program, including regular patient assessment, and exercise, educational and psychological group sessions.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Ninety-eight CVD patients successfully completed all the online assessments (15.5% drop-out rate).</seg>
          <seg id="7">A favorable main effect of time was an increase in moderate to vigorous PA and a decrease in sedentary time at three months.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Almost half of the participants completed at least one online exercise training session per week and attended at least one of the online educational sessions. No major adverse events were reported and only one minor event occurred. During the pandemic, levels of moderate to vigorous PA improved after three months of home-based CR in CVD patients with previous experience in a face-to-face CR model.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Diversified CR programs with a greater variety of content tailored to individual preferences are needed to meet the motivational and clinical requirements of CVD patients.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc17">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">This qualitative research aimed to investigate workers' theoretical conceptions regarding group work and analyze the driving and restrictive factors of group therapeutic practice in Psychosocial Care Centers (CAPS).</seg>
          <seg id="2">Sixty-six workers from CAPS and outpatient clinics from the Psychosocial Care Network from twenty-three municipalities in the State of Goiás participated in the study.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Data were collected through a structured questionnaire and a group interview audio-recorded and documented with photographs.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The concept of what the group is and is not emerged from the thematic analysis of the data.</seg>
          <seg id="5">The categories were organized into three analysis blocks concerning driving and restrictive forces: service-related, professional-related, and user-related.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Relational, structural, and therapeutic aspects and professional competence for group coordination are integrated in an antagonistic, complementary, and inseparable way to apprehend the studied reality.</seg>
          <seg id="7">We conclude that highlighting the restrictive aspects that must be recognized and improved and the drivers that must be maintained and enhanced can actively contribute to expanding the therapeutic capacity related to the use of group technology in mental health.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc21">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">To describe the quality of life (QoL) of Brazilian speech therapists and relate it to sociodemographic and professiographic aspects, and to their role in the COVID-19 pandemic.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Population-based, cross-sectional epidemiological study.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The research involved speech therapists from Brazil, who were invited to answer, online, the WHOQOL-bref form about their health and QoL, in addition to sociodemographic and professional questions.</seg>
          <seg id="4">609 speech therapists aged between 21 and 65 years, average age of 34 years, participated in the study.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Lower scores in the physical domain of QoL were given by female speech therapists, providing outpatient care, who did not work in private clinics, acted indirectly in the pandemic, were absent from work due to psycho-emotional aspects; in the psychological domain, they were female, without a partner, working in a private clinic or elsewhere and acted directly or indirectly in the pandemic; in the social relations domain, they had no partner, worked in outpatient care, but not in private clinics; and in the environment domain, lower scores were in black and brown race/color, without a partner, attending home care, but not in a private clinic or management/administrative or other.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Brazilian speech therapists had the lowest QoL scores in the psychological and environmental domains; their QoL is related to factors such as sex, color/race, presence of a partner, council region, service environments, direct action with COVID-19 patients and COVID-19 diagnosis.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc13">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Brain injury caused by extracorporeal circulation during cardiovascular surgical procedures has been a recurring complication since the implementation of extracorporeal circulation five decades ago.</seg>
          <seg id="2">There is no unique cause of brain injury due to the use of extracorporeal circulation, but it is known that brain injury affects about 70% of patients who undergo this procedure.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Intracranial pressure assessment is one method that can guide the management of patients undergoing procedures associated with neurological disturbances.</seg>
          <seg id="4">This study describes two cases of patients who underwent cardiovascular surgery with extracorporeal circulation in whom clinical protocols for neuroprotection in the postoperative phase were guided by intracranial pressure waveform findings obtained with a novel noninvasive intracranial pressure monitoring method.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc41">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">To describe the efficacy and safety of protective embolization during prostatic artery embolization, as well as to discuss its clinical relevance.</seg>
          <seg id="2">This was a retrospective, observational, single-center study including 39 patients who underwent prostatic artery embolization to treat lower urinary tract symptoms related to benign prostatic hyperplasia between June 2008 and March 2018.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Follow-up evaluations, performed at 3 and 12 months after the procedure, included determination of the International Prostate Symptom Score, a quality of life score, and prostate-specific antigen levels, as well as ultrasound, magnetic resonance imaging, and uroflowmetry.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Protective embolization was performed in 45 arteries: in the middle rectal artery in 19 (42.2%); in the accessory internal pudendal artery in 11 (24.4%); in an internal pudendal artery anastomosis in 10 (22.2%); in the superior vesical artery in four (8.9%); and in the obturator artery in one (2.2%).</seg>
          <seg id="5">There was one case of nontarget embolization leading to a penile ulcer, which was attributed to reflux of microspheres to an unprotected artery.</seg>
          <seg id="6">There were no complications related to the protected branches.</seg>
          <seg id="7">All of the patients showed significant improvement in all of the outcomes studied (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.05), and none reported worsening of sexual function during follow-up.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Protective embolization can reduce nontarget embolization during prostatic artery embolization without affecting the results of the procedure.</seg>
          <seg id="9">In addition, no adverse events other than those expected or previously reported were observed.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Therefore, protective embolization of pudendal region is safe.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc32">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Spontaneous hemoperitoneum in pregnancy is a rare complication resulting in high maternal and fetal morbidity and mortality.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The authors describe the case of a pregnant woman presenting at 32 weeks of gestation with abdominal pain and free abdominal fluid on ultrasound.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Laparotomy revealed a hemoperitoneum resulting from a suspected ruptured varices on the uterine posterior surface.</seg>
          <seg id="4">A live newborn was delivered by cesarean-section, and hemorrhage was controlled with sutures and compression.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Clinicians should be aware of this diagnosis when a pregnant woman presents with abdominal pain, anemia or hypovolemic shock.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Early intervention will avoid poor outcomes for both the mother and the fetus.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc26">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">It is essential to maintain the alveolar bone ridge to ensure the success of implant therapy.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Platelet-rich fibrin (PRF) may benefit bone repair, but its quantitative microscopic results are still inconclusive.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The aim of this study was to histomorphometrically analyze human dental alveoli after extraction treated with autologous fibrin, biphasic calcium phosphate or sticky bone.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The sample consisted of healthy adult volunteer patients, with clinical and tomographic indication for single post-extraction graft of upper premolars for maintenance of the alveolar ridge and subsequent implantation.</seg>
          <seg id="5">The 10 remaining patients in the study were divided into three groups according to the type of filling used in the dental socket: autologous PRF plug covered by a PRF membrane (G1), PRF associated with an alloplastic graft based on hydroxyapatite with beta tricalcium phosphate covered by a collagen membrane (G2) or alloplastic graft based on beta tricalcium phosphate covered by collagen membrane (control).</seg>
          <seg id="6">After 8 months, bone biopsies were performed at the grafted sites and the patients underwent implant-prosthetic rehabilitation.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Paraffin-embedded tissue blocks were routinely processed and sectionsfrom different depths were mounted in 3 slides and stained with HE.</seg>
          <seg id="8">The histomorphometric evaluation analyzed 30 photomicrographs per block, quantifying the percentage presence of newly formed bone, connective tissue and remaining biomaterial using the ImageJ software. Parametric data enabled intergroup comparisons using ANOVA and Tukey's post-hoc test for multiple comparison with statistical significance of 5% (p&lt;0.05), with normality of the 3 groups by the Jarque-Bera test (p&gt;0.05).</seg>
          <seg id="9">There was a higher mean of newly formed bone in G1 (68.83%) compared to G2 (35.69%) and control (16.28%).</seg>
          <seg id="10">There was greater presence of connective tissue in the control (61.56%).</seg>
          <seg id="11">Remaining biomaterial was higher in G2 (15.75%), but did not differ statistically from the control.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Bone regeneration obtained with PRF alone or sticky bone suggests the efficacy of these therapies, encouraging the clinical use of this blood concentrate in dental procedures.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc8">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">This systematic review was designed to assess the usefulness of cough peak flow to predict the extubation outcome in subjects who passed a spontaneous breathing trial.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The search covered the scientific databases MEDLINE, Lilacs, Ibecs, Cinahl, SciELO, Cochrane, Scopus, Web of Science and gray literature.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The Quality Assessment of Diagnostic Accuracy Studies was used to assess the methodological quality and risk of study bias.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The statistical heterogeneity of the likelihood (LR) and diagnostic odds ratios were evaluated using forest plots and Cochran's Q statistic, and a crosshair summary Receiver Operating Characteristic plot using the multiple cutoffs model was calculated.</seg>
          <seg id="5">We initially retrieved 3,522 references from the databases; among these, 12 studies including 1,757 subjects were selected for the qualitative analysis.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Many studies presented an unclear risk of bias in the 'patient selection' and 'flow and time' criteria.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Among the 12 included studies, seven presented 'high risk' and five 'unclear risk' for the item 'reference standard.' The diagnostic performance of the cough peak flow for the extubation outcome was low to moderate when we considered the results from all included studies, with a +LR of 1.360 (95%CI 1.240 - 1.530), -LR of 0.218 (95%CI 0.159 - 0.293) and a diagnostic odds ratio of 6.450 (95%CI 4.490 - 9.090).</seg>
          <seg id="8">A subgroup analysis including only the studies with a cutoff between 55 and 65 L/minute showed a slightly better, although still moderate, performance.</seg>
          <seg id="9">A cough peak flow assessment considering a cutoff between 55 and 65L/minute may be useful as a complementary measurement prior to extubation.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Additional well-designed studies are necessary to identify the best method and equipment to record the cough peak flow as well as the best cutoff.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc22">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">The Western Ontario Shoulder Instability Index (WOSI) is a self-administered questionnaire specifically used to determine the impact of shoulder instability on quality of life.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The aim of this study was to translate the WOSI into European Portuguese and analyze its validity and reliability in a population with shoulder instability.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The WOSI was translated and culturally adapted from its original version into European Portuguese (WOSIPT).</seg>
          <seg id="4">Internal consistency and test-retest analyses were conducted to determine the level of reliability of the scale.</seg>
          <seg id="5">WOSI-PT, Quick-DASH, and SF-12 questionnaires were applied to 81 patients with symptomatic shoulder instability to assess validity, and reliability was tested by randomly selecting 50 patients within 72 hours using a test-retest design.</seg>
          <seg id="6">The reliability of the WOSI-PT was very high, with Cronbach´s alpha equal to 0.97 and an intraclass correlation coefficient of 0.98.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Regarding the construct validity, the correlation between the WOSI-PT and QuickDASH was high and negative (-0.79).</seg>
          <seg id="8">The correlations between WOSI-PT and SF-12 were positive, respectively, moderate with physical (0.66) and low with mental (0.34) health.</seg>
          <seg id="9">WOSI-PT is a reliable and valid instrument for assessing the functional impact of shoulder joint instability on quality of life.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc25">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Oxaliplatin-induced thrombotic microangiopathy: a case report</seg>
          <seg id="2">Background: Oxaliplatin-based chemotherapy represents a standard of care in the treatment of metastatic colorectal cancer.</seg>
          <seg id="3">We report a rare case of fulminant oxaliplatin-induced thrombotic microangiopathy, clinically suggestive of hemolytic-uremic syndrome, occurring in a female patient with a prolonged history of exposure to oxaliplatin for the treatment of metastatic colon cancer.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Case presentation: A 73-year-old Caucasian female with a treatment history including several lines of chemotherapy for the management of metastatic colon cancer was reinitiated on chemotherapy with oxaliplatin, fluorouracil, and leucovorin with bevacizumab for disease progression.</seg>
          <seg id="5">She presented to the emergency department with malaise, headache, vomiting, and decreased urine output appearing a few hours after chemotherapy administration.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Clinical symptoms and laboratory findings were suggestive of thrombotic microangiopathy, with a triad of microangiopathic hemolytic anemia, pronounced thrombocytopenia, and acute renal failure.</seg>
          <seg id="7">The predominance of the severe renal failure was evocative of hemolytic-uremic syndrome.</seg>
          <seg id="8">The rapid development of the thrombotic microangiopathy was linked to exposure to oxaliplatin.</seg>
          <seg id="9">The patient was promptly managed with daily plasma exchange and high-dose corticosteroids, platelet, and red blood cell transfusions in conjunction with intermittent hemodialysis, and she recovered progressively.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Conclusion: Our case confirms the risk of hemolytic-uremic syndrome as a rare and life-threatening complication of oxaliplatin-based chemotherapy.</seg>
          <seg id="11">A dose-dependent, drug-induced toxicity mechanism is suggested.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Physicians need to maintain a high level of clinical suspicion to diagnose and treat this acute life-threatening disorder.</seg>
          <seg id="13">A 73-year-old Caucasian female, never smoker, with a past medical history of hypertension was diagnosed with stage IV colon adenocarcinoma with liver metastasis in October 2008.</seg>
          <seg id="14">She received chemotherapy with capecitabine, leucovorin, and oxaliplatin (XELOX) and bevacizumab for five cycles, then underwent a right hemicolectomy and a partial hepatectomy followed by maintenance therapy with bevacizumab.</seg>
          <seg id="15">In February 2011, she was initiated on fluorouracil, leucovorin, and irinotecan (FOLFIRI) and cetuximab for disease progression in the liver.</seg>
          <seg id="16">In May 2011, she underwent a resection of the new hepatic lesion followed by intra-arterial chemoembolization sessions for 3 months.</seg>
          <seg id="17">Three years later, in August 2014, a positron emission tomography–computed tomography (PET–CT) scan showed evidence of metastatic retroperitoneal lymphadenopathy, consistent with disease recurrence.</seg>
          <seg id="18">She was then initiated on mFOLFOX-6 with bevacizumab with a good imaging response, followed by a year of maintenance therapy with fluorouracil, leucovorin, and bevacizumab.</seg>
          <seg id="19">In December 2016, her treatment plan was switched to fluorouracil, leucovorin, and irinotecan (FOLFIRI) for disease progression to the lungs, followed by maintenance therapy with fluorouracil, leucovorin, and bevacizumab.</seg>
          <seg id="20">A few months later, in August 2017, a PET–CT scan showed a new lung nodule.</seg>
          <seg id="21">She was then shifted to mFOLFOX6 with panitumumab followed by maintenance therapy with fluorouracil and leucovorin.</seg>
          <seg id="22">In May 2018, the treatment protocol was changed to FOLFIRI with cetuximab, until a new disease progression in the lymph nodes, and then around the hepatic artery stent, occurred in January 2019.</seg>
          <seg id="23">The patient was then reinitiated on mFOLFOX6 with bevacizumab.</seg>
          <seg id="24">She received her first cycle on 21 February and later experienced an episode of neutropenia for which the second cycle was delayed.</seg>
          <seg id="25">On 11 March, she received her second cycle of chemotherapy with a 25% dose reduction.</seg>
          <seg id="26">On 13 March, she presented to the emergency department with fatigue, malaise, orbital headache, nausea and vomiting, mild abdominal pain, and chills.</seg>
          <seg id="27">She stated that her symptoms started hours after the chemotherapy infusion and reported a decrease in urine output and a darkening of urine.</seg>
          <seg id="28">On physical examination, the patient had jaundice with icteric sclera since a day ago.</seg>
          <seg id="29">Her vitals showed a temperature of 37.1 °C, a heart rate of 88 beats per minute, a respiratory rate of 18 breaths per minute, a blood pressure of 16.7/7.2 mmHg, and oxygen saturation of 100%.</seg>
          <seg id="30">A cardiac workup ruled out acute myocardial infarction.</seg>
          <seg id="31">The initial blood workup was significant for thrombocytopenia (platelet count 30.103 cells/mm3) and anemia (hemoglobin 8.1 mg/dL).</seg>
          <seg id="32">The anemia was defined as hemolytic by markedly increased bilirubin (total bilirubin 6.4 mg/dL, indirect bilirubin 3.3 mg/dL), high aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (1725 IU/L), high lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) (4866 IU/L), and low haptoglobin (&lt; 0.1 g/L).</seg>
          <seg id="33">The patient also showed signs of acute renal failure (serum creatinine had markedly increased from 0.9 to 5.5 mg/dL within a week, blood urea nitrogen (BUN) 78 mg/dL, and uric acid 10.6 mg/dL).</seg>
          <seg id="34">The blood film inspection showed signs of hemolysis with a slight anisopoikilocytosis, slight hypochromia, some ovalocytes and echinocytes, few schistocytes and helmet cells, rare teardrop red blood cells, and rare stomatocytes.</seg>
          <seg id="35">There were also occasional polychromatophilic red blood cells (reticulocytosis).</seg>
          <seg id="36">Antibody screening was negative, confirming the MAHA diagnosis.</seg>
          <seg id="37">The coagulation panel was normal.</seg>
          <seg id="38">Relevant laboratory parameters are documented in Table 1.</seg>
          <seg id="39">Her chronic medications included irbesartan/amlodipine and atenolol.</seg>
          <seg id="40">The clinical laboratory findings were consistent with thrombotic microangiopathy (TMA).</seg>
          <seg id="41">An ADAMTS13 activity test was performed to investigate a potential TTP, whereas the significant picture of the predominance of renal failure was more suggestive of HUS.</seg>
          <seg id="42">The occurrence of TMA after the chemotherapy session was suggestive of drug-induced thrombotic microangiopathy (DITMA), notably related to the administration of a chemotherapy agent.</seg>
          <seg id="43">Treatment was started promptly with daily plasma exchange and immunosuppression with methylprednisolone (1 mg/kg/day) until a diagnosis of TTP was ruled out, then tapered later on.</seg>
          <seg id="44">She also received packed red blood cell transfusions and platelet transfusions, and underwent daily intermittent hemodialysis.</seg>
          <seg id="45">Electrolyte imbalances were also managed.</seg>
          <seg id="46">Seven days later, the patient’s laboratory studies (Table 1) showed a stable hemoglobin level, a much-improved platelet count, and no clinical evidence of hemolysis.</seg>
          <seg id="47">Her platelet count normalized on day 12.</seg>
          <seg id="48">Daily plasma exchange was continued for eight consecutive days, and dialysis for eight consecutive days.</seg>
          <seg id="49">The patient was transferred to another medical center in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia (KSA) for continuity of care and possible treatment of the DITMA with eculizumab.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc29">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Endoscopic treatment for esophageal variceal has been used as the main intervention in patients with portal hypertension secondary to schistosomiasis, but with significant rates of recurrence of esophageal variceal and rebleeding.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The long-term results of exclusive endoscopic treatment are poorly studied as the relationship of the splenic dimensions in this context.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The aim of this study was to identify, through ultrasonography, whether the splenic index and the longitudinal (craniocaudal) dimension of the spleen are the predictors of rebleeding and variceal recurrence in late follow-up of patients with nonoperated schistosomiasis, after endoscopic eradication of esophageal variceal.</seg>
          <seg id="4">This is a retrospective and observational study analyzing the medical records of patients diagnosed with hepatosplenic schistosomiasis.</seg>
          <seg id="5">The receiver operating characteristic curve was used to determine the best cutoff point for the mean splenic index as a predictor of recurrence and bleeding.</seg>
          <seg id="6">A follow-up of 54 patients were analyzed during the period from 2002 to 2018.</seg>
          <seg id="7">The mean follow-up time was 8 years.</seg>
          <seg id="8">The splenic index with value &gt;144 was proved to be a sensitive test for rebleeding.</seg>
          <seg id="9">In the analysis of the longitudinal dimension, the spleen length of &gt;20 cm showed a statistically significant test for recurrence of variceal and a length &gt;19 cm presented as a very sensitive and statistically significant test for rebleeding.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Splenic index and craniocaudal dimension analysis, obtained by ultrasonography, can predict recurrence of varicose veins and rebleeding after exclusive endoscopic treatment.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc4">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Complete heart block ensuing from a metastatic small cell carcinoma: a case report</seg>
          <seg id="2">Introduction: Notwithstanding the diagnostic and therapeutic advancements, the incidence of cardiac metastases has increased in recent decades.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Lung cancers are the most common primary malignant neoplasms with cardiac metastasis potential.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The clinical presentation of cardiac metastases is either silent or vague, and largely depends on the infiltrated location and tumor burden.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Although arrhythmias are not uncommon in metastatic cardiac tumors, complete heart block is relatively a rare manifestation.</seg>
          <seg id="6">We present a case of complete heart block due to a metastatic small cell carcinoma in a 67-year-old male of African origin.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Case presentation: A 67-year-old male of African origin from rural Tanzania was referred to us for expert management.</seg>
          <seg id="8">He is a retired agromechanic with over 30 years exposure to asbestos-containing brake linings.</seg>
          <seg id="9">His past medical history was unremarkable, but the family-social history was evident for a heavy alcohol intake and chronic cigarette smoking.</seg>
          <seg id="10">He presented with a 24-week history of progressive shortness of breath and an 8-week history of recurrent syncopal attacks coupled with a significant weight loss.</seg>
          <seg id="11">He had normal echocardiographic findings, however, the electrocardiogram showed features of complete heart block.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Chest X-ray showed a homogeneous opacification on the right side and computed tomography scan revealed a solid right lung mass with metastases to the liver, heart, bowels, and bone.</seg>
          <seg id="13">He underwent bronchoscopy, which revealed an endobronchial mass obstructing the bronchus intermedius.</seg>
          <seg id="14">Histological examination of a section of lung biopsy taken during bronchoscopy confirmed the diagnosis of a small cell carcinoma.</seg>
          <seg id="15">The patient underwent dual chamber pacemaker implantation with successful sinus rhythm restoration.</seg>
          <seg id="16">He made an informed refusal of chemotherapy and inevitably died 18 months post pacing.</seg>
          <seg id="17">Conclusions: Despite the advancements in medical diagnostics and management, lung cancers are often diagnosed in advanced stages, with an inevitable grave prognosis.</seg>
          <seg id="18">Small cell carcinoma has the potential to metastasize to the heart, resulting in complete heart block.</seg>
          <seg id="19">A 67-year-old male of African origin from the Kilimanjaro region north of Tanzania was referred to us for expert management.</seg>
          <seg id="20">He is a retired agromechanic with over 30 years exposure to asbestos-containing brake linings.</seg>
          <seg id="21">His past medical history was unremarkable, but the family-social history was evident for a heavy alcohol intake (5 units/day) and chronic cigarette smoking (20 pack years).</seg>
          <seg id="22">He presented with a 24-week history of progressive shortness of breath and an 8-week history of recurrent syncopal attacks.</seg>
          <seg id="23">Such complaints were associated with awareness of heart beat, easy fatigability, light headedness, dry cough, and weight loss (∼15 kg in 6 months).</seg>
          <seg id="24">There was a negative history of fever, night sweats, chest pain, visual disturbances, recurrent headaches, bone pain, vomiting, or diarrhea.</seg>
          <seg id="25">General examination revealed a wasted (BMI 17.6 kg/m2) man.</seg>
          <seg id="26">He had a sinus bradycardia of 32 beats/minute and blood pressure of 117/66 mmHg on cardiovascular examination.</seg>
          <seg id="27">Respiratory examination revealed features suggestive of right lung consolidation.</seg>
          <seg id="28">Other systems were essentially normal.</seg>
          <seg id="29">He underwent a number of hematological, biochemical, and serological tests, which revealed a normocytic normochromic anemia [hemoglobin (Hb) 11.1 g/dL] but otherwise normal.</seg>
          <seg id="30">His echocardiography (ECHO) was essentially normal, however the electrocardiogram (ECG) showed features in keeping with the diagnosis of CHB, Fig. 1.</seg>
          <seg id="31">Chest X-ray (CXR) showed a homogeneous opacification on the right side, and CT scan revealed a solid right lung mass with metastases to the heart, liver, bowels, and bone; Figs. 2, 3, 4, 5 and 6.</seg>
          <seg id="32">Furthermore, he underwent bronchoscopy, which revealed an endobronchial mass occluding the bronchus intermedius.</seg>
          <seg id="33">Histological examination of a section of lung biopsy taken during bronchoscopy confirmed the diagnosis of small cell carcinoma, Fig. 7.</seg>
          <seg id="34">Correspondingly, a histological section of heart muscle tissue revealed similar findings to lung biopsy.</seg>
          <seg id="35">The patient underwent dual chamber pacemaker implantation with successful sinus rhythm restoration.</seg>
          <seg id="36">He made an informed refusal of chemotherapy and inevitably died in his home village 18 months post pacing.</seg>
          <seg id="37">We received the death information from his son via a phone call, and an autopsy was not practical.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc7">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Even though the risk of COVID-19 in pregnancy may be increased, large-scale studies are needed to better understand the impact of the infection in this population.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The aim of this study is to describe obstetric complications and the rate of vertical transmission in pregnant women with SARS-CoV-2 infection.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Detected cases of SARS-CoV-2 infection in pregnancy were registered in Portuguese hospitals by obstetricians.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Epidemiological, pregnancy and childbirth data were collected.</seg>
          <seg id="5">There were 630 positive cases in 23 Portuguese maternity hospitals, most at term (87.9%) and asymptomatic (62.9%).</seg>
          <seg id="6">The most frequent maternal comorbidity was obesity.</seg>
          <seg id="7">The rates of preterm birth and small-to-gestational-age were 12.1% and 9.9%, respectively.</seg>
          <seg id="8">In the third trimester, 2.9% of pregnant women required respiratory support.</seg>
          <seg id="9">There were eight cases (1.5%) of fetal death, including two cases of vertical transmission.</seg>
          <seg id="10">There were five cases of postpartum respiratory degradation, but no maternal deaths were recorded.</seg>
          <seg id="11">The caesarean section rate was higher in the first than in the second wave (68.5% vs 31.5%).</seg>
          <seg id="12">RT-PCR SARS-CoV-2 positivity among newborns was 1.3%.</seg>
          <seg id="13">SARS-Cov-2 infection in pregnancy may carry increased risks for both pregnant women and the fetuses.</seg>
          <seg id="14">Individualized surveillance and the prophylaxis of this population with vaccination. is recommended in these cases.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc44">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">To identify current evidence on the use of topiramate for refractory status epilepticus.</seg>
          <seg id="2">We reviewed the literature to investigate the efficacy of topiramate in the treatment of refractory status epilepticus.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The search terms used were 'status epilepticus', 'refractory', 'treatment' and 'topiramate'.</seg>
          <seg id="4">No restrictions were used.</seg>
          <seg id="5">The search yielded 487 articles that reported using topiramate as a treatment for refractory status epilepticus and its outcomes.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Case reports, review articles, and animal experiments were excluded.</seg>
          <seg id="7">After excluding duplicates and applying inclusion and exclusion criteria, nine studies were included for analyses.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Descriptive and qualitative analyses were performed, and the results were as follows: response rates (defined as termination in-hospital until 72 hours after the administration of topiramate) varied from 27% to 100%.</seg>
          <seg id="9">The mortality rate varied from 5.9% to 68%.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Positive functional long-term outcomes, defined as discharge, back to baseline or rehabilitation, were documented by seven studies, and the rates ranged between 4% and 55%.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Most studies reported no or mild adverse effects.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Topiramate was effective in terminating refractory status epilepticus, presented relatively low mortality and was well tolerated.</seg>
          <seg id="13">Therefore, topiramate could be a good option as a third-line therapy for refractory status epilepticus, but further studies are necessary.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc24">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Cardiac, ventilatory and kidney management in the critical care setting has been optimized over the past decades.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Cognition and sedation represent one of the last remaning challenges.</seg>
          <seg id="3">As conventional sedation is suboptimal and as the sedation evoked by alpha-2 adrenergic agonists ('cooperative' sedation with dexmedetomidine, clonidine or guanfacine) represents a valuable alternative, this manuscript covers three practical topics for which evidence-based medicine is lacking: a) Switching from conventional to cooperative sedation ('switching'): the short answer is the abrupt withdrawal of conventional sedation, immediate implementation of alpha-2 agonist infusion and the use of 'rescue sedation' (midazolam bolus[es]) or 'breakthrough sedation' (haloperidol bolus[es]) to stabilize cooperative sedation.</seg>
          <seg id="4">b) Switching from conventional to cooperative sedation in unstable patients (e.g., refractory delirium tremens, septic shock, acute respiratory distress syndrome, etc. ): to avoid hypotension and bradycardia evoked by sympathetic deactivation, the short answer is to maintain the stroke volume through volume loading, vasopressors and inotropes.</seg>
          <seg id="5">c) To avoid these switches and associated difficulties, alpha-2 agonists may be considered first-line sedatives.</seg>
          <seg id="6">The short answer is to administer alpha-2 agonists slowly from admission or endotracheal intubation up to stabilized cooperative sedation.</seg>
          <seg id="7">The 'take home' message is as follows: a) alpha-2 agonists are jointly sympathetic deactivators and sedative agents; b) sympathetic deactivation implies maintaining the stroke volume and iterative assessment of volemia.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Evidence-based medicine should document our propositions.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc6">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Sickle cell disease (SCD) is the most common monogenic disease worldwide, with a variable prevalence in each continent.</seg>
          <seg id="2">A single nucleotide substitution leads to an amino-acid change in the β-globin chain, altering the normal structure ofhemoglobin, which is then called hemoglobin S inherited in homozygosity (HbSS) or double heterozygosity (HbSC, HbSβ), and leads to chronic hemolysis, vaso-occlusion, inflammation, and endothelium activation.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Pregnant women with SCD are at a higher risk of developing maternal and perinatal complications.</seg>
          <seg id="4">We performed a narrative review of the literature considering SCD and pregnancy, the main clinical and obstetrical complications, the specific antenatal care, and the follow-up for maternal and fetal surveillance.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Pregnant women with SCD are at a higher risk of developing clinical and obstetric complications such as pain episodes, pulmonary complications, infections, thromboembolic events, preeclampsia, and maternal death.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Their newborns are also at an increased risk of developing neonatal complications: fetal growth restriction, preterm birth, stillbirth.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Severe complications can occur in patients of any genotype.</seg>
          <seg id="8">We concluded that SCD is a high-risk condition that increases maternal and perinatal morbidity and mortality.</seg>
          <seg id="9">A multidisciplinary approach during pregnancy and the postpartum period is key to adequately diagnose and treat complications.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc12">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">To assess the influence of oxidative stress on the gene expression of nitric oxide synthases (NOS 3 and NOS 2) and, hence, the cardiovascular responses in preeclampsia.</seg>
          <seg id="2">This was a case control study in which patients with preeclampsia (PE group) and normal pregnancy controls (NP group) were included according to the guidelines of the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists (ACOG).</seg>
          <seg id="3">The serum levels of malondialdehyde (MDA), total antioxidant capacity, and nitric oxide (NO) were estimated, and the heart rate and mean arterial pressure were recorded.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The gene profiling of NOS3 and NOS2 was performed through real-time polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR).</seg>
          <seg id="5">The statistical analysis was performed using the Student &lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt;-test, and values of &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.05 were considered statistically significant.</seg>
          <seg id="6">The serum levels of malondialdehyde were increased (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.0001), and the total antioxidant capacity was reduced in the PE group (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.034), indicating oxidative stress.</seg>
          <seg id="7">In the PE group, the mean arterial pressure was significantly higher (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.0001), but the serum levels of NO did not show a statistically significant reduction (&lt;i&gt;p &lt;/i&gt;= 0.20).</seg>
          <seg id="8">The gene expression profiling of NOS3 and NOS2 revealed a down regulation in the PE group by 8.49 and 51.05 times respectively.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Oxidative stress may lead to endothelial dysfunction, which could result in increased mean arterial pressure.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Nitric oxide may play a role in this mechanism, but interactions with other vasoactive /biological substances cannot be overlooked, as the gene expression of NOS3 and NOS2 has been reduced.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc40">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Few studies analyzed the safety of salvage nipple-sparing mastectomy (NSM) for local relapse treatment.</seg>
          <seg id="2">We evaluated the outcomes of patients with indications for mastectomy who chose to undergo NSM for ipsilateral breast tumor recurrence (IBTR).</seg>
          <seg id="3">Between January 2001 and December 2018, we evaluated 24 women who underwent NSM for local relapse after conservative surgery.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The patients were followed up for a mean time of 132 months since the first surgery.</seg>
          <seg id="5">After the NSM, 5 (20.8%) patients were diagnosed with local recurrence and only 1 (4.2%) patient died.</seg>
          <seg id="6">The patients presented 4.8% (2) of partial and 2.4% (1) of total nipple necrosis.</seg>
          <seg id="7">In this long-term follow-up since the first surgery, we observed low rates of complication and good survival, although associated with high local recurrence in patients diagnosed with IBTR undergoing NSM as salvage surgery.</seg>
          <seg id="8">We demonstrated that NSM may be considered after IBTR for patients who did not want to undergo total mastectomy.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc47">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">The Brazilian Psychiatric Reform (BPR) process proposes a break with the asylum paradigm in several dimensions.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Thinking about care spaces and the right to the city are important flags for this issue.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Bearing that in mind, a theoretical-conceptual framework was constructed, aiming to discuss and systematize the relationship between the architecture of care spaces geared toward madness and the production of subjectivities and relationships.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Thus, based on archeo-genealogy, a dialogue was organized between concepts and authors that approach space and architecture as devices for the production of subjectivities and relationships, such as total institutions and self-mortification (Erving Goffman) and space-behavioral syndrome (Mirian de Carvalho), as well as experiences such as those by Maura Lopes Cançado and Lima Barreto.</seg>
          <seg id="5">It is also the aim of this study to discuss and draw, through the lens of different fields of knowledge, an ideal city that will aid in facing the asylum paradigm and strengthening the BPR process: the open city, that which includes difference.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Locating the importance of discussing the architectures, spaces, and the city built for the BPR process, this article proposes to build and add a new dimension of analysis of such a process to those that already exist: the spatial dimension.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc49">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Although it is known that the left ventricular (LV) ejection fraction (EF) measured by echocardiography is preserved in patients with acromegaly, there is not enough information about the LV and left atrial strain (LV-GLS and LAS).</seg>
          <seg id="2">This study aimed to evaluate the left ventricular (LV) and left atrial (LA) functions with strain echocardiography (SE) in patients with acromegaly.</seg>
          <seg id="3">This study included 50 acromegaly patients with active disease and 50 healthy controls with similar age, gender, and body surface area.</seg>
          <seg id="4">In addition to routine echocardiography examinations, LV-GLS and LAS measurements were performed with SE.</seg>
          <seg id="5">LAS and LV-GLS values were significantly lower in patients with acromegaly (p&lt;0.05 for all).</seg>
          <seg id="6">In bivariate analysis, systolic blood pressure, N-terminal prohormone of brain natriuretic peptide, Insulin-like growth factor-1, LA diastolic diameter, and LVMI levels were found to be positively correlated with both LAS and LV-GLS (p &lt;0.05).</seg>
          <seg id="7">IGF-1 level was strongly correlated with LAS and LV-GLS (p&lt;0.001 and β=0.5 vs. p&lt;0.001 and β=0.626, respectively); 48% of patients with acromegaly have reduced LV-GLS (&lt;20%).</seg>
          <seg id="8">Left ventricular mass-index (LVMI) independently determines the presence of reduced LV-GLS and each 1g/m2increase in LVMI level increases the likelihood of reduced LV-GLS by 6%.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Although LV ejection fraction is normal in patients with acromegaly, LAS and LV-GLS values were significantly reduced.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Apart from LVMI increase, another finding of cardiac involvement may be LAS and LV-GLS decrease.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Therefore, in addition to routine echocardiography, LAS and LV-GLS may be useful to evaluate early signs of cardiac involvement before the occurrence of irreversible cardiac changes.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc18">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">To assess the extent of the scientific literature on avoidant/restrictive food intake disorder (ARFID) in children and young people with autism in order to evaluate and synthesize the evidence on (a) the nature of feeding and eating difficulties in children and young people with autism; (b) the consequences of a severely restricted diet; and (c) what is known about effective treatment approaches.</seg>
          <seg id="2">PubMed and PsycInfo databases were searched, identifying 56 studies and a narrative synthesis was effected. The literature suggested that ARFID-like presentations are common in children and young people with autism, with severe consequences for physical and mental health.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The three drivers mentioned in the DSM-5 criteria, namely a sensory-based avoidance, fear- or phobia-based restriction, and a lack of interest in eating, are present in this population, although sensory sensitivities are currently the most commonly described.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Research suggests that ARFID symptoms in children and young people with autism can be amenable to treatment, with evidence that behavioural interventions are feasible and potentially effective in this population.</seg>
          <seg id="5">ARFID is a common and impactful problem among young people with autism but is currently under researched. Work is required to (a) identify the prevalence of ARFID in children and young people with autism; (b) uncover the key drivers of ARFID in this population; (c) adapt currently available interventions for use with children and young people with autism; and (d) rigorously test these interventions in clinical trials.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Significant food restriction is common in children and young people with autism.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Sensory sensitivities are frequently cited as a reason for food restriction.</seg>
          <seg id="8">The prevalence and causes of avoidant/restrictive food disorders in children and young people with autism need further research.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc36">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">To determine the prevalence of the atypical glandular cells (AGCs) cytology and to analyze its clinical significance in different age ranges. Retrospective observational study using computerized data from the Brazilian National Cancer Institute, including women screened between January 2002 and December 2008.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The women included were those with an AGC result who were properly followed-up with colposcopy and a second cytology. A total of 132,147 cytopathological exams were performed during the study period.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Five-hundred and thirty-three (0.4%) women with AGC cytology were identified and, of these, 69.41% (370/533) were properly referred for colposcopy and a new cytology.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Most of the women (79.2%) with a 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; or 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; AGC cytology were between the ages of 25 and 54 years.</seg>
          <seg id="5">The 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; cytology demonstrated 67.6% (250/370) of normality, 24.5% (91/370) of squamous atypia, and 6.2% (23/370) of AGC, 0.8% (3/370) adenocarcinoma in situ and 0.8% (3/370) adenocarcinoma invasor.</seg>
          <seg id="6">On biopsy of the women with a second AGC cytology, 43.4% (10/23) had normal histology, 43.4% (10/23) had squamous lesions, 8.7% (2/23) had invasive adenocarcinoma, and 1.2% (1/23) had an inconclusive report.</seg>
          <seg id="7">All of the women with high-grade squamous intraepithelial lesion (HSIL) or invasive adenocarcinoma (respectively 5 and 2 patients), after a 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; AGC cytology were 25 years old or older.</seg>
          <seg id="8">The prevalence of the AGC cytology was low in the studied population.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Most of the AGC cytology cases occurred in adult women between the ages of 25 and 54.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Although most of the patients had normal histology after follow-up, several of them presented with squamous intraepithelial lesions or invasive adenocarcinoma.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc37">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">To assess the degree of correlation/agreement of maternal-fetal Doppler parameters between normal and growth-restricted fetuses (fetal growth restriction [FGR]).</seg>
          <seg id="2">The present observational and retrospective study included 274 singleton pregnancies.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The following maternal-fetal Doppler parameters were assessed: uterine artery (UAt), umbilical artery (UA), middle cerebral artery (MCA), cerebroplacental ratio (CPR), and umbilical-cerebral ratio (U/C).</seg>
          <seg id="4">The assessment of FGR was based on the Figueiras and Gratacós9 criteria. Spearman correlation coefficients were estimated to assess the correlation between resistance (RI) and pulsatility (PI) indices of Doppler parameters.</seg>
          <seg id="5">The agreement between two Doppler parameters was assessed by the Kappa coefficient.</seg>
          <seg id="6">In total, 502 Doppler examinations were included, and FGR was observed in 19 out of 274 fetuses.</seg>
          <seg id="7">A strong correlation was observed between RI and PI of UAt, UA, and MCA in all of the samples (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.001).</seg>
          <seg id="8">Of the 502 Doppler examinations, there was agreement between U/C and CPR percentiles for 480 (95.6%) and disagreement for 22 (4.4%), with Kappa coefficient of 0.26, thereby corresponding to weak agreement.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Of the 68 cases with estimated fetal weight ≤ 9&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; percentile (small for gestational age [SGA]), there was agreement between U/C &gt; 1.0 and CPR &lt; 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; percentile in 61 (88.4%) and disagreement in 7 (5.8%) with Kappa coefficient of 0.49, thereby corresponding to moderate agreement.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Strong correlation was observed among RI and PI UAt, UA, and MCA Doppler examinations in the present study; however, weak agreement was observed between U/C and CPR in the normal and FGR fetuses.</seg>
          <seg id="11">In SGA, U/C and CPR demonstrated moderate agreement.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc45">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Salvage surgery (SS) is defined as surgical resection after the failure of the first treatment with curative intent.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The aim of this study was to report the experience of a reference center with SS for stomach adenocarcinoma.</seg>
          <seg id="3">This is a retrospective study of patients with gastric cancer (GC) operated on between 2009 and 2020.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Notably, 40 patients were recommended for salvage gastrectomy with curative-intent treatment.</seg>
          <seg id="5">For analysis purpose, patients were divided into two groups: 23 patients after endoscopic resection and 17 patients after gastrectomy.</seg>
          <seg id="6">In the first group, all patients underwent R0 resection, their average hospital length of stay (LOS) was 15.7 days, and 2 (8.6%) patients had major complications.</seg>
          <seg id="7">During the average follow-up of 37.2 months, there was only one recurrence.</seg>
          <seg id="8">The median overall survival (OS) was 46 months.</seg>
          <seg id="9">In the postgastrectomy group, 9 (52.9%) patients were rescued with curative intent, the average hospital LOS was 12.2 days, and 3 (17.6%) had major complications.</seg>
          <seg id="10">In a mean follow-up of 22 months, five patients relapsed.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Median OS and disease-free survival were 24 and 16.5 months, respectively.</seg>
          <seg id="12">SS in GC offers the possibility of long-term disease control and increased survival rate with an acceptable complication rate.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc42">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Advances in endoscopy and open-access systems led to an increase in endoscopic procedures.</seg>
          <seg id="2">However, overuse of endoscopy has been consistently reported.</seg>
          <seg id="3">This study aims to assess the appropriateness of esophagogastroduodenoscopy (EGD) and colonoscopy referral in the private and public setting.</seg>
          <seg id="4">We conducted a prospective, multicenter study at 2 public and 5 private endoscopy units. Patients scheduled for elective EGD or colonoscopy were enrolled. Clinical data and endoscopy findings were recorded.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Appropriateness of endoscopy was defined according to the American Society for Gastrointestinal Endoscopy guidelines (for EGD) and the European Panel on Appropriateness of Gastrointestinal Endoscopy II (for colonoscopy).</seg>
          <seg id="6">Regarding EGD: 215 patients enrolled (43.7% were males) with a mean age of 61.0 ± 15.1 years; 54.0% (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 116) were in public hospitals.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Referral by a gastroenterologist was made for 34.9% (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 75).</seg>
          <seg id="8">Appropriate indications were made for 62.3% (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 134): 42.4% in private versus 79.3% in public endoscopy units (odds ratio [OR] 5.20; 95% confidence interval [CI] 2.85-9.49; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.01).</seg>
          <seg id="9">Rate of appropriate EGD was 74.7% for gastroenterologist referral and 56.1% for other specialties (OR 2.31; 95% CI 1.24-4.28; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.01).</seg>
          <seg id="10">Diagnostic yield for relevant findings was 47.9%.</seg>
          <seg id="11">No association between indication appropriateness, gastroenterologist referral, and relevant endoscopic findings was found.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Regarding colonoscopy: 287 patients enrolled (49.1% were males) with a mean age of 60.4 ± 14.4 years; 48.1% (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 138) were in public hospitals.</seg>
          <seg id="13">Referral by a gastroenterologist was made for 20.6% (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 59).</seg>
          <seg id="14">Appropriate indications were made for 70.0% (&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt; = 201): 53.0% in private vs. 88.4% in public endoscopy units (OR 6.75; 95% CI 3.66-12.47; &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.01).</seg>
          <seg id="15">Diagnostic yield was 57.1%. Relevant endoscopic diagnosis was associated with indication: 63.2% in the appropriate vs. 43.0% in the nonappropriate indication group (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.05).</seg>
          <seg id="16">A significant percentage of endoscopies, mainly in the private setting, were performed without an appropriate indication. This influenced the diagnostic yield.</seg>
          <seg id="17">The use of adequate criteria is fundamental for the rational use of an open-access system.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc5">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">It has been shown that interleukin-35 (IL-35) subunits are strongly expressed in atherosclerotic plaques in humans.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Therefore, it is considered to play a role in atherosclerosis.</seg>
          <seg id="3">In this study, IL-35 levels were compared with the control group in patients with stable coronary artery disease (CAD), and the association between IL-35 levels and the lesion type, lesion severity and extension was investigated with the Gensini score (GS) and the Syntax score (SS) in the patient group.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Sixty patients (18 female and 42 male) with CAD diagnosed by coronary angiography, who presented with typical chest pain and positive noninvasive cardiac stress test, and 46 patients (18 female and 28 male) with normal coronary lumenogram, were included in this study.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Gensini and Syntax scores were calculated in the patient group, and these values were compared with IL-35 levels.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Non-normally distributed variables were analyzed by the Mann-Whitney U test, whereas normally distributed parameters were assessed by Student's t-test.</seg>
          <seg id="7">The difference between categorical variables were evaluated by the Chi-square or Fisher test.</seg>
          <seg id="8">P-values&lt;0.05 were considered as statistically significant.</seg>
          <seg id="9">No significant differences were observed between patients and the control group in terms of demographic characteristics and laboratory findings.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Compared to the control group, IL-35 levels of the CAD group were considerably lower (36.9±63.9 ng/ml vs. 33.2±13.2 ng/ml, p&lt;0.008).</seg>
          <seg id="11">Although not statistically significant, IL-35 levels were higher in patients with low SS than among those with high SS (33.2±13.7 vs. 31.8±8.9, p=0.51).</seg>
          <seg id="12">The IL-35 values of the patients with high GS were significantly lower than in patients with low GS (35±17.4 vs. 30.7±8.6, p=0.043).</seg>
          <seg id="13">It has been shown that IL-35 levels can be a new biomarker for stable CAD, and IL-35 is associated with the extension of CAD.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc10">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">This research highlights housing as one of the dimensions of the lives of individuals who experience severe psychological suffering, which reverberates in their care and unique therapeutic plan.</seg>
          <seg id="2">This paper aims to grasp the Psychosocial Care Centers (CAPS) users' meanings of their experiences of living in Santos (SP), Brazil.</seg>
          <seg id="3">This qualitative research was conducted with users of different services through semi-structured interviews submitted to the thematic content analysis.</seg>
          <seg id="4">This study identified how the conception of housing relates to protection, individuality, and affective memories that corroborate the construction of an expanded concrete life regarding living in freedom in the city, presenting plural housing located in different territories.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Taking ownership of spaces reveals the possibilities and challenges inherent to social exchanges and daily experiences.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Being and living in a house means having access to material and subjective goods, besides assuring care in freedom.</seg>
          <seg id="7">However, there are still limitations in the effective exercise of social participation.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc23">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Treatment of severe neutropenia with high-dose pyridoxine in a patient with chronic graft versus host disease and squamous cell carcinoma: a case report</seg>
          <seg id="2">Introduction: The differential diagnosis of neutropenia includes medications, infections, autoimmune diseases, and deficiencies of Vitamin B12 and folate.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The association of Vitamin B6 deficiency with severe neutropenia is a rare finding.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Case presentation: A 51-year-old Caucasian woman presented with fever and profound neutropenia (48 neutrophils/uL).</seg>
          <seg id="5">Her clinical history included non-Hodgkin lymphoma, in remission following treatment with allogeneic bone marrow transplantation, quiescent chronic graft-versus-host disease, and squamous cell carcinoma of the skin metastatic to cervical lymph nodes.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Medications included atenolol, topical clobetasol, Ditropan (oxybutynin), prophylactic voriconazole, prophylactic valganciclovir, Soriatane (acitretin), and Carac (fluorouracil) cream.</seg>
          <seg id="7">The bone marrow was hypocellular without metastatic cancer or myelodysplasia.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Neutropenia did not respond to stopping medications that have been associated with neutropenia (valganciclovir, voriconazole and Soriatane) or treatment with antibiotics or granulocyte colony stimulating factor.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Blood tests revealed absence of antineutrophil antibodies, normal folate and B12 levels, moderate zinc deficiency and severe Vitamin B6 deficiency.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Replacement therapy with oral Vitamin B6 restored blood vitamin levels to the normal range and corrected the neutropenia.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Her cervical adenopathy regressed clinically and became negative on scintography following Vitamin B6 therapy and normalization of the blood neutrophil count.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Conclusion: Severe pyridoxine deficiency can lead to neutropenia.</seg>
          <seg id="13">Screening for Vitamin B6 deficiency, along with folate and Vitamin B12 levels, is recommended in patients with refractory neutropenia, especially those with possible malabsorption syndromes, or a history of chronic-graft-versus host disease.</seg>
          <seg id="14">Severe neutropenia may facilitate progression of squamous cell carcinoma.</seg>
          <seg id="15">The patient was a 51-year-old Caucasian woman with relapsed non-Hodgkin lymphoma treated four years earlier with an allogeneic stem cell transplant.</seg>
          <seg id="16">Her lymphoma was in remission.</seg>
          <seg id="17">Complications of her allogeneic transplant included a history of chronic extensive graft-versus-host disease (GvHD) involving the skin and dermal squamous cell carcinoma.</seg>
          <seg id="18">Immunosuppression with cyclosporine had been discontinued two months earlier due to the development of squamous cell carcinoma and the absence of active GvHD.</seg>
          <seg id="19">She had no history of smoking, alcohol, or drug abuse.</seg>
          <seg id="20">She presented with fever and profound neutropenia; serial blood counts showed that the neutropenia had been present for more than a month (Figure 1).</seg>
          <seg id="21">Her examination showed moderate cachexia, long-standing sclerodermatous changes and hyper-pigmentation of the skin consistent with quiescent GvHD, palpable 2.5 cm left cervical and submandibular adenopathy that was flurodeoxy glucose (FDG) avid on positron emission tomography/computerized tomography (PET/CT) scan.</seg>
          <seg id="22">She had a non-focal neurological examination.</seg>
          <seg id="23">A complete blood count showed a normal total leukocyte count (4,600/uL) with 2% granulocytes (48 neutrophils/uL) together with 84% lymphocytes and 14% monocytes.</seg>
          <seg id="24">Red blood cells were 4.24 × 10E12/L, hemoglobin was 12.4 g/dL, hematocrit was 0.37, and the platelet count was 113 × 10E9/L.</seg>
          <seg id="25">Medications included atenolol, topical clobetasol, Ditropan (oxybutynin), prophylactic voriconazole, prophylactic valganciclovir, Soriatane (acitretin), and Carac (fluorouracil) cream.</seg>
          <seg id="26">Blood cultures showed a micrococcus species.</seg>
          <seg id="27">Her iron level was 330 mcg/L with 20% saturation.</seg>
          <seg id="28">Folate, vitamin B1, vitamin B12, copper, vitamin D levels, thyroid function tests, creatinine, bilirubin, liver enzymes and lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) were normal.</seg>
          <seg id="29">Her blood zinc level was borderline low at 49 mcg/dL.</seg>
          <seg id="30">Antineutrophil antibodies were absent (&lt;1:10 titer).</seg>
          <seg id="31">PCR tests for cytomegalovirus (CMV) and Epstein Barr virus (EBV) in the blood were negative, and had remained negative on prophylactic doses of valganciclovir following CMV reactivation five months earlier.</seg>
          <seg id="32">Her vitamin B6 level was very low at 0.5 ng/mL (reference range 5 to 30 ng/mL).</seg>
          <seg id="33">Serum IgG was polyclonally elevated at 3720 mg/dL as were blood T-cells (4580 cells/uL) and CD8+ T-cells (2836 cells/uL) with normal numbers of CD4+ T-cells, B-cells and natural killer (NK) cells.</seg>
          <seg id="34">Her fever resolved with a course of vancomycin, without identifying a site of infection.</seg>
          <seg id="35">Histological examination of the marrow demonstrated marked hypocellularity without specific megaloblastic or myelodysplastic findings, metastatic cancer, or features to suggest immune-mediated thrombocytopenia.</seg>
          <seg id="36">Cytogenetic analysis showed 100% donor (male) cells without any clonotypic abnormalities.</seg>
          <seg id="37">Biopsy of a cervical lymph node showed poorly differentiated carcinoma, consistent with metastatic squamous cell carcinoma.</seg>
          <seg id="38">Valganciclovir, voriconazole, and Soriatane (acitretin) were discontinued (as potential causes of neutropenia) and prophylactic fluconazole and acyclovir were started.</seg>
          <seg id="39">Granulocyte colony stimulating factor (G-CSF; 300 ug subcutaneously every other day) was administered for four doses in mid February 2010 without any improvement in her neutropenia.</seg>
          <seg id="40">Following daily supplementation with 150 mg Vitamin B6, blood B6 levels normalized concomitant with resolution of the neutropenia (Figure 1).</seg>
          <seg id="41">Following correction of the B6 deficiency and neutropenia, the cervical adenopathy completely regressed by clinical examination and became scintographically negative by PET/CT.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc3">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Ultra-processed foods are markers of unhealthy eating patterns, and their consumption is high among adolescents.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Characteristics of the school eating environment associate with student eating practices.</seg>
          <seg id="3">This study aims to investigate the association between the presence of school canteens and the availability of ultra-processed foods in school canteens with the consumption of these foods, inside the school, among adolescents of the 9th grade (14 years) of the public and private schools of the city of São Paulo, Brazil.</seg>
          <seg id="4">We conducted a cross-sectional study with SP-Proso data, in a sample of 2,680 adolescents.</seg>
          <seg id="5">We elaborated multilevel linear regression models to evaluate associations between the exposures: presence of school canteens and availability of ultra-processed foods with outcomes of consumption frequency of ultra-processed foods in the school.</seg>
          <seg id="6">We found an association between the presence of school canteens and the higher frequency of consumption of sausages (0.46; 95%CI: 0.24; 0.68), package snacks (0.50; 95%CI: 0.19; 0.80), goodies (0.82; 95%CI: 0.55; 1.09), and sugary drinks (0.34; 95%CI: 0.06; 0.62), as well as a score of consumption frequency of ultra-processed foods (2.37; 95%CI: 1.25; 3.48).</seg>
          <seg id="7">The availability of package snacks, goodies, and sugary drinks in school canteens increased the frequency of consumption of these foods.</seg>
          <seg id="8">We observed a dose-response effect between the diversity of ultra-processed foods in canteens and the frequency of consumption of these foods.</seg>
          <seg id="9">A school food environment with greater availability of ultra-processed products is associated with their higher consumption in school, indicating the need to regulate the sale of food within these institutions.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc15">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">To describe current clinical practices related to the use of high-flow nasal cannula therapy by Brazilian pediatric intensivists and compare them with those in other countries.</seg>
          <seg id="2">A questionnaire was administered to pediatric intensivists in North and South America, Asia, Europe, and Australia/New Zealand for the main study.</seg>
          <seg id="3">We compared the Brazilian cohort with cohorts in the United States of America, Canada, the United Kingdom, and India.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Overall, 501 physicians responded, 127 of which were in Brazil.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Only 63.8% of respondents in Brazil had a high-flow nasal cannula available, in contrast to 100% of respondents in the United Kingdom, Canada, and the United States.</seg>
          <seg id="6">The attending physician was responsible for the decision to start a high-flow nasal cannula according to 61.2% respondents in Brazil, 95.5% in the United Kingdom, 96.6% in the United States, 96.8% in Canada, and 84.7% in India. A total of 62% of respondents in Brazil, 96.3% in the United Kingdom, 96.6% in the United States, 96.8% in Canada, and 84.7% in India reported that the attending physician was responsible for the decision to wean or modify the high-flow nasal cannula settings.</seg>
          <seg id="7">When high-flow nasal cannula therapy failed due to respiratory distress/failure, 82% of respondents in Brazil would consider a trial of noninvasive ventilation before endotracheal intubation, compared to 93% in the United Kingdom, 88% in the United States, 91.5% in Canada, and 76.8% in India.</seg>
          <seg id="8">More Brazilian intensivists (6.5%) than intensivists in the United Kingdom, United States, and India (1.6% for all) affirmed using sedatives frequently with high-flow nasal cannulas.</seg>
          <seg id="9">The availability of high-flow nasal cannulas in Brazil is still not widespread.</seg>
          <seg id="10">There are some divergences in clinical practices between Brazilian intensivists and their colleagues abroad, mainly in processes and decision-making about starting and weaning high-flow nasal cannula therapy.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc50">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">This study evaluated the role of social inequalities in complementary feeding patterns between and within countries in Latin America and the Caribbean.</seg>
          <seg id="2">This ecological study employed aggregate data from population-based surveys.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The units of analysis were all 16 countries in Latin America and the Caribbean for which information was available in the Demographic and Health Surveys (DHS) and Multiple Indicator Cluster Surveys (MICS) databases.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The outcomes selected were the prevalences indicated by the 'introduction of solid, semi-solid or soft foods' (ISSSF), 'minimum dietary diversity' (MDD), 'minimum meal frequency' (MMF) and 'minimum acceptable diet' (MAD) standardised complementary feeding indicators recommended by the WHO and available in UNICEF databases.</seg>
          <seg id="5">The differences in prevalences between the wealthiest and poorest income quintiles were calculated in absolute and relative terms.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Comparing the four indicators of complementary feeding, the ISSSF showed best performance, returning prevalence above 80% in 10 of the 11 countries evaluated.</seg>
          <seg id="7">The indicator showing worst performance was the MAD, with prevalence above 60% in only one of the eight countries evaluated.</seg>
          <seg id="8">In almost all countries, by all indicators, prevalences of complementary feeding were lower in the poorest population groups than in the wealthiest.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc48">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">To verify the association between family resources, sociodemographic aspects, and school performance in middle school students.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Observational, analytical, cross-sectional study with a probabilistic sample stratified by sex, age, and grade in school.</seg>
          <seg id="3">A total of 124 adolescents of both sexes, aged 11 to 14 years, enrolled in a private middle school participated in the study.</seg>
          <seg id="4">We sent to their parents/guardians an online form with the Home Environment Resources Scale (HER), Brazilian Economic Classification Criteria (CCEB), and sociodemographic questions.</seg>
          <seg id="5">The school performance was furnished by the institution.</seg>
          <seg id="6">We used frequency distribution analysis of categorical variables and measures of central tendency and dispersion of the continuous ones.</seg>
          <seg id="7">We used the Mann-Whitney, Kruskal-Wallis, and Spearman correlation coefficient tests and set the significance level at p ≤ 0.05.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Most of the sample was 11 years old, females, sixth graders, with very good school performance, belonging to social class A, and whose householder had a bachelor's degree.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Age and grade in school were associated with interaction with the parents, 'family-school connection', and total HER score.</seg>
          <seg id="10">The 'proximal processes' had a moderate positive correlation with outings and toys.</seg>
          <seg id="11">There was a moderate positive correlation between total HER score and 'predictable activities that indicate stability'.</seg>
          <seg id="12">The 'proximal processes' had a strong positive correlation with 'family-school connection'.</seg>
          <seg id="13">There was a weak positive correlation between books available at home and school performance.</seg>
          <seg id="14">The family resources were related to the adolescents' school performance.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc11">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">The SARS-CoV-2 infection has been associated with the acute onset of mental and behavioural symptoms and psychiatric disorders.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The aim of this study was to assess the prevalence of the different neuropsychiatric diagnoses in hospitalized patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection assessed by Liaison Psychiatry.</seg>
          <seg id="3">We performed a cross-sectional study in a hospital near Lisbon, Portugal.</seg>
          <seg id="4">We reviewed the electronic health records from all inpatients with a positive SARS-CoV-2 RT-PCR test that were assessed by the Liaison Psychiatry Unit (LPU) between February and December 2020.</seg>
          <seg id="5">We reviewed relevant sociodemographic and clinical data, including 15 neuropsychiatric symptoms.</seg>
          <seg id="6">The prevalence of psychiatric disorders was our main outcome.</seg>
          <seg id="7">We also explored differences between two groups: patients with delirium (delirium group) and patients without delirium (no delirium group).</seg>
          <seg id="8">We included 46 cases [Age: median = 67 years; interquartile range (IQR) = 24)], with 60.9% male individuals.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Delirium was the most frequent diagnosis in our sample (43.5%), followed by major depressive disorder (21.7%).</seg>
          <seg id="10">Patients with delirium were more likely to suffer from COVID-19 symptoms (delirium: 19/20, 95%; no delirium: 14/26, 53.8%; p = 0.02), and to have a longer time interval between a positive SARS-CoV-2 RT-PCR test and an evaluation by the LPU (delirium: median = 16.5 days, IQR = 16; no delirium: median = 8 days, IQR = 16.3; p = 0.045).</seg>
          <seg id="11">Agitation (52.2%) and cognitive symptoms (47.8%) were the most reported neuropsychiatric symptoms.</seg>
          <seg id="12">We found a high prevalence of delirium in our sample.</seg>
          <seg id="13">This finding is in line with recent literature concerning hospitalized COVID-19 patients The higher frequency of COVID-19 symptoms found in the delirium group suggests a possible association between symptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection and delirium onset.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc43">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Factors related to weight loss in obese patients undergoing bariatric surgery have always been exhaustively studied in an attempt to propose the best surgical technique with greater weight loss and long-term resolution of comorbidities.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Patients present anatomical variations regarding the length of the small intestine.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Some studies demonstrate weight changes in patients with different lengths of the intestinal loops in the Roux-en-Y bypass technique.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The present work carried out a study on the influence of body mass index, weight loss, and common loop length on long-term surgical outcomes.</seg>
          <seg id="5">This is a descriptive cross-sectional study by retrospective analysis of 112 medical records of patients undergoing open bariatric surgery using the gastric bypass technique at University Hospital - UFPR.</seg>
          <seg id="6">The data were correlated in statistical programs for this purpose.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Out of 112 patients, 83.03% were women, with mean age of 41.52 years.</seg>
          <seg id="8">The mean length of the total small bowel of the patients was 5.02 m. There was a directly proportional relationship between the length of the small intestine and weight loss (p=0.0428).</seg>
          <seg id="9">There is a wide range of variables related to weight loss in patients undergoing bariatric surgery, such as the technique used, the length of the loops in the Roux-en-Y gastric bypass, and the routine of nutritional and physical monitoring of the patient.</seg>
          <seg id="10">It is important to assess the technical details of the surgical procedure and to verify the weight loss by evaluating integrally the patient and other variables.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc14">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Eradicating modern slavery is a relevant scientific, social, and institutional challenge issue.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Indeed, efforts are being made globally to understand, map, and eradicate contemporary slavery as a target of the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals by 2030.</seg>
          <seg id="3">However, little attention has been given to the Occupational Health Surveillance (VISAT) in the strategies and struggle against exploiting relationships.</seg>
          <seg id="4">In order to fill this gap, the paper discusses contemporary slave labor (CSL) and its specificities in Brazil from an occupational health surveillance perspective.</seg>
          <seg id="5">We initially highlight the link between CSL, occupational health, and occupational health surveillance (VISAT). We then present three VISAT challenges to addressing CSL: the challenging task of characterizing economic sectors and populations most affected; identifying determinants, risks, and effects on health; and strengthening occupational health practices and services to trigger specific actions regarding formation, information, and intervention in regions of high CSL prevalence.</seg>
          <seg id="6">We conclude that Occupational Health Surveillance can play an essential role in the emancipation of workers engaged in slavery relationships.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc1">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">To understand the factors that most influence decision-making in the treatment of infantile spinal muscular atrophy (SMA).</seg>
          <seg id="2">A discrete choice experiment was conducted among parents of people with SMA (parents), healthcare professionals (HCPs), and members of the Australian general population (GenPop). Respondents were asked to accept/reject treatment for an infant newly diagnosed with SMA in eight hypothetical scenarios, characterized by different combinations of the attributes of the treatment offered.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The results were analyzed using probability analysis. Completed responses were provided from 1113 individuals (1024 GenPop, 21 parents, 68 HCPs).</seg>
          <seg id="4">Respondents were more likely to accept treatments that improved functioning and mobility.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Treatments with higher costs, invasive delivery, and risks of adverse events were accepted less often.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Cost most affected treatment choices by HCPs and GenPop, while change in mobility and mode of administration were most influential for parents.</seg>
          <seg id="7">These results highlight the importance of understanding value for money and clinical impact in affecting treatment choice, which are crucial for effective planning of healthcare and the successful implementation of treatment programmes for SMA.</seg>
          <seg id="8">What this paper adds Spinal muscular atrophy (SMA) treatments with a higher chance of improving functioning and mobility are preferred by the general population, parents, and healthcare professionals.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Treatments with higher costs, invasive delivery, and risk of adverse events are less preferred. Willingness to pay for SMA treatments increases with impact on functioning.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc16">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">To assess the levels of physical activity and exercise practice, and examine the associated maternal characteristics; as well as the anxiety levels of high-risk pregnant women.</seg>
          <seg id="2">A cross-sectional study conducted with pregnant women at a High-risk Prenatal Clinic (HRPC) in a tertiary maternity.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Pregnant women of 18 to 40-years-old, with a single fetus, and with gestational age up to 38 weeks were included.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The level of physical activity and exercise practice of the study's participants were investigated using the Pregnancy Physical Activity Questionnaire (PPAQ).</seg>
          <seg id="5">Maternal sociodemographic, anthropometric, and medical data were investigated using a specific form.</seg>
          <seg id="6">For anxiety levels, the short version of the State-Trait Anxiety Inventory (STAI) was applied.</seg>
          <seg id="7">We used the Student &lt;i&gt;t&lt;/i&gt;-test, chi-square test, odds ratio (OR) with 95% confidence interval (95% CI) and multiple logistic regression.</seg>
          <seg id="8">The significance level was 5%.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Among the 109 pregnant women included, 82 (75.2%) were classified as sedentary/little active.</seg>
          <seg id="10">The higher energy expenditure were for domestic activities (133.81 ± 81.84 METs), followed by work-related activities (40.77 ± 84.71 METs).</seg>
          <seg id="11">Only 19.3% women exercised during pregnancy (4.76 ± 12.47 METs), with slow walking being the most reported exercise.</seg>
          <seg id="12">A higher level of education was the most important factor associated with women being moderately or vigorously active (OR = 29.8; 95% CI 4.9-117.8).</seg>
          <seg id="13">Nulliparity (OR = 3.1; 95% CI 1.0-9.1), low levels of anxiety (OR = 3.6; 95% CI 1.2-10.7), and unemployment (OR = 4.8; 95% CI 1.1-19.6) were associated with the practice of exercise during pregnancy.</seg>
          <seg id="14">Most women with high-risk pregnancies exhibited a sedentary pattern, with low prevalence of physical exercise practice.</seg>
          <seg id="15">Recognizing factors that hinder the adoption of a more physically active lifestyle is essential for an individualized guidance regarding exercise during pregnancy.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc35">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Intracystic papillary carcinoma in a male as a rare presentation of breast cancer: a case report and literature review</seg>
          <seg id="2">Introduction: The term "intracystic papillary ductal carcinoma in situ" has recently changed and is now more appropriately referred to "intracystic papillary carcinoma".</seg>
          <seg id="3">Intracystic papillary carcinoma in men is an extremely rare disease with only a few case presentations published in the literature so far.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Case presentation: We discuss a case of a 44-year-old Caucasian man with an intracystic papillary carcinoma treated with simple mastectomy, sentinel lymph-node biopsy and contralateral risk-reducing mastectomy.</seg>
          <seg id="5">These were followed by adjuvant radiotherapy of the breast.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Conclusion: Triple assessment (i.e. clinical examination and radiological and histological assessment) with a high level of clinical suspicion is necessary to diagnose intracystic papillary carcinoma in men due to its rarity.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Furthermore, genetic testing and risk-reducing mastectomy should also be considered in cases of a strong family history for male breast cancer.</seg>
          <seg id="8">A 44-year-old Caucasian man presented to the breast clinic with a 3-week history of a swelling in his left breast.</seg>
          <seg id="9">He also had a significant family history for breast cancer including a maternal grandmother, two of his maternal aunts and a maternal first cousin diagnosed with breast cancer.</seg>
          <seg id="10">On examination, a well-circumscribed, 2.5 cm swelling was palpable within an area of gynecomastia on the left chest wall.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Sonographically, a cystic mass with internal echoes was present without posterior acoustic shadowing.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Aspiration of the lesion revealed uniformly blood-stained fluid and a residual swelling persisted.</seg>
          <seg id="13">Cytology analysis of the aspirate confirmed the presence of atypical cells.</seg>
          <seg id="14">Mammography showed a circumscribed mass in the sub-areolar region of the left breast with partially obscured margins.</seg>
          <seg id="15">An irregular outline was noted on cranio-caudal view, but no spiculation or suspicious internal micro-calcifications were found.</seg>
          <seg id="16">A core biopsy of the lesion revealed atypical ductal hyperplasia, but no evidence of malignancy was seen.</seg>
          <seg id="17">In view of the atypical cells and residual swelling the lesion was excised.</seg>
          <seg id="18">Histological analysis revealed a lesion 2.5 cm × 1.8 cm × 1.2 cm in size.</seg>
          <seg id="19">The lesion comprised a papillary and solid proliferation of atypical cells within a large cystic space with a thick fibrous capsule (Figures 1, 2, 3) Haemorrhage was also noted within the cyst with changes consistent with the prior biopsy.</seg>
          <seg id="20">The margins were clear; there was no evidence of stromal or fibrovascular invasion.</seg>
          <seg id="21">The lesion displayed features of papillary DCIS and a diagnosis of intracystic papillary DCIS was made.</seg>
          <seg id="22">Immunohistochemistry showed oestrogen receptor (ER) and progesterone receptor (PR) positivity.</seg>
          <seg id="23">Completion left mastectomy with sentinel lymph-node mapping was carried out.</seg>
          <seg id="24">Contralateral risk-reducing mastectomy was also performed in view of the strong family history for breast cancer.</seg>
          <seg id="25">No evidence of further disease was detected in the mammary tissue and the sentinel node was clear.</seg>
          <seg id="26">Adjuvant radiotherapy (40 Gy in 25 fractions) was advised due to tumour extension close to deep margin.</seg>
          <seg id="27">Due to his significant family history for breast cancer, genetic testing was offered.</seg>
          <seg id="28">Breast-cancer gene 2 (BRCA2) mutation had been identified in a maternal aunt recently on the exon 24 insertion called c9481_9482insA.</seg>
          <seg id="29">It was very likely that this patient was a carrier of this BRCA2 mutation, which poses a small risk for him to develop prostate cancer.</seg>
          <seg id="30">He was therefore advised to undergo prostate-specific antigen (PSA) blood testing on a yearly basis.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc9">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">To translate the My Experience Book toll into Portuguese, evaluate the translation content, readability, quality, and visual identity of the material, and make it available online.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Descriptive, cross-sectional, quantitative, and qualitative study.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The procedures consisted of five stages: translation of the material; evaluation and response to questionnaire one regarding translation; determining the validity of the content; readability assessment; availability of material online and evaluation of content aimed at quality and visual identity (questionnaire two).</seg>
          <seg id="4">Twenty-five professionals (audiologists and physicians) participated in the study.</seg>
          <seg id="5">The translation of the notebook showed validity agreement rates greater than 90%.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Readability rated the material easy to read.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Among the 184 invited professionals, only 25 agreed to participate, demonstrating low adherence to the study.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Most respondents agreed positively about the content and consistency of the translated material, videos, illustrative images, and captions.</seg>
          <seg id="9">The material was also considered necessary by the majority of the evaluators.</seg>
          <seg id="10">All audiologists reported using the instrument in clinical practice.</seg>
          <seg id="11">The translated toll is of great relevance. It gathers practical information to create a notebook of experiences and guidance on using the material as an additional resource to stimulate the auditory skills of children with hearing impairment.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
  </collection>
</dataset>
