<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<dataset id="wmttest2022">
  <collection id="biomedical-ref">
    <doc origlang="en" id="parallel">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Anthelmintic resistance (AR) of ruminant gastrointestinal nematodes (GINs) constitutes a major problem worldwide.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Among GINs, the abomasal blood-feeding parasite Haemonchus contortus is particularly pathogenic and may show resistance against all major anthelmintic substance classes.</seg>
          <seg id="3">In the present study, the death of a 1,5 year-old European bison (Bison bonasus) from a German wildlife park due to haemonchosis despite frequent anthelmintic treatment of the herd with fenbendazole as well as doramectin prompted an investigation regarding AR.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Pooled faecal samples were collected from four different bison groups as well as from mouflons (Ovis orientalis), elk (Alces alces), reindeer (Rangifer tarandus), sika deer (Cervus nippon), Persian fallow deer (Dama mesopotamica) and red deer (Cervus elaphus) housed by the wildlife park.</seg>
          <seg id="5">After coproscopical examination, faecal larval cultures were established.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Haemonchus contortus-positive larval cultures were further examined for genetic polymorphisms associated with benzimidazole resistance at codons 167 and 200 of the β-tubulin isotype 1 gene by real-time pyrosequencing.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Infections with H. contortus were detected in all four bison groups, as well as in mouflons.</seg>
          <seg id="8">In five samples, representing two bison groups and the mouflons, the frequency of the resistance-associated single-nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) at codon 200 was 100%.</seg>
          <seg id="9">In contrast, resistance-associated SNPs were not detected at codon 167.</seg>
          <seg id="10">In addition, faecal egg counts from two bison before and 14 days after parenteral doramectin treatment indicated possible macrocyclic lactone resistance.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Detection of anthelmintic resistant nematodes in these animals was especially concerning in the light of planned reintroduction into the wild.</seg>
          <seg id="12">As helminth control in zoological gardens and wildlife parks relies mostly on anthelmintic treatment due to restricted possibilities regarding management practices such as rotational grazing, care should be taken to avoid underdosing or unnecessary frequent treatments facilitating the development of AR.</seg>
          <seg id="13">Appendicular schwannoma is a rare benign neoplastic proliferation of the appendicular Schwann cells.</seg>
          <seg id="14">It is often asymptomatic until it occludes the appendicular lumen thus causing appendicitis-like symptoms.</seg>
          <seg id="15">The neoplastic proliferation of the Schwann cells, although benign, may rarely degenerate into a malignant neoplasm, thus denoting the importance of diagnosis.</seg>
          <seg id="16">Some Authors in the Literature used the term 'neuroma' or 'neurinoma' to indicate either a hyperplastic proliferation of the Schwann cells or its neoplastic but benign proliferation, thus raising the important question of a probable mistaking of these two different histologic entities.</seg>
          <seg id="17">The hyperplastic proliferation is usually subsequent to a chronic appendicular inflammation, and it is a more common finding in specimen of appendectomy.</seg>
          <seg id="18">Aim of the study is to review the published scientific papers about the rare histologic entity of appendicular schwannoma and to define the not clear aspects of Schwann cell neoplasia versus hyperplasia.</seg>
          <seg id="19">A review of the Literature from Medline/Pubmed has been accomplished.</seg>
          <seg id="20">Forty-four studies from the Literature resulted suitable for our study.</seg>
          <seg id="21">Appendicular schwannoma has to be considered in patients with recurrent right lower quadrant pain, and may affect the patient's prognosis if it remains undiagnosed, since it may degenerate in malignancy.</seg>
          <seg id="22">There is a lack of clarity in the Literature about the distinction between the hyperplastic and the neoplastic benign Schwann cells proliferation, which must be clarified.</seg>
          <seg id="23">The application of laparoscopic partial tubal resection with end-to-end anastomosis can reduce the incidence of persistent ectopic pregnancy.</seg>
          <seg id="24">We aim to compare the therapeutic effects of laparoscopic fenestration and laparoscopic partial tubal resection with end-to-end anastomosis in the treatment of tubal ectopic pregnancy.</seg>
          <seg id="25">The average operation time, intraoperative blood loss, postoperative exhaust time and hospital stay were observed to evaluate the clinical effect.</seg>
          <seg id="26">In addition, the time required for the β-HCG to drop to normal level, the patency of the fallopian tubes and the ovarian function were observed in the two groups after the operation.</seg>
          <seg id="27">The postoperative fallopian tube patency rate in the observation group was 67.58%, significantly higher than the control group (P &lt; 0.05).</seg>
          <seg id="28">The relationship between chronic rhinosinusitis, asthma and allergic rhinitis is well known, but only recently has the scientific community started to evaluate these as different manifestations of a common pathogenic phenomenon, considering them as a unified airway disease.</seg>
          <seg id="29">Two months after surgery, SNAQ questionnaire, nasal endoscopy, spirometry and bronchodilator responsiveness testing were repeated.</seg>
          <seg id="30">ESS achieved a beneficial effect on upper and lower airway status in patients with chronic rhinosinusitis with or without lower airway diseases.</seg>
          <seg id="31">X-ray Reconstruction of Moving Morphology (XROMM) permits researchers to see beneath the skin, usually to see musculoskeletal movements.</seg>
          <seg id="32">These movements can be tracked and later used to provide information regarding the mechanics of movement.</seg>
          <seg id="33">Here, we discuss '&lt;i&gt;IK marker-guided rotoscoping&lt;/i&gt;'-a method that combines inverse kinematic solvers with that of traditional scientific rotoscoping methods to quickly and efficiently overlay 3D bone geometries with the X-ray shadows from XROMM data.</seg>
          <seg id="34">We use a case study of three Nile crocodiles' (&lt;i&gt;Crocodylus niloticus&lt;/i&gt;) forelimbs and hindlimbs to evaluate this method.</seg>
          <seg id="35">Within these limbs, different marker configurations were used: some configurations had six markers, others had five markers, and all forelimb data only had three markers.</seg>
          <seg id="36">To evaluate IK marker-guided rotoscoping, we systematically remove markers in the six-marker configuration and then test the magnitudes of deviation in translations and rotations of the rigged setup with fewer markers versus those of the six-marker configuration.</seg>
          <seg id="37">Work-related musculoskeletal disorders are among the main occupational health problems.</seg>
          <seg id="38">Substantial evidence has shown that work-related physical risk factors are the main source of low back complaints, particularly affecting heavy and repetitive manual lifting activities.</seg>
          <seg id="39">The aim of the study is, during load lifting tasks, to explore the correlation between the time domain features extracted from the acceleration and angular velocity signals of the performing subject and the load lifted, and to explore the feasibility of a multiple linear regression model to predict the lifted load.</seg>
          <seg id="40">The acceleration and angular velocity signals were acquired along the three directions of space by means of an inertial sensor placed on the subject's chest, during lifting activities with load gradually increased by 1 kg from 0 kg to 18 kg.</seg>
          <seg id="41">Successively three time-domain features (Root Mean Square, Standard Deviation and MinMax value) were extracted from the acquired signals.</seg>
          <seg id="42">First a correlation analysis was carried out between each individual feature and the load lifted (calculating r); then the time-domain features that proved most representative (strong correlation) were used to create a multiple linear regression model (calculating R-square).</seg>
          <seg id="43">The statistical analysis was carried out by means of the Pearson correlation and multiple linear regression model was fed with the most informative time-domain features according to the correlation analysis.</seg>
          <seg id="44">The correlation analysis showed a strong correlation (r &gt; 0,7) between six features (three extracted from z-axes acceleration and three extracted from y-axes angular velocity) and the lifted load.</seg>
          <seg id="45">The predictive multiple linear regression model, fed with these six features achieved a Rsquare greater than 0,9.The study demonstrated that the proposed combination of kinematic features and a multiple regression model represents a valid approach to automatically calculate the load lifted based on raw signals obtained by means of an inertial sensor placed on the chest.</seg>
          <seg id="46">The results confirm the potential application of this methodology to indirectly monitor the load lifted by workers during their activity.</seg>
          <seg id="47">Many factors that influence patient outcome in colorectal surgery are not editable, and these are related either the tumor, the patient and the treatment. The surgeon- and hospital-related factors are independent predictors of outcome for colorectal cancer surgery and these are supervision, teaching/training, specialization in colorectal surgery, high caseload, high hospital caseload. We evaluated the impact of the experience of 4 surgeons on the 5 years survival rate of patients with colon and rectal cancer and we valued if the surgeons' experience plays an equal role in both.</seg>
          <seg id="48">Four experienced surgeons operated 384 patients with colorectal cancer.</seg>
          <seg id="49">Surgeon with the major experience and colorectal-dedicated presented a slightly better total 5 years survival rate, comparing to other surgeons, although he had a considerably better 5 years survival rate in rectal operations.</seg>
          <seg id="50">We concluded that surgeon- and hospital-related factors directly influence the surgeon learning curve and are therefore rightly considered predictors of outcome in colorectal cancer surgery.</seg>
          <seg id="51">SP represents the gold standard for the surgical treatment of benign tumors of the parotid gland greater than 3,5 cm in size involving superficial portion of the gland, for the low rate of recurrences over time and lower incidence of transient or permanent facial paralysis to which this technique leads.</seg>
          <seg id="52">However, SP is not free from other complications such as FS, haematoma, salivary fistula and aesthetic results like facial contour deformity due to surgical site depression and visible scar.</seg>
          <seg id="53">A reconstructive technique to reduce the impact of complications after SP is the SMAS flap because its preparation is easy, contextual to the parotidectomy and increases a little the surgical time.</seg>
          <seg id="54">The aim of this study is to evaluate the factors that has an effect on Cecal Intubation time (CIT), and to define the relationship between quality of bowel preparation and body mass index (BMI).</seg>
          <seg id="55">The Boston Bowel Preparation Scale (BBPS) was used for the evaluation of bowel cleansing.</seg>
          <seg id="56">A total of 346 patients were included.</seg>
          <seg id="57">The time from anus to caecum was recorded as the time of the cecal intubation time.</seg>
          <seg id="58">Patients were defined under 3 subgroup BMI-1; ≤ 24.9, BMI-2; 25-29.9, BMI-3; ≥30.</seg>
          <seg id="59">The mean BMI of women was 29.30 4.25 and men were 26.19 6.14 (p&lt;0,001).</seg>
          <seg id="60">Mean Cecal Intubation time was 9.11 6.00 and 10.21 3.45 minutes for women and men (p=0.012).</seg>
          <seg id="61">Women with High BMI (≥30) have shorter Cecal Intubation time compared to women with BMI less than 30 (p=0001).</seg>
          <seg id="62">When BBPS evaluated, there was a significant difference in BMI-3 due to high scores compared to both BMI-1 and BMI-2 (p&lt;0.001).</seg>
          <seg id="63">In BMI-3 group, also women had significantly higher scores in terms of BBPS(p=0.006).</seg>
          <seg id="64">Also a negative correlation between BBPS and BMI with CIT has been found (r = - 0.371, p&lt;0.001 / r = -0.191 p&lt;0.001).</seg>
          <seg id="65">To investigate the relationship between risk of Benign Paroxysmal Positional Vertigo (BPPV) recurrence and hypothyroidism treated with hormone replacement therapy (HRT).</seg>
          <seg id="66">797 patients with idiopathic BPPV were divided into two groups: 250 patients with recurrence of BPPV (R-BPPV) and 547 patients without recurrence (NR-BPPV).</seg>
          <seg id="67">Regarding patients with thyroid disease on HRT, we collected serum test results of thyroidstimulating hormone (TSH), free triiodothyronine f-T3, free thyroxine f-T4, thyroglobulin antibodies (TG-Ab) and thyroid peroxidase antibodies (TPO-Ab).</seg>
          <seg id="68">Hypothyroidism in long-term HRT was found in 61/250 (24.4%) patients of the RBPPV group vs 79/547 (14.4%) of the NR-BPPV-group (p = 0.0006).</seg>
          <seg id="69">Hashimoto thyroiditis (HT) was associated with recurrence (p &lt; 0.0001). A significant correlation was found between recurrence and level of serum TPO-Ab (p = 0.0117) and TG-Ab (p = 0.0025), but not with mean serum TSH, f-T3 and f-T4.</seg>
          <seg id="70">We assume that patients with hypothyroidism in HRT have an increased risk of BPPV recurrence, which is particularly strong for patients with HT and positive thyroid antibodies, suggesting an association between autoimmunity and recurrent vertigo.</seg>
          <seg id="71">Oral lichen planus (OLP) is a chronic inflammatory disease.</seg>
          <seg id="72">There are no markers that can be used to identify the risk of a malignant transformation of OLP to oral squamous cell carcinoma (OSCC).</seg>
          <seg id="73">Significant differences in p53 and HSP90 expression between OLP and OSCC were found (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.01 and &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.006, respectively).</seg>
          <seg id="74">A positive correlation between HSP90 and p53 expression was seen in OLP (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.017).</seg>
          <seg id="75">In multivariate analysis, only HSP90 expression was an independent prediction factor for shorter OS of OSCC patients (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.016).</seg>
          <seg id="76">The present study suggests that cooperation between p53 and HSP90 as well as between HPV16/18 and HSP90 exists in OLP and may affect the biological behaviour of OLP.</seg>
          <seg id="77">The observed expression of HSP90 and p53 in OLP and their increase in OSCC suggests that these proteins participate in the malignant transformation of OLP.</seg>
          <seg id="78">This retrospective study aimed to verify the outcomes of stabilising occlusal splint therapy prescribed to 22 patients with unilateral definite Ménière's disease and comorbid temporomandibular joint disorder.</seg>
          <seg id="79">The average hearing threshold in the affected ear and the acoustic immittance were unchanged. No spontaneous and positional nystagmus were recorded.</seg>
          <seg id="80">Occlusal splint therapy is a favourable option to reduce aural symptoms of Ménière's disease and comorbid temporomandibular joint disorder, even if its pathophysiological mechanism remains elusive.</seg>
          <seg id="81">Bariatric surgery is recognized as the most effective treatment for morbid obesity, maintaining a stable weight reduction in the long term and reducing comorbidities, with a favorable impact on mortality.</seg>
          <seg id="82">The aim of this study is to evaluate the complication rate and treatment techniques adopted in all patients undergoing bariatric surgery procedures in our center.</seg>
          <seg id="83">From May 2017 to March 2020, 91 patients with morbid obesity are admitted to the Department of Medical and Surgical Science of the University Hospital of Foggia undergoing bariatric surgery.</seg>
          <seg id="84">Regarding postoperative complications (8,8%), there were 1 gastric leak (1,09%), 4 bleedings (4,39%) - 1 intraluminal bleeding and 3 intra-abdominal bleedings, 2 port-sites infections (2,19%) and 1 haemoperitoneum (1,09%).</seg>
          <seg id="85">In our center we have also treated 3 cases of complications after bariatric surgery procedures performed in others centers.</seg>
          <seg id="86">There were no deaths.</seg>
          <seg id="87">The present study aimed to perform differences and any potential risk factors in anxious and depressive symptoms in Italian nurses during the Covid-19 pandemic according to selected sociodemographic variables.</seg>
          <seg id="88">In November 2020 an 'ad hoc' questionnaire was administered online to all Italian nurses.</seg>
          <seg id="89">In the first part, a whole series of socio-demographic variables relating to the reference sample were collected, as: gender, the department to which participants belonged, if the respondent suffered from pulmonary or cardiovascular diseases, if the nurse lived alone or with other cohabitants and whether during the pandemic the participant contracted the SARS-CoV-2 infection or not.</seg>
          <seg id="90">In the second part of the questionnaire, the Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale was administered to quickly and easily assess the anxiety and depression levels among the Italian nurses during the Covid-19 pandemic.</seg>
          <seg id="91">Results. 732 nurses agreed to participate to this survey.</seg>
          <seg id="92">Among participants, 479 (65.3%) recorded an anxious symptomatology and 267 (6.4%) a depressive one.</seg>
          <seg id="93">According to anxious symptoms, a significant difference was recorded between females and males (p min 0.001), as females recorded higher mild (24.04%), moderate (23.09%) and severe (13.39%) anxious symptom levels than males (Mild:1.50%; Moderate: 2.46%; Severe: 0.96%).</seg>
          <seg id="94">By considering depressive symptoms according to socio demographic variables, only nurses without cardiovascular diseases recorded higher frequencies in mild (21.58%), moderate (8.47%) and severe (2.46%) depressive symptoms than nurses who suffered from a cardiovascular disease (Mild:2.05%; Moderate: 1.64%; Severe: 0.27%).</seg>
          <seg id="95">Potential risk factors identified for anxious symptoms were: gender, both for mild (p min 0.001), moderate (p=.008) and severe (p=.003) anxious symptoms, and pulmonary diseases for severe anxious disorders (p=.014).</seg>
          <seg id="96">Potential risk factors identified for the onset of depressive symptoms were: gender (p=.026), pulmonary diseases (p=.021), domestic partnership (p=.035), for mild symptoms; the presence of cardiac diseases (p=.006) for moderate symptoms.</seg>
          <seg id="97">Conclusions.</seg>
          <seg id="98">It urged to begin to further implement all forms of psychological support for nurses and further implementation of university nursing training programs that aim at both the technical and psychological management of the future professional to cope with maxi emergencies.</seg>
          <seg id="99">Setaria tundra is known as a common parasite of sylvatic ungulates in Northern latitudes.</seg>
          <seg id="100">Although mostly considered of low pathogenicity, severe disease outbreaks and remarkable economic losses have been observed in reindeer (Rangifer tarandus tarandus).</seg>
          <seg id="101">Host density and climatic factors are major drivers of the expansion of Setaria spp.</seg>
          <seg id="102">facilitating their development and spread.</seg>
          <seg id="103">Five adult specimens of S. tundra were retrieved from a male roe deer in Bavaria, Germany.</seg>
          <seg id="104">Deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) barcoding confirmed morphological identification.</seg>
          <seg id="105">Cyclooxygenase 1 gene sequences showed 98,73-99,68 % similarity to sequences of other S. tundra specimens found in deer (Cervidae) and mosquitoes (Culicidae).</seg>
          <seg id="106">The results raise awareness for the presence of S. tundra in a hitherto unkown endemic region and represent a starting point for broader investigations to understand the biology and distribution of this parasite in roe deer as well as other potential definitive hosts.</seg>
          <seg id="107">Development and validation of a confocal laser endomicroscopy (CLE) classification score for the larynx and pharynx.</seg>
          <seg id="108">Thirteen patients (154 video sequences, 9240 images) with laryngeal or pharyngeal SCC were included in this prospective study between October 2020 and February 2021.</seg>
          <seg id="109">Each CLE sequence was correlated with the gold standard of histopathological examination.</seg>
          <seg id="110">Based on a dataset of 94 video sequences (5640 images), a scoring system was developed.</seg>
          <seg id="111">In the remaining 60 sequences (3600 images), the score was validated by four CLE experts and four head and neck surgeons who were not familiar with CLE.</seg>
          <seg id="112">Tissue homogeneity, cell size, borders and clusters, capillary loops and the nucleus/cytoplasm ratio were defined as the scoring criteria.</seg>
          <seg id="113">Using this score, the CLE experts obtained an accuracy, sensitivity, and specificity of 90.8%, 95.1%, and 86.4%, respectively, and the CLE non-experts of 86.2%, 86.4%, and 86.1%.</seg>
          <seg id="114">Interobserver agreement Fleiss' kappa was 0.8 and 0.6, respectively.</seg>
          <seg id="115">CLE can be reliably evaluated based on defined and reproducible imaging features, which demonstrate a high diagnostic value.</seg>
          <seg id="116">CLE can be easily integrated into the intraoperative setting and generate real-time, in-vivo microscopic images to demarcate malignant changes.</seg>
          <seg id="117">Therefore, the research team cut out an appropriately sized right pericardial fat pad patch during the operation for repairing and then covered it with a biological patch (Neoveil) for reinforcement.</seg>
          <seg id="118">A CT scan with contrast showed hemoperitoneum with a 20mm splenic aneurysm, which was located at the bifurcation of the splenic and left gastroepiploic artery.</seg>
          <seg id="119">After opening the gastro-colic ligament and obtaining vascular control of the splenic artery, the aneurysm was clipped and resected.</seg>
          <seg id="120">No macroscopic modifications occurred to the spleen.</seg>
          <seg id="121">This finding was confirmed by intravenous administration of indocyanine green.</seg>
          <seg id="122">Thyroid nodules with indeterminate cytology represent 20% of all thyroid nodules.</seg>
          <seg id="123">Inflammation plays an important role in cancer.</seg>
          <seg id="124">Lymphocyte-to-monocyte ratio (LMR), neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio (NLR) and platelet-to-lymphocyte ratio (PLR) are independent prognostic scores in numerous cancers, although no study has documented their role in cytology indeterminate nodules.</seg>
          <seg id="125">The aim of this study is to evaluate the role of LMR, NLR and PLR values as predictors of malignancy in patients with cytology indeterminate nodules.</seg>
          <seg id="126">This retrospective study analysed data from 298 patients with indeterminate thyroid nodule.</seg>
          <seg id="127">Anatomopathological and haematological data were analysed, dividing the population into two groups.</seg>
          <seg id="128">LMR, NLR and PLR values were determined using ROC curve and data were analysed using independent samples t-test, test of proportions, Fisher's exact test and univariate and multivariate logistic regression.</seg>
          <seg id="129">We found that a baseline LMR value ≥ 4.09 was indicative of benignity of indeterminate nodule.</seg>
          <seg id="130">The probability of malignancy in patients with LMR &lt; 4.09 was 26 times higher than patients with a LMR value ≥ 4.09.</seg>
          <seg id="131">The outbreak of the Covid-19 pandemic has seriously affected our society.</seg>
          <seg id="132">Governments have difficult situations by adopting strict and severe mitigation measures in order to contain the pandemic spreading.</seg>
          <seg id="133">These decisions influenced significatively people's behavior changing their habits and routines.</seg>
          <seg id="134">This study offers a statistical analysis of the incidence of the Maxillo-Facial traumas in Tuscany southern area, during the pandemic lockdown.</seg>
          <seg id="135">The calves were seven to nine days of age, and each feeding consisted of a volume of milk that was 6 % of the body weight of the calves.</seg>
          <seg id="136">The reticulum and abomasum were scanned ultrasonographically before, during and after drenching.</seg>
          <seg id="137">Drenching led to ruminal acidosis evidenced by a significant decrease in median pH from 7,0 (6,0 - 7,0) to 4,5 (3,0 - 5,0) and a 93-fold increase in median D-lactate concentration from 0,39 (0,14 - 1,33) to 36,3 (17,9 - 53,3) mmol/l but it did not cause metabolic acidosis.</seg>
          <seg id="138">Based on these findings, we concluded that milk administered to calves via an oesophageal tube feeder flows into the reticulum and abomasum simultaneously and three force feedings 12 hours apart cause acute ruminal acidosis, which was not accompanied by metabolic acidosis in the short term.</seg>
          <seg id="139">Equine granulocytic anaplasmosis (EGA) and equine piroplasmosis (EP) are triggered by tick-borne pathogens - the intracellular bacterium Anaplasma phagocytophilum and the intracellular protozoa Babesia caballi and Theileria equi.</seg>
          <seg id="140">These pathogens attack cells in the blood stream and cause similar clinical symptoms and changes in laboratory values.</seg>
          <seg id="141">Although the treatment principles are naturally different, similarities in prophylaxis exists due to the transmission route.</seg>
          <seg id="142">Tick transmitted pathogens can play a greater role in equine medicine in the future due to various factors, such as the tendency of relevant tick species to spread, but also the increasing import and travel activities of and with pets (both in the context of sporting events and as a leisure activity).</seg>
          <seg id="143">While EGA is endemic in Central Europe, EP is a sporadic disease in Switzerland, Austria and Germany.</seg>
          <seg id="144">However, EP must be viewed as underdiagnosed, as horses persistently infected with T. equi are also repeatedly detected in Central Europe.</seg>
          <seg id="145">These diseases should be considered in horses with a fever and corresponding laboratory changes.</seg>
          <seg id="146">Available diagnostic tests are direct pathogen detection by blood smear or PCR, and, indirect antibody detection, which is considered to be highly sensitive and (as a competitive ELISA) also very specific.</seg>
          <seg id="147">Acute infections can be detected with PCR, serology is more suitable for chronic infections.</seg>
          <seg id="148">A pathogen-free condition after treatment can be demonstrated with decreasing antibody titers in combination with repeated PCR tests.</seg>
          <seg id="149">In addition, clinically healthy horses infected with T. equi should be identified by antibody detection and appropriate preventative transmission measures must be initiated.</seg>
          <seg id="150">The prophylaxis of tick bites in horses is difficult due to the high exposure, and long-term tick bite prevention can hardly be guaranteed.</seg>
          <seg id="151">Monitoring of tick activity and strict measures to prevent the spread of the pathogen within the tick population are therefore of great importance.</seg>
          <seg id="152">We present the clinical observation of a female patient with cystic peritoneal malignant mesothelioma developed in the thickness of the abdominal wall.</seg>
          <seg id="153">The diagnosis included several steps: tumor classification as mesothelioma, tumor differentiation from reactive mesothelial hyperplasia, establishment of the malignant nature and differentiation from other malignant peritoneal tumors.</seg>
          <seg id="154">Relapse in about one year after surgery and about six months after the end of chemotherapy also claim malignancy of the tumor.</seg>
          <seg id="155">Toxoplasmosis is a worldwide occurring zoonosis caused by the obligate intracellular parasite Toxoplasma gondii (T. gondii).</seg>
          <seg id="156">All warm-blooded species, including humans, serve as intermediate hosts.</seg>
          <seg id="157">Definitive hosts are exclusively cats.</seg>
          <seg id="158">Farm poultry can become infected with oocysts from contaminated feed or directly from the ground, or by pecking of e.g. infected rodents.</seg>
          <seg id="159">This short literature review attempts to assess the current epidemiological situation in farmed poultry and to assess the possible relevance of toxoplasmosis of poultry meat and poultry meat products for human consumption.</seg>
          <seg id="160">Meningiomas as anatomo-pathological entities were first described in the sixteenth century, but it was Harvey Cusching who in 1922 proposed to identify them with the term 'meningioma'.</seg>
          <seg id="161">They are the most common intracranial tumors, occur between middle and late age and prefer female sex.</seg>
          <seg id="162">The symptoms depend on their position with respect to the brain regions.</seg>
          <seg id="163">These are mostly benign neoplasms, but there are atypical and even malignant forms.</seg>
          <seg id="164">Plaque meningioma refers to a specific macroscopic aspect of the meningioma, due to diffuse dural involvement and usually with extracranial extension.</seg>
          <seg id="165">The development of acute pancreatitis is multifactorial requiring predisposition and relevant injury.</seg>
          <seg id="166">Viral acute pancreatitis has been described in other viral infections.</seg>
          <seg id="167">However, pancreatic involvement in SARS-CoV-2 infection is still poorly defined.</seg>
          <seg id="168">The present comparative study reports the patients with acute pancreatitis during the COVID-19 pandemic and last year covering the same period to appraise the link between COVID-19 and acute biliary pancreatitis.</seg>
          <seg id="169">The retrospective observational study was conducted in acute biliary pancreatitis patients from 13.03.19to13.09.19 and from 13.03.20to13.09.20 respectively. The study included 181patients(105patients in 2019;76 patients in 2020(during COVID-19 pandemic)).The patients were named as Group A(Normal period)and GroupB(Pandemic period),respectively.</seg>
          <seg id="170">The groups were found to be comparable as there was no significant difference between the mean age, sex, comorbidities, cholecystectomized, and recurrency.</seg>
          <seg id="171">Awareness of these issues and addressing them adequately will be crucial for the management.</seg>
          <seg id="172">Enterobius Vermicularis (EV) is the most commonly identified heminth incidentally found within the appendix of a clinically diagnosed appendicitis.</seg>
          <seg id="173">Early diagnosis of cochlear implant failures (CIF) is a critical part of post-implantation follow-up.</seg>
          <seg id="174">Diagnosis is challenging and time consuming.</seg>
          <seg id="175">Our study aimed to describe diagnoses of CIF with emphasis on soft failures (SF), focusing on symptoms, time from symptoms to replacement, and differences between SF and hard failures (HF).</seg>
          <seg id="176">A retrospective review of medical records in a tertiary care referral paediatric medical centre including all patients who experienced CIF during 2000-2020.</seg>
          <seg id="177">Of 1004 CI surgeries, 72 (7.2%) cases of CIF were included, of which 60 CIF were in children (mean age 3.1 years).</seg>
          <seg id="178">Twenty-five cases were due to HF, 26 SF, and 21 due to medical reasons.</seg>
          <seg id="179">Patients with SF were more likely to present with headache, dizziness, or tinnitus compared with those with HF.</seg>
          <seg id="180">Facial stimulation and disconnections were more common in implants from Advanced Bionics, dizziness and tinnitus in Cochlear, and poor progression in Med-El.</seg>
          <seg id="181">Mean time from symptoms to implant replacement surgery was longer in cases with SF compared to HF.</seg>
          <seg id="182">SF poses a diagnostic challenge.</seg>
          <seg id="183">Symptoms such as headache, dizziness, and tinnitus are common.</seg>
          <seg id="184">Diagnosis of failure should often be based on assessments of the implant and rehabilitation teams.</seg>
          <seg id="185">This paper retrospectively reviews our experience with endovascular and hybrid treatments for subclavian artery aneurysms (SAA).</seg>
          <seg id="186">Seventeen patients with SAAs were treated at our center between July 2011 and October 2018.</seg>
          <seg id="187">Clinical and follow-up data were extracted from the hospital records and retrospectively reviewed.</seg>
          <seg id="188">We routinely use endovascular treatments and stenting or axillary-axillary bypass to treat SAA if vertebral artery blood flow requires restoration.</seg>
          <seg id="189">Patients were followed up at 3, 6, and 12 months after their operations and yearly thereafter.</seg>
          <seg id="190">Median follow-up was 30.5 months.</seg>
          <seg id="191">In 6 patients, the SAAs involved the ipsilateral vertebral artery. Simple coil embolization was performed for 1 patient; endovascular covered stenting and coil embolization for 4 patients; and hybrid treatment for 1 patient.</seg>
          <seg id="192">In 11 patients, the SAAs did not involve the ipsilateral vertebral artery.</seg>
          <seg id="193">Hybrid treatment was performed for 1 patient; thoracic aortic stent implantation with coil embolization for 1 patient; and covered stent placement in the subclavian artery for 9 patients.</seg>
          <seg id="194">Among the 9 patients who were symptomatic at presentation, 8 had relief of symptoms.</seg>
          <seg id="195">Leakage was observed in 1 patient, but it stopped spontaneously.</seg>
          <seg id="196">Stent occlusion occurred in 33% (3/9), but all were asymptomatic, and no interventions were necessary.</seg>
          <seg id="197">We aimed to determine whether intraabdominal pressure change caused by pneumoperitoneum created during laparoscopic cholecystectomy (LC) has effects on abdominal and shoulder pain, nausea, vomiting, bowel movements, time of first flatus and defecation, and biochemical parameters.</seg>
          <seg id="198">Seventy patients that were diagnosed with cholelithiasis and would undergo LC, between the ages of 18-75, with the Society of Anesthesia Physical Status (ASA) I-III classifications were included in the study.</seg>
          <seg id="199">Patients were divided into two groups as whose intervention was defined as low pressure (8-10 mm/hg) and whose intervention was defined as high pressure (14-16 mm/hg).</seg>
          <seg id="200">The COVID-19 pandemic emergency forced the health system in Italy to implement an immediate reorganisation to support the care of tens of thousands of patients and to maintain the quality of care for patients with other pathologies, such as oncologic diseases.</seg>
          <seg id="201">The main goal of this study was to evaluate the impact of COVID-19 restrictions on the hospitalisation and post-operative rehabilitation of head and neck oncologic patients and to determine whether the introduction of new technologies such as video-communication may be useful to mitigate social distancing by close family members.</seg>
          <seg id="202">Fifty-one consecutive patients underwent surgery for head and neck cancer during the period of lockdown caused by the COVID-19 pandemic.</seg>
          <seg id="203">The data collected (post-operative pain, post-operative complications, duration of hospitalisation) were compared with those of 51 consecutive patients treated for head and neck cancer in the period immediately preceding lockdown.</seg>
          <seg id="204">The average duration of hospitalisation was longer in patients operated on in the COVID-19 period, and, in particular, among patients who underwent a more demanding rehabilitation protocol.</seg>
          <seg id="205">Despite this, our study did not show a significant difference in psychological aspects during hospitalisation.</seg>
          <seg id="206">The greatest difficulties that occurred in the COVID-19 period were met by a greater commitment from medical staff, allowing the quality of life of head and neck cancer patients during post-operative rehabilitation to be maintained at a similar level to that before the pandemic.</seg>
          <seg id="207">In the future, there will be a need for technological solutions to bring the patient closer to family members.</seg>
          <seg id="208">A series of oligomers of the type Boc-(L-Phe-D-Oxd)(n)-OBn (Boc = tert-butoxycarbonyl; Oxd = 4-methyl-5-carboxy oxazolidin-2-one; Bn = benzyl) were prepared for n = 2-5.</seg>
          <seg id="209">The shortest oligomer, Boc-(L-Phe-D-Oxd)(2)-OBn, aggregates and forms a fiber-like material with an anti-parallel beta-sheet structure in which the oligopeptide units are connected to each other by only one intermolecular hydrogen bond. The longer oligomers exhibit structural heterogeneity.</seg>
          <seg id="210">They start to organize into secondary structures by the formation of intramolecular hydrogen bonds at the pentamer level.</seg>
          <seg id="211">Microscopy and diffraction of the oligomers indicated a crystalline character for only the shorter ones.</seg>
          <seg id="212">Feline Calicivirus (FCV) is one of the most common viral pathogens in domestic cats worldwide.</seg>
          <seg id="213">The first report of FCV dates back to 1957, when FCV was isolated from the gastrointestinal tract of cats in New Zealand.</seg>
          <seg id="214">Subsequent reports recognised FCV as a cause of respiratory disease in cats, and at present, feline practitioners worldwide are daily confronted with cats suffering from suspected FCV.</seg>
          <seg id="215">The highly mutagenic nature of FCV and its high genetic plasticity enable the virus to successfully survive in the feline population, and pose a special challenge as regards the diagnosis, treatment, and prevention of FCV-induced disease.</seg>
          <seg id="216">Upper respiratory tract disease has been considered a common clinical sign of FCV infection.</seg>
          <seg id="217">A study from Switzerland demonstrated that oral ulcerations, salivation and gingivitis-stomatitis were more commonly associated with FCV infection than upper respiratory tract disease, and less than half of the cats suspected to have FCV infection were found to be FCV-positive.</seg>
          <seg id="218">Furthermore, a study investigating FCV isolates from Switzerland found some evidence that the genetic background of cats might influence their susceptibility to FCV infection.</seg>
          <seg id="219">This review article provides a comprehensive summary of the FCV literature, and integrates the results of recent research on FCV's genetic characteristics, the cellular and humoral immunity evoked by FCV vaccination and infection, the diagnosis of FCV, FCV prevention/vaccination, the risk factors associated with FCV, and the hygienic measures necessary in FCV-contaminated areas.</seg>
          <seg id="220">After each section, the key points are summarised, and relevant information is outlined to help feline practitioners in FCV diagnosis, treatment and prevention.</seg>
          <seg id="221">Cochlear fistula (CF) is a rare finding, usually associated with extensive middle ear cholesteatoma.</seg>
          <seg id="222">There is agreement on the fact that removing the cholesteatoma matrix on a CF exposes the ear to a high risk of sensorineural hearing loss or dead ear.</seg>
          <seg id="223">The study considers a retrospective case series of patients with CF diagnosis supported by CT-scan and intraoperative/otoscopic evidence.</seg>
          <seg id="224">Five cases of CF were identified, 4 associated with cholesteatoma and 1 associated with non-cholesteatomatous COM.</seg>
          <seg id="225">Two patients presenting with anacusis underwent a subtotal petrosectomy. Two patients with useful hearing underwent a radical mastoidectomy in order to preserve the cholesteatoma matrix on the promontorium.</seg>
          <seg id="226">One patient with good hearing and COM was treated conservatively.</seg>
          <seg id="227">Conservative management should be considered for rare cases of CF in COM with residual hearing.</seg>
          <seg id="228">Matrix preservation through radical/modified radical mastoidectomy is strongly advised in the presence of useful preoperative bone conduction.</seg>
          <seg id="229">Subtotal petrosectomy should be considered the preferred option in presence of cholesteatoma with preoperative profound hearing loss.</seg>
          <seg id="230">Ethyl nitroacetate (1) reacts with electron-poor olefins in the presence of a base to give either the Michael adducts 3 or the isoxazoline cycloadducts 4, resulting from water elimination.</seg>
          <seg id="231">The proportions of the two products depend on the reaction conditions and change in the course of the process.</seg>
          <seg id="232">Kinetic profiles for the two reactions show that the cycloaddition-condensations require long induction times that dramatically decrease upon addition of a copper salt to the catalytic system: the drops in the induction time cause increases in the proportion of cycloadducts 4, which are often the sole reaction products.</seg>
          <seg id="233">This is the first report on the selective formation of products 3 and 4 from primary nitro compounds through modulation of the catalytic system.</seg>
          <seg id="234">The prevalence of methicillin-resistant Macrococcus spp.</seg>
          <seg id="235">in calves and pigs at slaughterhouses and in retail beef and pork meat was determined using samples taken in 2019 within the framework of the national monitoring of methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus in food producing animals in Switzerland.</seg>
          <seg id="236">The isolates were submitted to antimicrobial susceptibility testing of 19 antibiotics and to molecular techniques (e.g. PCR, microarray, WGS) for the identification of resistance genes, elements containing the methicillin resistance genes mec and sequence type (ST).</seg>
          <seg id="237">Methicillin-resistant Macrococcus spp. (M. caseolyticus (n=38), M. bohemicus (n=4) and Macrococcus spp. (n=2)) were isolated in 40 of 299 nasal swabs from calves representing a prevalence of 13,38 % (95 % CI, 9,98 % - 17,70 %), and in four of 303 nasal swabs from pigs [1,32 % (95 % CI, 0,36 % - 3,35 %)].</seg>
          <seg id="238">One of 311 samples of Swiss pork meat contained a Macrococcus sp. [0,32 % (95 % CI, 0,01 % - 1,78 %)], and four of 309 beef meat samples (260 domestic and 49 imported) contained M. caseolyticus [1,29 % (95 % CI, 0,35 % - 3,28 %)].</seg>
          <seg id="239">The M. caseolyticus strains belonged to diverse STs, with ST21 being the most common in both pigs and calves.</seg>
          <seg id="240">The mecD gene was located on Macrococcus resistance island mecD (McRImecD) in 42 strains and on staphylococcal cassette chromosome mec (SCCmecD) in three strains, while mecB was found on plasmids in four strains.</seg>
          <seg id="241">In addition to resistance to β-lactams, the strains also exhibited resistance to tetracycline (n=17; tet(L), tet(K), tet(M)), streptomycin (n=13; str, ant(6)-Ia, rpsL mutation [K56R in ribosomal protein S12]), kanamycin (n=10; aac(6')-Ie - aph(2'')-Ia, aph(2')-Ib, aph(2')-Ic, ant(4')-Ia), clindamycin (n=9; erm(B), erm(45)), erythromycin (n=9; erm(B), msr(G), erm(45)), fusidic acid (n=9; fusC) and gentamicin (n=1; aac(6')-Ie - aph(2'')-Ia).</seg>
          <seg id="242">This study represents the first national prevalence study of methicillin-resistant Macrococcus spp.</seg>
          <seg id="243">in pigs, calves, pork and beef meat in Switzerland and revealed a reservoir of genetically diverse strains carrying several resistance traits.</seg>
          <seg id="244">The aim of this study was to evaluate the safety and efficacy of endoscopic submucosal dissection (ESD) of colonic polyps larger than 20 mm.</seg>
          <seg id="245">Between March 2017 and July 2019, a gastro-entero endoscopist team resected 24 large colorectal polyps measuring 20-35 mm in diameter using the ESD technique.</seg>
          <seg id="246">After the injection of a mixture of hydroxypropyl methylcellulose with dilute epinephrine and methylene blue into the submucosal layer, a circumferential incision was performed using an electrosurgical knife.</seg>
          <seg id="247">The mean age of the patients was 60 years; 16 patients were men and 4 patients were women.</seg>
          <seg id="248">The mean polyp size removed by colorectal ESD was 35.3 mm (range 20.0-70.1 mm), and all 24 polyps were larger than 2 cm (100%).</seg>
          <seg id="249">There were no cases of delayed bleeding after the colorectal ESD nor were there any post-surgery complications.</seg>
          <seg id="250">This study demonstrates the efficacy and safety of carrying out ESD of large polyps.</seg>
          <seg id="251">This is important because there is not a large body of literature on this subject in this specific population. Colonic polyps, Endoscopic submucosal dissection, Gastrointestinal endoscopy.</seg>
          <seg id="252">This study sought to identify the optimal intraoperative sphenoidotomy size for prevention of postoperative stenosis.</seg>
          <seg id="253">32 patients affected by chronic rhinosinusitis not associated with nasal polyps (CRSsNP) underwent 52 sphenoidotomies.</seg>
          <seg id="254">Sphenoidotomy size was assessed using a ruler intraoperatively and at the first, third and sixth months postoperatively.</seg>
          <seg id="255">Ostia sizes, SNOT-22 questionnaire findings, episodes of recurrent sinusitis and need for revision surgery were recorded.</seg>
          <seg id="256">All sphenoidotomies exhibited a significant size reduction (mean 43.4 ± 6.8%) at the first month postoperatively, with a tendency to enlarge at 3 months and stabilise at 6 months.</seg>
          <seg id="257">Ostia larger than 61.3 mm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; did not exhibit stenoses postoperatively.</seg>
          <seg id="258">Stenosis was observed in 11 sphenoidotomies (21.2%); however, only five presented with recurrent symptoms (9.6%), while three required revision sphenoid surgery (5.8%).</seg>
          <seg id="259">Sphenoidotomy size significantly reduced during the first postoperative month and then stabilised.</seg>
          <seg id="260">A baseline sphenoidotomy size of 61.3 mm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; at the time of the operation seemed sufficient to prevent ostium stenosis.</seg>
          <seg id="261">Half of stenosed ostia presented with recurrent symptoms.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
      <ref lang="it" translator="A">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">La resistenza agli antielmintici (RA) dei nematodi gastrointestinali (GIN) dei ruminanti costituisce un problema importante a livello mondiale.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Tra i GIN, il parassita abomasale che si nutre di sangue Haemonchus contortus è particolarmente patogeno e può mostrare resistenza contro tutte le principali classi di sostanze antielmintiche.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Nel presente studio, la morte di un bisonte europeo di 1,5 anni (Bison bonasus) di un parco faunistico tedesco a causa di una emoncosi, nonostante il frequente trattamento antielmintico della mandria con fenbendazolo e doramectina, ha spinto ad indagare sulla RA.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Campioni fecali raggruppati sono stati raccolti da quattro diversi gruppi di bisonti, nonché da mufloni (Ovis orientalis), alci (Alces alces), renne (Rangifer tarandus), cervi sika (Cervus nippon), daini persiani (Dama mesopotamica) e cervi nobili (Cervus elaphus) ospitati nel parco naturale.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Dopo l’esame coproscopico, sono state stabilite le colture larvali fecali.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Le colture larvali risultate positive di Haemonchus contortus sono state ulteriormente esaminate per i polimorfismi genetici associati alla resistenza al benzimidazolo ai codoni 167 e 200 del gene isotipo 1 della β-tubulina mediante pirosequenziamento in tempo reale.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Le infezioni da H. contortus sono state rilevate in tutti e quattro i gruppi di bisonti, così come nei mufloni.</seg>
          <seg id="8">In cinque campioni, che rappresentano due gruppi di bisonti e i mufloni, la frequenza del polimorfismo a singolo nucleotide (SNP) associato alla resistenza al codone 200 era del 100%.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Al contrario, gli SNP associati alla resistenza non sono stati rilevati al codone 167.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Inoltre, il conteggio delle uova fecali di due bisonti prima e 14 giorni dopo il trattamento parenterale con doramectina ha indicato una possibile resistenza ai lattoni macrociclici.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Il rilevamento di nematodi resistenti agli antielmintici in questi animali è particolarmente preoccupante alla luce della prevista reintroduzione in natura.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Poiché il controllo degli elminti nei giardini zoologici e nei parchi faunistici si basa principalmente sul trattamento antielmintico a causa delle limitate possibilità relative alle pratiche di gestione come il pascolo a rotazione, si dovrebbe fare attenzione ad evitare il sotto dosaggio o trattamenti frequenti non necessari che facilitano lo sviluppo della RA.</seg>
          <seg id="13">Lo schwannoma appendicolare è una rara proliferazione neoplastica benigna delle cellule di Schwann della parete della struttura.</seg>
          <seg id="14">È spesso asintomatico fino a quando non occlude il lume della struttura causando sintomi simili all’appendicite acuta.</seg>
          <seg id="15">La proliferazione neoplastica delle cellule di Schwann, sebbene benigna, può raramente degenerare in una neoplasia maligna, motivando pertanto l’importanza della diagnosi puntuale.</seg>
          <seg id="16">Alcuni Autori in Letteratura hanno utilizzato il termine “neuroma” o “neurinoma” per indicare rispettivamente una proliferazione iperplastica delle cellule di Schwann o una sua proliferazione neoplastica ma benigna, sollevando così l’importante questione di un probabile equivoco tra queste due diverse entità istologiche.</seg>
          <seg id="17">La proliferazione iperplastica è solitamente successiva a un’infiammazione appendicolare cronica ed è un reperto più comune nei campioni di appendicectomia.</seg>
          <seg id="18">Scopo dello studio è rivedere i lavori scientifici pubblicati sulla rara entità istologica dello schwannoma appendicolare e definire gli aspetti non chiari della neoplasia a cellule di Schwann rispetto all’iperplasia.</seg>
          <seg id="19">È stata effettuata una revisione della letteratura da Medline/Pubmed.</seg>
          <seg id="20">Quarantaquattro studi della Letteratura sono risultati idonei per il nostro studio.</seg>
          <seg id="21">Lo schwannoma appendicolare deve essere preso in considerazione nei pazienti con dolore ricorrente al quadrante inferiore destro e può influenzare la prognosi del paziente se rimane non diagnosticato, poiché può degenerare in tumore maligno.</seg>
          <seg id="22">C’è una mancanza di chiarezza in Letteratura sulla distinzione tra proliferazione iperplastica e neoplastica benigna delle cellule di Schwann, che deve essere chiarita.</seg>
          <seg id="23">L’esecuzione della resezione tubarica parziale laparoscopica con anastomosi end-to-end può ridurre l’incidenza di gravidanze ectopiche ricorrenti.</seg>
          <seg id="24">Lo scopo di questo studio è quello di confrontare gli effetti terapeutici della fenestrazione laparoscopica e della resezione tubarica parziale laparoscopica con l’anastomosi end-to-end nel trattamento della gravidanza ectopica tubarica.</seg>
          <seg id="25">Il tempo medio dell’operazione, la perdita di sangue intraoperatoria, il tempo di dimissione postoperatoria e la degenza ospedaliera sono stati osservati per valutare il loro effetto clinico.</seg>
          <seg id="26">Inoltre, nei due gruppi dopo l’operazione sono stati osservati il tempo necessario affinché la -HCG scenda a livelli normali, la pervietà delle tube di Falloppio e la funzione ovarica.</seg>
          <seg id="27">Il normale tasso di gravidanza del gruppo di osservazione era del 67,58%, significativamente più alto rispetto al gruppo di controllo (P &lt;0,05).</seg>
          <seg id="28">La relazione tra rinosinusite cronica, asma e rinite allergica è ben nota, ma solo recentemente la comunità scientifica ha iniziato a considerarle come manifestazioni differenti di un comune evento patogenetico.</seg>
          <seg id="29">A distanza di 2 mesi dall’operazione i pazienti sono stati nuovamente sottoposti a SNAQ, endoscopia nasale, spirometria e test di broncoreversibilità.</seg>
          <seg id="30">La chirurgia dei seni paranasali ha dimostrato di apportare benefici sia alle alte che alle basse vie aeree in pazienti con rinosinusite cronica, associata o meno a disturbi delle basse vie aeree.</seg>
          <seg id="31">X-ray Reconstruction of Moving Morphology (XROMM) consente a ricercatori di vedere sotto la pelle, solitamente per osservare movimenti muscoloscheletrici.</seg>
          <seg id="32">Questi movimenti possono essere tracciati per poi ottenere informazioni sulle meccaniche del movimento.</seg>
          <seg id="33">In questo articolo discutiamo ‘IK marker-guided rotoscoping’ - un metodo che combina inverse kinematic solvers con metodi scientifici tradizionali di rotoscoping per sovrapporre modelli geometrici 3D delle ossa in modo rapido ed efficiente utilizzando le ombre a raggi x dai dati XROMM.</seg>
          <seg id="34">Per valutare questo metodo usiamo come studio di caso arti anteriori e posteriori di tre coccodrilli del Nilo (&lt;i&gt;Crocodylus niloticus&lt;/i&gt;).</seg>
          <seg id="35">Tra questi arti, sono state usate diverse configurazioni per i marker: alcune configurazioni avevano 6 marker, altre 5 e tutti gli arti anteriori avevano 3 marker.</seg>
          <seg id="36">Per valutare ‘IK marker-guided rotoscoping', sistematicamente rimuoviamo marker dalla configurazione che usava 6 marker e poi testiamo la magnitudine della deviazione in traslazione e rotazione tra il modello con meno marker e quello originale da 6.</seg>
          <seg id="37">I disturbi muscoloscheletrici rappresentano uno dei principali problemi di salute sul lavoro.</seg>
          <seg id="38">Prove sostanziali hanno dimostrato che i fattori di rischio fisico legati al lavoro sono la principale fonte di disturbi al rachide, in particolare per le attività di sollevamento manuale pesanti e ripetitive.</seg>
          <seg id="39">Lo scopo dello studio è di esplorare, su soggetti che svolgono attività di sollevamento carichi, la correlazione tra le caratteristiche nel dominio del tempo estratte da segnali di accelerazione e velocità angolare, ed esplorare la fattibilità di un modello di regressione lineare multipla per stimare il carico sollevato.</seg>
          <seg id="40">I segnali di accelerazione e velocità angolare sono stati acquisiti lungo le tre direzioni dello spazio mediante un sensore inerziale posto sul torace del soggetto, durante attività di sollevamento con carico progressivamente aumentato di 1 kg, da 0 kg a 18 kg.</seg>
          <seg id="41">Successivamente tre caratteristiche del dominio del tempo (valore quadratico medio, deviazione standard e valore MinMax) sono state estratte dai segnali acquisiti.</seg>
          <seg id="42">Dapprima è stata effettuata un’analisi di correlazione tra ogni singola caratteristica e il carico sollevato (calcolando il coefficiente di correlazione); quindi le caratteristiche del dominio del tempo che si sono dimostrate più rappresentative (alta correlazione) sono state utilizzate per creare un modello di regressione multipla (calcolo del coefficiente di determinazione).</seg>
          <seg id="43">L’analisi statistica è stata effettuata mediante il calcolo del coefficiente di correlazione di Pearson e il modello di regressione lineare multipla alimentato con le caratteristiche nel dominio del tempo che sono risultate più informative secondo l’analisi di correlazione.</seg>
          <seg id="44">L’analisi di correlazione ha mostrato una correlazione forte (r &gt; 0,7) tra sei caratteristiche (tre estratte dall’accelerazione lungo l’asse z e tre estratte dalla velocità angolare intorno all’asse y) e il carico sollevato.</seg>
          <seg id="45">Il modello di regressione lineare multipla, alimentato con queste sei caratteristiche, ha ottenuto un coefficiente di determinazione maggiore di 0,9. Lo studio ha dimostrato che il modello di regressione lineare multipla proposto, alimentato con specifiche caratteristiche estratte da segnali prelevati da un sensore inerziale posizionato sullo sterno, rappresenta un valido approccio per calcolare automaticamente il carico sollevato.</seg>
          <seg id="46">I risultati confermano la potenziale applicazione di questa metodologia per monitorare indirettamente il carico sollevato dai lavoratori durante la loro attività..</seg>
          <seg id="47">Molti fattori che influenzano l’esito del paziente operato per Chirurgia colorettale sono indipendenti, come correlati al chirurgo, al numero degli interventi dell’ospedale, all’addestramento chirurgico ed alla specializzazione in Chirurgia colorettale Abbiamo valutato l’impatto dell’esperienza di 4 chirurghi seniors della nostra istituzione sulla sopravvivenza dei pazienti affetti da carcinoma colorettale valutando il ruolo dell’esperienza del singolo dedicato.</seg>
          <seg id="48">Come risultato quattro chirurghi seniors hanno trattato 384 casi affetti da carcinoma colorettale.</seg>
          <seg id="49">Il chirurgo con la maggior esperienza e dedicato a questa chirurgia ha havuto come risultato una migliore sopravvivenza a 5 anni, avendo trattato un maggior numero di carcinomi rettali.</seg>
          <seg id="50">In conclusione l’esperienza del chirurgo e della squadra chirurgica influenza direttamente la curva di apprendimento e possono essere considerati i fattori che influenzano l’esito.</seg>
          <seg id="51">La parotidectomia superficiale rappresenta il gold standard per il trattamento chirurgico dei tumori benigni della porzione superficiale della ghiandola parotide di dimensioni superiori a 3,5 cm per il basso tasso di recidive nel tempo e per la minore incidenza di paralisi facciale transitoria o permanente.</seg>
          <seg id="52">Tuttavia tale tecnica chirurgica non   esente da altre complicanze quali Sindrome di Frey, ematoma, fistola salivare e danni estetici (depressione del sito chirurgico, cicatrice cutanea visibile).</seg>
          <seg id="53">Una delle tecniche ricostruttive per ridurre l’impatto delle complicanze dopo parotidectomia superficiale   il lembo del Sistema Muscolo aponeurotico Superficiale (SMAS) perch  la sua preparazione   facile, contestuale alla parotidectomia ed aumenta solo di un poco il tempo chirurgico.</seg>
          <seg id="54">Lo scopo di questo studio   valutare i fattori che hanno un effetto sul tempo di intubazione cecale (CIT) e definire la relazione tra la qualit  della preparazione intestinale e l’indice di massa corporea (BMI).</seg>
          <seg id="55">Per la valutazione della pulizia dell’intestino   stata utilizzata la Boston Bowel Preparation Scale (BBPS).</seg>
          <seg id="56">Sono stati inclusi un totale di 346 pazienti.</seg>
          <seg id="57">Il tempo dall’ano al cieco   stato registrato come tempo di intubazione cecale.</seg>
          <seg id="58">I pazienti sono stati definiti sotto 3 sottogruppi BMI-1; ≤ 24,9, BMI- 2; 25-29,9, BMI-3; ≥30.</seg>
          <seg id="59">Il BMI medio delle donne era 29,30   4,25 e gli uomini 26,19   6,14 (p &lt;0,001).</seg>
          <seg id="60">Il tempo medio di intubazione cecale era di 9,11   6,00 e 10,21   3,45 minuti per donne e uomini (p = 0,012).</seg>
          <seg id="61">Le donne con BMI elevato (≥30) hanno un tempo di intubazione cecale pi  breve rispetto alle donne con BMI inferiore a 30 (p = 0001).</seg>
          <seg id="62">Quando BBPS ha valutato, c’era una differenza significativa nell’IMC-3 a causa dei punteggi pi  alti rispetto a entrambi BMI-1 e BMI-2 (p &lt;0,001).</seg>
          <seg id="63">Nel gruppo BMI-3, anche le donne avevano punteggi significativamente pi  alti in termini di BBPS (p = 0,006).</seg>
          <seg id="64">stata trovata anche una correlazione negativa tra BBPS e BMI con CIT (r = – 0,371, p &lt;0,001 / r = – 0,191 p &lt;0,001).</seg>
          <seg id="65">Analisi dell’associazione tra la ricorrenza della Vertigine parossistica posizionale benigna (BPPV) e l’ipotiroidismo in corso di terapia ormonale sostitutiva (TOS).</seg>
          <seg id="66">797 pazienti affetti da BPPV idiopatica sono stati suddivisi in due gruppi: 250 con vertigine ricorrente (R-BPPV) e 547 (NR-BPPV) non ricorrente.</seg>
          <seg id="67">Nei pazienti ipotiroidei sono stati analizzati i valori ematici tiroidei: ormone tireotropo (TSH), frazioni libere di tetraiodotironina (f-T4) e triiodiotironina (f-T3), anticorpi anti tireoperossidasi (TPO-Ab) ed anti tireoglobulina (TG-Ab).</seg>
          <seg id="68">L’ipotiroidismo è emerso in 61/250 (24,4%) pazienti del gruppo R-BPPV vs 79/547 (14,4%) del gruppo NR - BPPV (p = 0,0006).</seg>
          <seg id="69">La ricorrenza è risultata statisticamente associata alla tiroidite di Hashimoto (HT) (p &lt; 0,0001) ed alla positività anticorpale di Ab-TPO (p = 0,0117) e Ab-TG (p = 0,0025); le concentrazioni sieriche medie di TSH, f-T3 e f-T4 non sono risultate statisticamente significative.</seg>
          <seg id="70">nei pazienti affetti da ipotiroidismo in TOS è stato dimostrato un aumentato rischio di ricorrenza di BPPV, particolarmente evidente nei pazienti con HT e dosaggio anticorpale tiroideo positivo, suggerendo l’associazione tra autoimmunità e ricorrenza della vertigine.</seg>
          <seg id="71">Il lichen planus orale (OLP) è una malattia cronica infiammatoria.</seg>
          <seg id="72">Non ci sono marcatori predittivi del rischio di trasformazione di OLP nel carcinoma a cellule squamose del cavo orale (OSCC).</seg>
          <seg id="73">Sono state rilevate le differenze, statisticamente significative, nell’occorrenza di p53 e HSP90 nell’OLP e OSCC (p = 0,01; p = 0,006; rispettivamente).</seg>
          <seg id="74">La correlazione positiva tra l’occorrenza di HSP90 e p53 è stata notata in OLP (p = 0,017).</seg>
          <seg id="75">L’analisi multivariata ha evidenziato che HSP90 è un fattore prognostico indipendente correlato ad una OS più breve negli OSCC (p = 0,016).</seg>
          <seg id="76">Questo studio suggerisce che esiste una correlazione fra interazione di p53 e HSP90 e di HSP90 ed HPV ed il comportamento biologico di OLP.</seg>
          <seg id="77">L’accertamento della presenza di p53 e HSP90 in OLP e l’aumento della loro espressione in OSCC indica che queste proteine possono partecipare al processo di trasformazione di OLP.</seg>
          <seg id="78">Questo studio esplora gli effetti dello splint occlusale in 22 pazienti affetti da malattia di Ménière monolaterale e disturbi dell’articolazione temporo-mandibolare.</seg>
          <seg id="79">La soglia uditiva media nell’orecchio malato e l’impedenza acustica sono rimaste invariate e non è stato registrato nessun nistagmo clinicamente significativo. I potenziali evocati miogenici non hanno subito variazioni.</seg>
          <seg id="80">La terapia con splint occlusale è efficace nel ridurre alcuni sintomi della malattia di Ménière in comorbidità con il disordine dell’articolazione temporomandibolare, anche se il suo meccanismo fisiopatologico rimane indeterminato.</seg>
          <seg id="81">La chirurgia bariatrica   riconosciuta come il trattamento pi  efficace e duraturo per la cura dell’obesit  patologica, garantendo il mantenimento di una riduzione stabile del peso a lungo termine e il miglioramento delle comorbidit , con un impatto favorevole sulla mortalit .</seg>
          <seg id="82">Lo scopo di questo studio   valutare il tasso di complicanze e le tecniche di trattamento adottate in tutti i pazienti sottoposti a procedure di chirurgia bariatrica nel nostro centro.</seg>
          <seg id="83">Da maggio 2017 a marzo 2020, 91 pazienti affetti da obesit  patologica sono stati ricoverati presso il reparto di Chirurgia Generale Universitaria del Policlinico Riuniti di Foggia per essere sottoposti ad intervento di chirurgia bariatrica.</seg>
          <seg id="84">Le complicanze postoperatorie (8,8%) che si sono verificate sono state: 1 fistola gastrica (1,09%), 4 sanguinamenti (4,39%) - 1 sanguinamento intraluminale e 3 sanguinamenti intra-addominali, 2 infezioni dei port-site (2,19 %) e 1 emoperitoneo (1,09%).</seg>
          <seg id="85">Nel nostro centro abbiamo trattato anche 3 casi di complicanze successive ad interventi di chirurgia bariatrica eseguiti in altri centri.</seg>
          <seg id="86">Il tasso di mortalit    dello 0 %.</seg>
          <seg id="87">Il presente studio mirava a eseguire differenze ed eventuali fattori di rischio potenziali nei sintomi ansiosi e depressivi negli infermieri italiani durante la pandemia Covid-19 in base a variabili sociodemografiche selezionate.</seg>
          <seg id="88">Durante il mese di novembre 2020 è stato somministrato online un questionario “ad hoc” a tutti gli infermieri italiani.</seg>
          <seg id="89">Nella prima parte sono state raccolte le variabili socio-demografiche relative al campione di riferimento, quali: sesso, reparto di appartenenza dei partecipanti, se l’intervistato soffriva di malattie polmonari o cardiovascolari, se viveva da solo o con altri conviventi e se durante la pandemia il partecipante ha contratto o meno l’infezione da SARS-CoV-2.</seg>
          <seg id="90">Nella seconda parte del questionario, è stata somministrata la scala Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale per valutare i livelli di ansia e di depressione tra gli infermieri italiani durante la pandemia Covid-19.</seg>
          <seg id="91">Risultati. 732 infermieri hanno accettato di partecipare allo studio.</seg>
          <seg id="92">Tra i partecipanti, 479 (65.3%) riportano una sintomatologia ansiosa e 267 (6.4%) una depressiva.</seg>
          <seg id="93">In base ai sintomi ansiosi, è stata registrata una differenza significativa tra donne e uomini (p min 0.001), poiché le infermiere registrano livelli più elevati di sintomi ansiosi lievi (24.04%), moderati (23.09%) e gravi (13.39%) rispetto agli infermieri uomini (Lieve: 1.50%; Moderato: 2.46%; Grave: 0.96%).</seg>
          <seg id="94">Considerando i sintomi depressivi in base alle variabili sociodemografiche, solo gli infermieri che non presentano malattie cardiovascolari registrano frequenze più elevate nei sintomi depressivi lievi (21.58%), moderati (8.47%) e gravi (2.46%) rispetto agli infermieri che affetti da una malattia cardiovascolare (Lieve: 2.05 %; Moderato: 1.64%; Grave: 0.27%).</seg>
          <seg id="95">I potenziali fattori di rischio identificati per i sintomi ansiosi erano: sesso, sia per sintomi ansiosi lievi (p min 0.001), moderati (p=.008) e gravi (p=.003) e malattie polmonari per disturbi ansiosi gravi (p =. 014).</seg>
          <seg id="96">I potenziali fattori di rischio identificati per l’insorgenza di sintomi depressivi sono stati: sesso (p=.026), malattie polmonari (p=.021), partnership domestica (p=.035), per sintomi lievi; la presenza di malattie cardiache (p=.006) per sintomi moderati.</seg>
          <seg id="97">Conclusioni.</seg>
          <seg id="98">Urge implementare ulteriormente tutte le forme di supporto psicologico per gli infermieri nonché l’ulteriore implementazione di programmi di formazione infermieristica universitaria che mirano alla gestione sia tecnica che psicologica del futuro professionista nel fronteggiare le maxi emergenze.</seg>
          <seg id="99">La Setaria tundra è nota come un comune parassita degli ungulati selvatici nelle latitudini settentrionali.</seg>
          <seg id="100">Anche se viene considerata a bassa patogenicità, si sono osservati gravi epidemie e quindi notevoli perdite economiche per le renne (Rangifer tarandus tarandus).</seg>
          <seg id="101">La densità della popolazione e i fattori climatici sono i principali artefici dell’espansione della Setaria spp.</seg>
          <seg id="102">che ne hanno facilitato lo sviluppo e la diffusione.</seg>
          <seg id="103">Cinque esemplari di S. tundra adulti sono stati ritrovati in un capriolo maschio in Baviera, Germania.</seg>
          <seg id="104">L’identificazione morfologica è stata confermata dalla codifica dell’acido desossiribonucleico (DNA).</seg>
          <seg id="105">Le sequenze del gene della cicloossigenasi 1 hanno rilevato il 98,73–99,68 % di somiglianza con le sequenze di altri esemplari di S. tundra trovati in cervi (Cervidae) e zanzare (Culicidae).</seg>
          <seg id="106">I risultati confermano la presenza di S. tundra in una regione endemica finora sconosciuta e rappresentano un punto di avvio per delle indagini più vaste per capire la biologia e la distribuzione di questo parassita nei caprioli e in altri ospiti potenziali.</seg>
          <seg id="107">Sviluppo e validazione di un punteggio di classificazione dell’endomicroscopia laser confocale (CLE) per la laringe ed il faringe.</seg>
          <seg id="108">Tredici pazienti (154 sequenze video, 9240 immagini) con SCC laringeo o faringeo sono stati inclusi in questo studio prospettico tra ottobre 2020 e febbraio 2021.</seg>
          <seg id="109">Ogni sequenza CLE è stata correlata con il gold standard, ovvero l’esame istopatologico fissato con ematossilina ed eosina (H&amp;E).</seg>
          <seg id="110">Sulla base di un set di dati di 94 sequenze video (5640 immagini), è stato sviluppato un sistema di punteggio.</seg>
          <seg id="111">Nelle restanti 60 sequenze (3600 immagini), il punteggio è stato convalidato da quattro esperti di CLE e quattro chirurghi della testa e del collo che non avevano familiarità con la CLE.</seg>
          <seg id="112">L’omogeneità dei tessuti, le dimensioni delle cellule, i bordi e i cluster, i loop capillari e il rapporto nucleo/citoplasma sono stati definiti come criteri di punteggio.</seg>
          <seg id="113">Utilizzando questo punteggio, gli esperti di CLE hanno ottenuto un’accuratezza, una sensibilità e una specificità del 90,8%, 95,1% e 86,4%, rispettivamente, e i non esperti di CLE dell’86,2%, 86,4% e 86,1%.</seg>
          <seg id="114">L’accordo tra osservatori Fleiss’kappa era rispettivamente di 0,8 e 0,6.</seg>
          <seg id="115">CLE può essere valutato in modo affidabile sulla base di caratteristiche di imaging definite e riproducibili, che dimostrano un alto valore diagnostico.</seg>
          <seg id="116">CLE può essere facilmente integrato nell’impostazione intraoperatoria e generare immagini microscopiche in tempo reale e in vivo per delimitare i cambiamenti maligni.</seg>
          <seg id="117">Pertanto nel corso dell’intervento per riparare la fistola   stato usato un patch dal pericardio destro con tessuto adiposo circostante di dimensioni adeguate che poi   stato ricoperto con un tessuto biologico (Neoveil) di rinforzo.</seg>
          <seg id="118">La TAC con mezzo di contrasto evidenziava emoperitoneo con un aneurisma splenico di 20 mm, localizzato in sede perilare.</seg>
          <seg id="119">Dopo aver aperto il legamento gastro- colico e ottenuto il controllo vascolare dell’arteria splenica, l’aneurisma è stato resecato.</seg>
          <seg id="120">Non sono state identificate modifiche macroscopiche alla milza.</seg>
          <seg id="121">Tale reperto è stato confermato anche dalla somministrazione endovenosa di verde indocianina.</seg>
          <seg id="122">I noduli tiroidei a citologia indeterminata rappresentano il 20% di tutti i noduli tiroidei.</seg>
          <seg id="123">L’infiammazione gioca un ruolo importante nel cancro.</seg>
          <seg id="124">LMR, NLR e PLR sono fattori prognostici indipendenti in numerosi tumori; tuttavia, nessuno studio ha mostrato il loro ruolo nei noduli a citologia indeterminata.</seg>
          <seg id="125">Questo studio si propone di valutare il ruolo di LMR, NLR e PLR come predittori di malignità in pazienti con noduli a citologia indeterminata.</seg>
          <seg id="126">Abbiamo analizzato retrospettivamente i dati di 298 pazienti con nodulo tiroideo indeterminato.</seg>
          <seg id="127">Abbiamo analizzato i dati anatomopatologici ed ematologici, dividendo la popolazione in due gruppi.</seg>
          <seg id="128">I valori cut-off di LMR, NLR e PLR sono stati determinati con la curva ROC e i dati sono stati esaminati utilizzando il t-test per campioni indipendenti, il test delle proporzioni, il Fisher exact test e la regressione univariata e multivariata.</seg>
          <seg id="129">Un valore LMR basale ≥ 4,09 è indicativo di benignità.</seg>
          <seg id="130">La probabilità di neoplasia nei pazienti con LMR &lt; 4,09 è 26 volte superiore rispetto ai pazienti con valore LMR ≥ 4,09.</seg>
          <seg id="131">Lo scoppio della pandemia Covid-19 ha gravemente colpito la nostra società.</seg>
          <seg id="132">I governi si trovano in situazioni difficili adottando misure di mitigazione rigorose e severe al fine di contenere la diffusione della pandemia.</seg>
          <seg id="133">Queste decisioni hanno influenzato in modo significativo il comportamento delle persone cambiando le loro abitudini e routine.</seg>
          <seg id="134">Questo studio offre un’analisi statistica dell’incidenza dei traumi maxillo-facciali nell’area meridionale della Toscana, durante il blocco della pandemia.</seg>
          <seg id="135">Dal settimo giorno di vita, a sei vitelli è stato somministrato (drenching) latte per il 6 % del loro peso corporeo tre volte ad intervalli di 12 ore.</seg>
          <seg id="136">Prima, durante e dopo la somministrazione, il reticolo e l’abomaso sono stati esaminati ecograficamente.</seg>
          <seg id="137">Nel rumine, si è prodotta un’acidosi dopo il drenching con una diminuzione significativa del pH mediano da 7,0 (6,0 – 7,0) a 4,5 (3,0 – 5,0) e un aumento della concentrazione mediana di D-lattato di un fattore 93 da 0,39 (0,14 – 1,33) a 36,3 (17,9 – 53,3) mmol/l.</seg>
          <seg id="138">Gli esami dimostrano che il latte entra nel reticolo e nell’abomaso simultaneamente durante la somministrazione nei vitelli e che la somministrazione per tre volte in un intervallo di 12 ore porta a un’acidosi acuta del rumine, che (per il momento) non è accompagnata da alcun cambiamento significativo del pH del sangue e della deviazione di base.</seg>
          <seg id="139">L’anaplasmosi granulocitica equina (EGA) e la piroplasmosi equina (EP) sono provocate da agenti patogeni trasmessi dalle zecche - il batterio intracellulare Anaplasma phagocytophilum e i protozoi intracellulari Babesia caballi e Theileria equi.</seg>
          <seg id="140">Questi agenti patogeni attaccano le cellule nel flusso sanguigno e causano sintomi clinici simili e cambiamenti nei valori di laboratorio.</seg>
          <seg id="141">Anche se i principi di trattamento sono naturalmente diversi, esistono somiglianze nella profilassi a causa della via di trasmissione.</seg>
          <seg id="142">Gli agenti patogeni trasmessi dalle zecche potrebbero assumere un ruolo maggiore nella medicina equina nel futuro a causa di vari fattori, come la tendenza alla diffusione delle specie di zecche rilevanti, ma anche la crescente attività di importazione e di viaggio di e con animali domestici (sia nel contesto di eventi sportivi che come attività di svago).</seg>
          <seg id="143">Mentre l’EGA è endemica in Europa centrale, l’EP è una malattia sporadica in Svizzera, Austria e Germania.</seg>
          <seg id="144">Tuttavia, l’EP deve essere considerata come sotto diagnosticata, poiché anche i cavalli persistentemente infettati da T. equi sono ripetutamente identificati in Europa centrale.</seg>
          <seg id="145">Queste malattie dovrebbero essere considerate nel caso di cavalli con febbre e corrispondenti cambiamenti di laboratorio.</seg>
          <seg id="146">I test diagnostici disponibili sono il rilevamento diretto del patogeno tramite striscio di sangue o PCR, e il rilevamento indiretto degli anticorpi, che è considerato altamente sensibile e (come ELISA competitivo) anche molto specifico.</seg>
          <seg id="147">Le infezioni acute possono essere rilevate con la PCR, per le infezioni croniche la sierologia è spesso più adatta.</seg>
          <seg id="148">La scomparsa del patogeno dopo il trattamento può essere dimostrata con titoli anticorpali decrescenti in combinazione con ripetuti esami PCR.</seg>
          <seg id="149">Anche i cavalli clinicamente sani infettati da T. equi devono essere identificati mediante la rilevazione degli anticorpi e devono essere adottate delle misure appropriate per prevenire la trasmissione.</seg>
          <seg id="150">La profilassi delle punture di zecca è naturalmente difficile nei cavalli a causa dell’alta esposizione, e una protezione dalle zecche di lunga durata non può essere garantita.</seg>
          <seg id="151">Il controllo dell’attività delle zecche e le misure rigorose per prevenire la diffusione di agenti patogeni all’interno della popolazione di zecche sono quindi di grande importanza.</seg>
          <seg id="152">Presentiamo il caso clinico di una paziente con un mesotelioma peritoneale cistico maligno sviluppatosi nello spessore della muscolatura della parete addominale.</seg>
          <seg id="153">La diagnosi ha seguito diverse tappe: classificazione del tumore come mesotelioma, differenziazione dall’iperplasia mesoteliale reattiva, identificazione della malignità del tumore e diagnosi differenziale con altri tipi di tumori peritoneali maligni.</seg>
          <seg id="154">La recidiva del tumore a circa un anno dall’intervento chirurgico, e a 6 mesi dalla fine del trattamento chemioterapico conferma la sua malignità.</seg>
          <seg id="155">La toxoplasmosi è una zoonosi mondiale causata dal parassita intracellulare obbligato Toxoplasma gondii (T. gondii).</seg>
          <seg id="156">Tutte le specie a sangue caldo, compreso l’uomo, fungono da ospiti intermedi.</seg>
          <seg id="157">Gli ospiti finali sono esclusivamente i gatti.</seg>
          <seg id="158">Il pollame da reddito può essere infettato da mangime contaminato da oocisti, direttamente da oocisti dal terreno e beccando per esempio dei roditori infetti.</seg>
          <seg id="159">Questa breve recensione della letteratura cerca di valutare l’attuale situazione dell’infezione nel pollame da reddito e di valutare la potenziale rilevanza della toxoplasmosi nel pollame da reddito per gli esseri umani come consumatori di carne di pollame e prodotti a base di carne di pollame.</seg>
          <seg id="160">I meningiomi come entità anatomo-patologiche furono descritti per la prima volta nel XVI secolo, ma fu Harvey Cusching che nel 1922 propose di identificarli con il termine di “meningioma”.</seg>
          <seg id="161">Sono i tumori intracranici più comuni, si manifestano tra la mezza e la tarda età e prediligono il sesso femminile.</seg>
          <seg id="162">La sintomatologia è funzione della loro posizione rispetto alle regioni dell’encefalo.</seg>
          <seg id="163">Si tratta per lo più di neoplasie benigne, ma esistono forme atipiche ed anche maligne.</seg>
          <seg id="164">Il meningioma “a placca” si riferisce a un aspetto macroscopico specifico del meningioma, per coinvolgimento durale diffuso e solitamente con estensione extracranica.</seg>
          <seg id="165">Lo sviluppo della pancreatite acuta   multifattoriale e prevede predisposizione e danni rilevanti.</seg>
          <seg id="166">La pancreatite acuta virale   stata descritta in concomitanza di altre infezioni virali.</seg>
          <seg id="167">Tuttavia il coinvolgimento del pancreas nell’infezione da SARS-CoV-2   ancora poco definita.</seg>
          <seg id="168">Il presente studio comparativo riporta i pazienti con pancreatite acuta durante la pandemia di COVID-19 e durante lo scorso anno coprendo lo stesso periodo, per valutare il legame tra COVID-19 e pancreatite biliare acuta.</seg>
          <seg id="169">Lo studio, osservazionale e retrospettivo,   stato condotto in pazienti con pancreatite biliare acuta rispettivamente dal 13.03.19 al 13.09.19 e dal 13.03.20 al 13.09.20, includendo 181 pazienti (105 pazienti nel 2019; 76 pazienti nel 2020 (durante la pandemia di COVID-19). RISULTATI: I 181 pazienti sono stati suddivisi rispettivamente come Gruppo A (periodo normale) e Gruppo B (periodo pandemico).</seg>
          <seg id="170">I gruppi sono risultati comparabili in quanto non c’era alcuna differenza significativa tra et  media, sesso, comorbidit , colecistectomia e recidiva.</seg>
          <seg id="171">La comprensione del processo della malattia e delle manifestazioni cliniche di COVID-19   ancora in via di sviluppo.</seg>
          <seg id="172">L’Enterobius Vermicularis (EV) è il più frequente ossiuro identificato occasionalmente all’analisi istologica dell’appendice eseguita a seguito di appendicectomia per appendicite acuta diagnosticata clinicamente.</seg>
          <seg id="173">La diagnosi precoce degli insuccessi dell’impianto cocleare (CIF) è una parte fondamentale del follow-up post-impianto.</seg>
          <seg id="174">La diagnosi è impegnativa e richiede tempo.</seg>
          <seg id="175">Il nostro studio mira a descrivere le diagnosi di CIF con focus sui fallimenti lievi (SF), i sintomi correlati, il tempo dall’insorgenza dei sintomi alla sostituzione dell’impianto e le differenze tra SF e fallimenti severi (HF).</seg>
          <seg id="176">Revisione retrospettiva delle cartelle cliniche di un centro medico pediatrico di riferimento, relative a tutti i pazienti che hanno avuto una CIF nel periodo 2000-2020.</seg>
          <seg id="177">Su 1004 interventi chirurgici di IC, sono stati inclusi 72 (7,2%) casi di CIF, di cui 60 CIF nei bambini (età media 3,1 anni).</seg>
          <seg id="178">Venticinque casi sono classificabili come HF, 26 SF e 21 iatrogeni.</seg>
          <seg id="179">I pazienti con SF avevano maggiori probabilità di presentare cefalea, vertigini o acufeni rispetto a quelli con HF.</seg>
          <seg id="180">La stimolazione facciale e le disconnessioni erano più comuni negli impianti con Advanced Bionics, vertigini e acufeni con Cochlear, e scarsa progressione con Med-El.</seg>
          <seg id="181">Il tempo medio dai sintomi all’intervento di sostituzione dell’impianto è stato più lungo nei casi con SF rispetto all’HF.</seg>
          <seg id="182">SF pone una sfida diagnostica.</seg>
          <seg id="183">Sintomi come mal di testa, vertigini e tinnito sono abbastanza comuni.</seg>
          <seg id="184">la diagnosi di fallimento dovrebbe spesso basarsi sulle valutazioni delle équipe implantari e riabilitative.</seg>
          <seg id="185">Studio retrospettivo della nostra esperienza con interventi endovascolari e ibridi per il trattamento degli aneurismi dell’arteria succlavia (SAA).</seg>
          <seg id="186">Lo studio comprende 17 pazienti con SAA trattati presso il nostro centro tra luglio 2011 e ottobre 2018.</seg>
          <seg id="187">I dati clinici e di follow-up sono stati estratti dalle cartelle cliniche e rivisti retrospettivamente.</seg>
          <seg id="188">Abitualmente adottiamo tecniche endovascolari e stent, o bypass ascelloascellare per trattare SSA se si richiede il ripristino del flusso sanguigno dell’arteria vertebrale.</seg>
          <seg id="189">I pazienti trattati sono stati seguiti a 3, 6 e 12 mesi dopo l’operazione e successivamente ogni anno.</seg>
          <seg id="190">RISULTATI: il follow-up   stato in media di 30,5 mesi.</seg>
          <seg id="191">In 6 pazienti, gli SAA coinvolgevano l’arteria vertebrale omolaterale, ed in uno di essi   stata eseguita la semplice embolizzazione con spirale; in 4 pazienti si   proceduto con embolizzazione con spirale e stent endovascolare rivestito; in un paziente si   adottato un trattamento ibrido.</seg>
          <seg id="192">In 11 pazienti, gli SAA non coinvolgevano l’arteria vertebrale omolaterale.</seg>
          <seg id="193">Il trattamento ibrido   stato eseguito per 1 paziente; un impianto di stent aortico toracico con embolizzazione a spirale in 1 paziente; il posizionamento di stent rivestito nell’arteria succlavia per 9 pazienti.</seg>
          <seg id="194">Tra i 9 pazienti che erano sintomatici alla presentazione, 8 hanno avuto sollievo dai sintomi.</seg>
          <seg id="195">Una filtrazione emorragica   stata osservata in 1 paziente, ma si   interrotta spontaneamente.</seg>
          <seg id="196">L’occlusione dello stent si   verificata nel 33% (3/9), ma tutti sono rimasti asintomatici e non sono stati necessari ulteriori interventi.</seg>
          <seg id="197">Scopo dello studio era quelo di determinare se la variazione della pressione intraaddominale causata dal pneumoperitoneo creato durante la colecistectomia laparoscopica (LC) ha effetti su dolore addominale e alla spalla, su nausea, vomito, movimenti intestinali, tempo del primo flatus e, della defecazione e sui parametri biochimici.</seg>
          <seg id="198">Nello studio sono stati inclusi settanta pazienti a cui è stata diagnosticata la colelitiasi e che sarebbero stati sottoposti a LC, di età compresa tra 18 e 75 anni, con le classificazioni I-III della Society of Anesthesia Physical Status (ASA).</seg>
          <seg id="199">I pazienti sono stati divisi in due gruppi: per intervento a bassa pressione (8-10 mm/hg) e intervento ad alta pressione (14-16 mm/hg).</seg>
          <seg id="200">L’emergenza causata dalla pandemia da COVID-19 ha costretto il sistema sanitario italiano ad attuare un’immediata riorganizzazione per supportare la cura di decine di migliaia di pazienti e mantenere la qualità delle cure di pazienti con altre patologie, quali le malattie oncologiche.</seg>
          <seg id="201">L’obiettivo principale di questo studio è stato quello di valutare l’impatto delle restrizioni da COVID-19 sulla degenza e sulla riabilitazione post-operatoria di pazienti oncologici testa-collo e determinare se l’introduzione di nuove tecnologie, come la videocomunicazione, possa essere utile per mitigare il distanziamento sociale dai familiari stretti.</seg>
          <seg id="202">Durante il periodo di lockdown causato dalla pandemia da COVID-19, 51 pazienti consecutivi sono stati sottoposti a intervento chirurgico per tumori maligni testa-collo.</seg>
          <seg id="203">I dati raccolti (dolore post-operatorio, complicanze post-operatorie, durata della degenza) sono stati confrontati con quelli di 51 pazienti consecutivi trattati per tumori maligni testa-collo nel periodo immediatamente precedente il lockdown.</seg>
          <seg id="204">La durata media della degenza è stata più lunga nei pazienti operati nel periodo del COVID-19, in particolare nei pazienti sottoposti a un protocollo riabilitativo più impegnativo.</seg>
          <seg id="205">Nonostante ciò, il nostro studio non ha dimostrato una differenza significativa negli aspetti psicologici durante il ricovero.</seg>
          <seg id="206">Le maggiori difficoltà che si sono incontrate nel periodo del COVID-19 sono state superate da un maggiore impegno da parte di tutto il personale sanitario, consentendo di mantenere la qualità di vita dei pazienti a un livello simile a quello precedente la pandemia.</seg>
          <seg id="207">In futuro, saranno necessarie soluzioni tecnologiche per avvicinare il paziente ai familiari.</seg>
          <seg id="208">E’ stata sintetizzata la serie di oligomeri Boc-(L-Phe-D-Oxd)&lt;sub&gt;n&lt;/sub&gt; -OBn (Boc=ter-butossi carbonile; Oxd=4-metil-5-carbossiossazolidin-2-one; Bn=benzile) contenenti l′unità L-Phe-D-Oxd ripetuta 2-5 volte.</seg>
          <seg id="209">L′oligomero più corto, Boc-(L-Phe-D-Oxd)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; -OBn, si aggrega in fase solida e forma un materiale fibroso avente una struttura a foglietto β antiparallelo, in cui le unità oligopeptidiche sono legate fra loro da un solo legame idrogeno.</seg>
          <seg id="210">Gli oligomeri superiori mostrano invece un disordine strutturale ed incominciano ad organizzarsi a livello del pentamero.</seg>
          <seg id="211">Analisi mediante microscopia ottica ed elettronica indicano che il solo dimero ha carattere cristallino.</seg>
          <seg id="212">Il Calicivirus felino (FCV) è uno degli agenti patogeni virali più comuni nei gatti domestici in tutto il mondo.</seg>
          <seg id="213">La prima segnalazione di FCV risale al 1957, quando il FCV fu isolato dal tratto gastrointestinale di gatti in Nuova Zelanda.</seg>
          <seg id="214">Rapporti successivi hanno riconosciuto il FCV come la causa delle malattie respiratorie nei gatti, e attualmente, gli studi veterinari per piccoli animali in tutto il mondo sono confrontati quotidianamente con gatti che soffrono di un sospetto FCV.</seg>
          <seg id="215">La natura altamente mutagena del FCV e la sua elevata plasticità genetica permettono al virus di sopravvivere con successo nella popolazione felina e rappresentano una sfida particolare per quanto riguarda la diagnosi, il trattamento e la prevenzione della malattia provocata da FCV.</seg>
          <seg id="216">La malattia del tratto respiratorio superiore è considerata un segno clinico comune di infezione da FCV.</seg>
          <seg id="217">Uno studio svizzero ha rilevato che ulcerazioni orali, salivazione e stomatite gengivale erano più comunemente associate all'infezione da FCV rispetto alle malattie del tratto respiratorio superiore, e meno della metà dei gatti sospettati di avere un'infezione da FCV erano positivi al FCV.</seg>
          <seg id="218">Inoltre, uno studio sugli isolati di FCV, provenienti dalla Svizzera, ha trovato alcune evidenze che il profilo genetico dei gatti può influenzare la loro suscettibilità all'infezione da FCV.</seg>
          <seg id="219">Questo articolo fornisce una sintesi completa della letteratura riguardante il FCV e integra i risultati delle recenti ricerche sulle caratteristiche genetiche del FCV, sull'immunità cellulare e umorale indotta dalla vaccinazione o dall'infezione da FCV, sulla diagnosi del FCV, sulla prevenzione/vaccinazione del FCV, sui fattori di rischio di infezione da FCV e sulle misure igieniche necessarie delle aree contaminate da FCV.</seg>
          <seg id="220">Dopo ogni sezione, vengono riassunti i punti chiave e vengono descritte le informazioni rilevanti per assistere i veterinari nella diagnosi, nel trattamento e nella prevenzione della FCV.</seg>
          <seg id="221">La fistola cocleare (FC) è una rara entità, solitamente associata a colesteatoma dell’orecchio medio.</seg>
          <seg id="222">Vi è generale accordo in letteratura sul fatto che la rimozione della matrice colesteatomatosa da una FC determini elevato rischio di ipoacusia neurosensoriale o anacusia.</seg>
          <seg id="223">Serie retrospettiva di casi clinici di fistola cocleare confermati da TC e da riscontro intraoperatorio o endoscopico.</seg>
          <seg id="224">Di 5 casi identificati, 4 si associavano a colesteatoma.</seg>
          <seg id="225">Di questi, 2 pazienti anacusici venivano sottoposti a petrosectomia subtotale, mentre 2 pazienti udenti venivano sottoposti a intervento di radicale con preservazione della matrice sul promontorio.</seg>
          <seg id="226">Il solo caso di FC associato a otite cronica non-colesteatomatosa (OMC) e con buon udito residuo veniva trattato conservativamente.</seg>
          <seg id="227">Per quei rari casi di FC associati a OMC con buon udito residuo dovrebbe essere considerato un trattamento conservativo.</seg>
          <seg id="228">In caso di via ossea preoperatoria protesizzabile, è fortemente indicata la preservazione della matrice di colesteatoma mediante mastoidectomia radicale o radicale modificata.</seg>
          <seg id="229">In presenza di colesteatoma con perdita uditiva profonda pre-operatoria, una petrosectomia subtotale dovrebbe essere il trattamento di scelta.</seg>
          <seg id="230">Il nitroacetato di etile (1) reagisce con olefine elettron-povere, in presenza di base, per dare sia l′addotto di Michael (3) che, con eliminazione di acqua, il cicloaddotto isossazolinico (4).</seg>
          <seg id="231">Il rapporto tra i prodotti 3 e 4 cambia nel corso del processo e dipende dalle condizioni di reazione.</seg>
          <seg id="232">I profili cinetici delle due reazioni mostrano che la cicloaddizione-condensazione è caratterizzata da un tempo di induzione il cui valore diminuisce notevolmente all′aggiunta nel sistema catalitico di sali di rame(II): la diminuzione del tempo di induzione provoca un incremento della quantità di cicloaddotto 4 che spesso è l′unico prodotto.</seg>
          <seg id="233">Questo lavoro rappresenta il primo esempio di trasformazione selettiva di nitrocomposti primari nei prodotti 3 o 4 attraverso la modulazione del sistema catalitico.</seg>
          <seg id="234">La prevalenza di Macrococcus spp.</seg>
          <seg id="235">meticillino-resistente nei vitelli e nei suini destinati al macello e nella carne bovina e suina in vendita al dettaglio è stata determinata utilizzando campioni prelevati nel 2019 nel quadro del monitoraggio nazionale dello Staphylococcus aureus meticillino-resistente negli animali da reddito in Svizzera.</seg>
          <seg id="236">Gli isolati sono stati sottoposti a test di suscettibilità antimicrobica per 19 antibiotici ed a diverse tecniche molecolari (ad es. PCR, microarray, WGS) per l’identificazione dei geni di resistenza, degli elementi contenenti i geni di resistenza alla meticillina mec e della variante di sequence type (ST).</seg>
          <seg id="237">I Macrococcus spp. meticillino-resistenti (M. caseolyticus (n=38), M. bohemicus (n=4) e Macrococcus spp. (n=2)) sono stati isolati in 40 dei 299 tamponi nasali dei vitelli con una prevalenza del 13,38 % (95 % CI, 9,98 % – 17,70 %), e in quattro dei 303 tamponi nasali dei maiali [1,32 % (95 % CI, 0,36 % – 3,35 %)].</seg>
          <seg id="238">Uno dei 311 campioni di carne suina svizzera conteneva un Macrococcus sp. [0,32 % (95 % CI, 0,01 % – 1,78 %)], e quattro dei 309 campioni di carne bovina (260 nazionali e 49 importati) contenevano M. caseolyticus [1,29 % (95 % CI, 0,35 % – 3,28 %)].</seg>
          <seg id="239">I ceppi di M. caseolyticus si sono rivelati appartenere a diversi sequence types, il più comune dei quali è risultato essere ST21 sia nei maiali che nei vitelli.</seg>
          <seg id="240">Il gene mecD è stato riscontrato a livello cromosomico in 42 ceppi sull’isola di resistenza Macrococcus mecD (McRImecD) e in tre ceppi sull’elemento mobile Staphylococcal cassette chromosome mec (SCCmecD), mentre mecB è stato trovato sui plasmidi in quattro ceppi.</seg>
          <seg id="241">Oltre alla resistenza ai β-lattamici, i ceppi hanno mostrato anche resistenza alla tetraciclina (n=17; tet(L), tet(K), tet(M)), streptomicina (n=13; str, ant(6)-Ia, mutazione rpsL [K56R nella proteina ribosomiale S12]), kanamicina (n=10; aac(6’)-Ie – aph(2’’)-Ia, aph(2’)-Ib, aph(2’)-Ic, ant(4’)-Ia), clindamicina (n=9; erm(B), erm(45)), eritromicina (n=9; erm(B), msr(G), erm(45)), acido fusidico (n=9; fusC) e gentamicina (n=1; aac(6’)-Ie – aph(2’’)-Ia).</seg>
          <seg id="242">Questo studio rappresenta il primo studio di prevalenza nazionale di Macrococcus spp.</seg>
          <seg id="243">resistente alla meticillina in suini, vitelli, carne di maiale e di manzo in Svizzera e ha rivelato un serbatoio di ceppi geneticamente diversi che portano diversi tratti di resistenza.</seg>
          <seg id="244">Lo scopo di questo studio era di valutare la sicurezza e l’efficacia della dissezione sottomucosa endoscopica (ESD) di polipi del colon di dimensioni maggiori di 20 mm.</seg>
          <seg id="245">Tra marzo 2017 e luglio 2019, un team di gastro-entero endoscopisti ha resecato 24 grandi polipi colorettali di 20-35 mm di diametro utilizzando la tecnica ESD.</seg>
          <seg id="246">Dopo l’iniezione di una miscela di idrossipropilmetilcellulosa con epinefrina diluita e blu di metilene nello strato sottomucoso,   stata eseguita un’incisione circonferenziale utilizzando un elettrobisturi.</seg>
          <seg id="247">L’et  media dei pazienti era di 60 anni; 16 pazienti erano uomini e 4 pazienti erano donne.</seg>
          <seg id="248">La dimensione media del polipo rimosso dall’ESD colorettale era di 35,3 mm (intervallo 20,0-70,1 mm) e tutti i 24 polipi erano pi  grandi di 2 cm (100%).</seg>
          <seg id="249">Non ci sono stati casi di sanguinamento ritardato dopo ESD colorettale n  complicazioni post-chirurgiche.</seg>
          <seg id="250">In cnclusione Questo studio dimostra l’efficacia e la sicurezza dell’esecuzione di ESD di grandi polipi.</seg>
          <seg id="251">Questo   importante perch  non c’  una grande quantit  di letteratura su questo argomento in questa specifica popolazione.</seg>
          <seg id="252">Questo studio ha cercato di identificare la dimensione ottimale della sfenoidotomia, misurata intraoperatoriamente, per prevenire la stenosi postoperatoria.</seg>
          <seg id="253">Trentadue pazienti affetti da rinosinusite cronica non associata a poliposi nasale (CRSsNP) sono stati sottoposti a sfenoidotomia (52 sfenoidotomie).</seg>
          <seg id="254">La dimensione della sfenoidotomia è stata valutata utilizzando un righello intraoperatoriamente, al primo, terzo e sesto mese dopo l’intervento.</seg>
          <seg id="255">Sono state registrate le dimensioni degli osti, i risultati del questionario SNOT-22, gli eventi di recidiva di sinusite e la necessità di un intervento chirurgico di revisione.</seg>
          <seg id="256">Tutte le sfenoidotomie (n = 52) hanno mostrato una significativa riduzione delle dimensioni (media 43,4 ± 6,8%) al primo mese dopo l’intervento, con una tendenza ad allargarsi a tre mesi e stabilizzarsi a sei mesi.</seg>
          <seg id="257">Gli osti più grandi di 61,3 mm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; non hanno mostrato stenosi dopo l’intervento.</seg>
          <seg id="258">La stenosi è stata osservata in 11 sfenoidotomie (21,2%); tuttavia, solo cinque erano associati a sintomi ostruttivi (9,6%), mentre in tre casi è stato necessario un intervento di revisione dello sfenoide (5,8%).</seg>
          <seg id="259">La dimensione della sfenoidotomia si è ridotta significativamente durante il primo mese postoperatorio, e successivamente si è stabilizzata.</seg>
          <seg id="260">Una dimensione della sfenoidotomia al basale di 61,3 mm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; sembra prevenire la stenosi dell’ostio.</seg>
          <seg id="261">La metà delle stenosi degli osti sfenoidali sembrerebbe associarsi a sintomi disventilativi.</seg>
        </p>
      </ref>
    </doc>
  </collection>
  <collection id="biomedical">
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc29">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Equine granulocytic anaplasmosis (EGA) and equine piroplasmosis (EP) are triggered by tick-borne pathogens - the intracellular bacterium Anaplasma phagocytophilum and the intracellular protozoa Babesia caballi and Theileria equi.</seg>
          <seg id="2">These pathogens attack cells in the blood stream and cause similar clinical symptoms and changes in laboratory values.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Although the treatment principles are naturally different, similarities in prophylaxis exists due to the transmission route.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Tick transmitted pathogens can play a greater role in equine medicine in the future due to various factors, such as the tendency of relevant tick species to spread, but also the increasing import and travel activities of and with pets (both in the context of sporting events and as a leisure activity).</seg>
          <seg id="5">While EGA is endemic in Central Europe, EP is a sporadic disease in Switzerland, Austria and Germany.</seg>
          <seg id="6">However, EP must be viewed as underdiagnosed, as horses persistently infected with T. equi are also repeatedly detected in Central Europe.</seg>
          <seg id="7">These diseases should be considered in horses with a fever and corresponding laboratory changes.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Available diagnostic tests are direct pathogen detection by blood smear or PCR, and, indirect antibody detection, which is considered to be highly sensitive and (as a competitive ELISA) also very specific.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Acute infections can be detected with PCR, serology is more suitable for chronic infections.</seg>
          <seg id="10">A pathogen-free condition after treatment can be demonstrated with decreasing antibody titers in combination with repeated PCR tests.</seg>
          <seg id="11">In addition, clinically healthy horses infected with T. equi should be identified by antibody detection and appropriate preventative transmission measures must be initiated.</seg>
          <seg id="12">The prophylaxis of tick bites in horses is difficult due to the high exposure, and long-term tick bite prevention can hardly be guaranteed.</seg>
          <seg id="13">Monitoring of tick activity and strict measures to prevent the spread of the pathogen within the tick population are therefore of great importance.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc17">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Ethyl nitroacetate (1) reacts with electron-poor olefins in the presence of a base to give either the Michael adducts 3 or the isoxazoline cycloadducts 4, resulting from water elimination.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The proportions of the two products depend on the reaction conditions and change in the course of the process.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Kinetic profiles for the two reactions show that the cycloaddition-condensations require long induction times that dramatically decrease upon addition of a copper salt to the catalytic system: the drops in the induction time cause increases in the proportion of cycloadducts 4, which are often the sole reaction products.</seg>
          <seg id="4">This is the first report on the selective formation of products 3 and 4 from primary nitro compounds through modulation of the catalytic system.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc13">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Stenosed sphenoid sinus ostia are among the most common findings in revision endoscopic sinus surgery.</seg>
          <seg id="2">This study sought to identify the optimal intraoperative sphenoidotomy size for prevention of postoperative stenosis.</seg>
          <seg id="3">32 patients affected by chronic rhinosinusitis not associated with nasal polyps (CRSsNP) underwent 52 sphenoidotomies.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Sphenoidotomy size was assessed using a ruler intraoperatively and at the first, third and sixth months postoperatively.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Ostia sizes, SNOT-22 questionnaire findings, episodes of recurrent sinusitis and need for revision surgery were recorded.</seg>
          <seg id="6">All sphenoidotomies exhibited a significant size reduction (mean 43.4 ± 6.8%) at the first month postoperatively, with a tendency to enlarge at 3 months and stabilise at 6 months.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Ostia larger than 61.3 mm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; did not exhibit stenoses postoperatively.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Stenosis was observed in 11 sphenoidotomies (21.2%); however, only five presented with recurrent symptoms (9.6%), while three required revision sphenoid surgery (5.8%).</seg>
          <seg id="9">Sphenoidotomy size significantly reduced during the first postoperative month and then stabilised.</seg>
          <seg id="10">A baseline sphenoidotomy size of 61.3 mm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; at the time of the operation seemed sufficient to prevent ostium stenosis.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Half of stenosed ostia presented with recurrent symptoms.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc44">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">A series of oligomers of the type Boc-(L-Phe-D-Oxd)(n)-OBn (Boc = tert-butoxycarbonyl; Oxd = 4-methyl-5-carboxy oxazolidin-2-one; Bn = benzyl) were prepared for n = 2-5.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The shortest oligomer, Boc-(L-Phe-D-Oxd)(2)-OBn, aggregates and forms a fiber-like material with an anti-parallel beta-sheet structure in which the oligopeptide units are connected to each other by only one intermolecular hydrogen bond. The longer oligomers exhibit structural heterogeneity.</seg>
          <seg id="3">They start to organize into secondary structures by the formation of intramolecular hydrogen bonds at the pentamer level.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Microscopy and diffraction of the oligomers indicated a crystalline character for only the shorter ones.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc20">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">This study reported a rare case of mediastinal abscess scrofula.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The patient was found to have a large left main bronchial orificium fistula (approximately 1.5x1.5cm in size) after clearing a mediastinal lymph node abscess via the right thoracotomy approach.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The adjacent tissue was empty and could not be directly repaired.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Therefore, the research team cut out an appropriately sized right pericardial fat pad patch during the operation for repairing and then covered it with a biological patch (Neoveil) for reinforcement.</seg>
          <seg id="5">The mediastinal pleura was treated by embedding and the postoperative recovery was good. KEY WORDS: Abscess, Fistula, Pericardial fat patch, Tuberculous bronchial lymphatic, Tuberculosis bacillus, Type mediastinal lymphatic tuberculosis.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc27">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">We aimed to determine whether intraabdominal pressure change caused by pneumoperitoneum created during laparoscopic cholecystectomy (LC) has effects on abdominal and shoulder pain, nausea, vomiting, bowel movements, time of first flatus and defecation, and biochemical parameters.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Seventy patients that were diagnosed with cholelithiasis and would undergo LC, between the ages of 18-75, with the Society of Anesthesia Physical Status (ASA) I-III classifications were included in the study.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Patients were divided into two groups as whose intervention was defined as low pressure (8-10 mm/hg) and whose intervention was defined as high pressure (14-16 mm/hg).</seg>
          <seg id="4">Differences in the prognoses of patients in both groups were observed for statistical significance. Shoulder pain- visual analogue scale (VAS) values in 6th and 24th hours were lower in Group 1(p&lt;0.005). There was no significant difference in abdominal pain-VAS values(p≥0.05). Mean intraoperative end-tidal carbon dioxide (ETCO2) values were higher in Group 2 (p&lt;0.005). Differences in nausea and vomiting were not significant(p≥0.05). There was no significant difference in the first flatus times(p≥0.05). Bowel movements resumed earlier in Group 1(p&lt;0.005). Changes were not significant for biochemical blood parameters in the preoperative and postoperative periods( p≥0.05). The use of low-pressure and high pressure carbon-dioxide (CO2)-pneumoperitoneum created during LC does not cause a significant difference in terms of clinical and laboratory results. Therefore, the surgical team should prefer an easy-to-apply pressure level which they are used to and in which they have low complication rates. Cholecystectomy, Pneumoperitoneum, Low-pressure CO2.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc16">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">This retrospective study aimed to verify the outcomes of stabilising occlusal splint therapy prescribed to 22 patients with unilateral definite Ménière's disease and comorbid temporomandibular joint disorder.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The results of a battery of audiometric and vestibular tests were recorded before and after 6 months of treatment, as well as the scores of disease-specific questionnaires.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The average hearing threshold in the affected ear and the acoustic immittance were unchanged. No spontaneous and positional nystagmus were recorded.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Caloric hypo-responsiveness and vestibular myogenic evoked responses did not vary.</seg>
          <seg id="5">No changes of stabilometric body sway parameters in eyes opened condition and with optokinetic stimulation delivered to the unaffected labyrinth were observed.</seg>
          <seg id="6">A significant reduction was recorded in eyes closed condition and with the optokinetic stimulation toward the affected ear.</seg>
          <seg id="7">The Tinnitus Handicap Inventory, the Situational Vertigo Questionnaire and the Numeric Pain Rating Scale scores improved. The number of vertigo attacks was reduced.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Occlusal splint therapy is a favourable option to reduce aural symptoms of Ménière's disease and comorbid temporomandibular joint disorder, even if its pathophysiological mechanism remains elusive.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc24">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Intracystic papillary carcinoma in a male as a rare presentation of breast cancer: a case report and literature review</seg>
          <seg id="2">Introduction: The term "intracystic papillary ductal carcinoma in situ" has recently changed and is now more appropriately referred to "intracystic papillary carcinoma".</seg>
          <seg id="3">Intracystic papillary carcinoma in men is an extremely rare disease with only a few case presentations published in the literature so far.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Case presentation: We discuss a case of a 44-year-old Caucasian man with an intracystic papillary carcinoma treated with simple mastectomy, sentinel lymph-node biopsy and contralateral risk-reducing mastectomy.</seg>
          <seg id="5">These were followed by adjuvant radiotherapy of the breast.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Conclusion: Triple assessment (i.e. clinical examination and radiological and histological assessment) with a high level of clinical suspicion is necessary to diagnose intracystic papillary carcinoma in men due to its rarity.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Furthermore, genetic testing and risk-reducing mastectomy should also be considered in cases of a strong family history for male breast cancer.</seg>
          <seg id="8">A 44-year-old Caucasian man presented to the breast clinic with a 3-week history of a swelling in his left breast.</seg>
          <seg id="9">He also had a significant family history for breast cancer including a maternal grandmother, two of his maternal aunts and a maternal first cousin diagnosed with breast cancer.</seg>
          <seg id="10">On examination, a well-circumscribed, 2.5 cm swelling was palpable within an area of gynecomastia on the left chest wall.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Sonographically, a cystic mass with internal echoes was present without posterior acoustic shadowing.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Aspiration of the lesion revealed uniformly blood-stained fluid and a residual swelling persisted.</seg>
          <seg id="13">Cytology analysis of the aspirate confirmed the presence of atypical cells.</seg>
          <seg id="14">Mammography showed a circumscribed mass in the sub-areolar region of the left breast with partially obscured margins.</seg>
          <seg id="15">An irregular outline was noted on cranio-caudal view, but no spiculation or suspicious internal micro-calcifications were found.</seg>
          <seg id="16">A core biopsy of the lesion revealed atypical ductal hyperplasia, but no evidence of malignancy was seen.</seg>
          <seg id="17">In view of the atypical cells and residual swelling the lesion was excised.</seg>
          <seg id="18">Histological analysis revealed a lesion 2.5 cm × 1.8 cm × 1.2 cm in size.</seg>
          <seg id="19">The lesion comprised a papillary and solid proliferation of atypical cells within a large cystic space with a thick fibrous capsule (Figures 1, 2, 3) Haemorrhage was also noted within the cyst with changes consistent with the prior biopsy.</seg>
          <seg id="20">The margins were clear; there was no evidence of stromal or fibrovascular invasion.</seg>
          <seg id="21">The lesion displayed features of papillary DCIS and a diagnosis of intracystic papillary DCIS was made.</seg>
          <seg id="22">Immunohistochemistry showed oestrogen receptor (ER) and progesterone receptor (PR) positivity.</seg>
          <seg id="23">Completion left mastectomy with sentinel lymph-node mapping was carried out.</seg>
          <seg id="24">Contralateral risk-reducing mastectomy was also performed in view of the strong family history for breast cancer.</seg>
          <seg id="25">No evidence of further disease was detected in the mammary tissue and the sentinel node was clear.</seg>
          <seg id="26">Adjuvant radiotherapy (40 Gy in 25 fractions) was advised due to tumour extension close to deep margin.</seg>
          <seg id="27">Due to his significant family history for breast cancer, genetic testing was offered.</seg>
          <seg id="28">Breast-cancer gene 2 (BRCA2) mutation had been identified in a maternal aunt recently on the exon 24 insertion called c9481_9482insA.</seg>
          <seg id="29">It was very likely that this patient was a carrier of this BRCA2 mutation, which poses a small risk for him to develop prostate cancer.</seg>
          <seg id="30">He was therefore advised to undergo prostate-specific antigen (PSA) blood testing on a yearly basis.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc26">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Bariatric surgery is recognized as the most effective treatment for morbid obesity, maintaining a stable weight reduction in the long term and reducing comorbidities, with a favorable impact on mortality.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The aim of this study is to evaluate the complication rate and treatment techniques adopted in all patients undergoing bariatric surgery procedures in our center.</seg>
          <seg id="3">From May 2017 to March 2020, 91 patients with morbid obesity are admitted to the Department of Medical and Surgical Science of the University Hospital of Foggia undergoing bariatric surgery.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Seventyone patients underwent sleeve gastrectomy, nineteen gastric bypass and one mini-gastric bypass, five of these were redo operation procedures.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Regarding postoperative complications (8,8%), there were 1 gastric leak (1,09%), 4 bleedings (4,39%) - 1 intraluminal bleeding and 3 intra-abdominal bleedings, 2 port-sites infections (2,19%) and 1 haemoperitoneum (1,09%).</seg>
          <seg id="6">In our center we have also treated 3 cases of complications after bariatric surgery procedures performed in others centers.</seg>
          <seg id="7">There were no deaths.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Despite improvement in the performance of bariatric surgical procedures, complications are not uncommon.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Flexible endoscopy has become an essential tool in managing bariatric surgery patients and offers the benefit of providing both diagnostic and therapeutic applications. KEY WORDS: Bariatric surgery, Bleeding post-bariatric surgery, Complications bariatric surgery, Gastric bypass, Leak post-sleeve gastrectomy, Mini invasive approach, Sleeve gastrectomy.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc6">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">The aim of this study is to evaluate the factors that has an effect on Cecal Intubation time (CIT), and to define the relationship between quality of bowel preparation and body mass index (BMI).</seg>
          <seg id="2">The Boston Bowel Preparation Scale (BBPS) was used for the evaluation of bowel cleansing.</seg>
          <seg id="3">A total of 346 patients were included.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The time from anus to caecum was recorded as the time of the cecal intubation time.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Patients were defined under 3 subgroup BMI-1; ≤ 24.9, BMI-2; 25-29.9, BMI-3; ≥30.</seg>
          <seg id="6">The mean BMI of women was 29.30 4.25 and men were 26.19 6.14 (p&lt;0,001).</seg>
          <seg id="7">Mean Cecal Intubation time was 9.11 6.00 and 10.21 3.45 minutes for women and men (p=0.012).</seg>
          <seg id="8">Women with High BMI (≥30) have shorter Cecal Intubation time compared to women with BMI less than 30 (p=0001).</seg>
          <seg id="9">When BBPS evaluated, there was a significant difference in BMI-3 due to high scores compared to both BMI-1 and BMI-2 (p&lt;0.001).</seg>
          <seg id="10">In BMI-3 group, also women had significantly higher scores in terms of BBPS(p=0.006).</seg>
          <seg id="11">Also a negative correlation between BBPS and BMI with CIT has been found (r = - 0.371, p&lt;0.001 / r = -0.191 p&lt;0.001).</seg>
          <seg id="12">In our study, women gender and increased BMI has a positive impact on the quality of intestinal cleansing that is associated with shortened Cecal Intubation time. Body Mass Index, Colonoscopy, Cecal intubation.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc8">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Enterobius Vermicularis (EV) is the most commonly identified heminth incidentally found within the appendix of a clinically diagnosed appendicitis.</seg>
          <seg id="2">This simple presence of EV may cause appendicular colic, primarily affecting children, it is an important cause of negative appendicectomy.</seg>
          <seg id="3">We report a case of a young male who presented with clinical features of acute appendicitis. Laparoscopic appendicectomy was uneventful and pathologic examination revealed the presence of an EV infestation originating from the lumen of his vermiform appendix. KEY WORDS: Acute appendicitis, Diagnosis, Enterobius Vermicularis.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc31">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">The outbreak of the Covid-19 pandemic has seriously affected our society.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Governments have difficult situations by adopting strict and severe mitigation measures in order to contain the pandemic spreading.</seg>
          <seg id="3">These decisions influenced significatively people's behavior changing their habits and routines.</seg>
          <seg id="4">This study offers a statistical analysis of the incidence of the Maxillo-Facial traumas in Tuscany southern area, during the pandemic lockdown.</seg>
          <seg id="5">The statistical analyzed has been obtained comparing the maxillo-facial trauma occurrence during the Italian lockdown between the 9th of March and the 18th of May 2020 in comparison with same period of the five previous years. KEY WORDS: Covid-19, Italian covid-19, Maxillofacial surgery, Maxillofacial trauma, Pandemic, Surgery management, Trauma incidence in Italy.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc4">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Feline Calicivirus (FCV) is one of the most common viral pathogens in domestic cats worldwide.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The first report of FCV dates back to 1957, when FCV was isolated from the gastrointestinal tract of cats in New Zealand.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Subsequent reports recognised FCV as a cause of respiratory disease in cats, and at present, feline practitioners worldwide are daily confronted with cats suffering from suspected FCV.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The highly mutagenic nature of FCV and its high genetic plasticity enable the virus to successfully survive in the feline population, and pose a special challenge as regards the diagnosis, treatment, and prevention of FCV-induced disease.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Upper respiratory tract disease has been considered a common clinical sign of FCV infection.</seg>
          <seg id="6">A study from Switzerland demonstrated that oral ulcerations, salivation and gingivitis-stomatitis were more commonly associated with FCV infection than upper respiratory tract disease, and less than half of the cats suspected to have FCV infection were found to be FCV-positive.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Furthermore, a study investigating FCV isolates from Switzerland found some evidence that the genetic background of cats might influence their susceptibility to FCV infection.</seg>
          <seg id="8">This review article provides a comprehensive summary of the FCV literature, and integrates the results of recent research on FCV's genetic characteristics, the cellular and humoral immunity evoked by FCV vaccination and infection, the diagnosis of FCV, FCV prevention/vaccination, the risk factors associated with FCV, and the hygienic measures necessary in FCV-contaminated areas.</seg>
          <seg id="9">After each section, the key points are summarised, and relevant information is outlined to help feline practitioners in FCV diagnosis, treatment and prevention.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc35">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">The aim of this study was to evaluate the safety and efficacy of endoscopic submucosal dissection (ESD) of colonic polyps larger than 20 mm.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Between March 2017 and July 2019, a gastro-entero endoscopist team resected 24 large colorectal polyps measuring 20-35 mm in diameter using the ESD technique.</seg>
          <seg id="3">After the injection of a mixture of hydroxypropyl methylcellulose with dilute epinephrine and methylene blue into the submucosal layer, a circumferential incision was performed using an electrosurgical knife.</seg>
          <seg id="4">A total of 24 colorectal polyps (≥20 mm) from 20 patients were evaluated.</seg>
          <seg id="5">The mean age of the patients was 60 years; 16 patients were men and 4 patients were women.</seg>
          <seg id="6">The mean polyp size removed by colorectal ESD was 35.3 mm (range 20.0-70.1 mm), and all 24 polyps were larger than 2 cm (100%).</seg>
          <seg id="7">There were no cases of delayed bleeding after the colorectal ESD nor were there any post-surgery complications.</seg>
          <seg id="8">This study demonstrates the efficacy and safety of carrying out ESD of large polyps.</seg>
          <seg id="9">This is important because there is not a large body of literature on this subject in this specific population. Colonic polyps, Endoscopic submucosal dissection, Gastrointestinal endoscopy.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc3">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Meningiomas as anatomo-pathological entities were first described in the sixteenth century, but it was Harvey Cusching who in 1922 proposed to identify them with the term 'meningioma'.</seg>
          <seg id="2">They are the most common intracranial tumors, occur between middle and late age and prefer female sex.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The symptoms depend on their position with respect to the brain regions.</seg>
          <seg id="4">These are mostly benign neoplasms, but there are atypical and even malignant forms.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Plaque meningioma refers to a specific macroscopic aspect of the meningioma, due to diffuse dural involvement and usually with extracranial extension.</seg>
          <seg id="6">We report here a case of plaque convex meningioma with typical grade I. Key Words: En plaque, Meningioma, WHO Meningioma.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc1">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">The COVID-19 pandemic emergency forced the health system in Italy to implement an immediate reorganisation to support the care of tens of thousands of patients and to maintain the quality of care for patients with other pathologies, such as oncologic diseases.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The main goal of this study was to evaluate the impact of COVID-19 restrictions on the hospitalisation and post-operative rehabilitation of head and neck oncologic patients and to determine whether the introduction of new technologies such as video-communication may be useful to mitigate social distancing by close family members.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Fifty-one consecutive patients underwent surgery for head and neck cancer during the period of lockdown caused by the COVID-19 pandemic.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The data collected (post-operative pain, post-operative complications, duration of hospitalisation) were compared with those of 51 consecutive patients treated for head and neck cancer in the period immediately preceding lockdown.</seg>
          <seg id="5">The average duration of hospitalisation was longer in patients operated on in the COVID-19 period, and, in particular, among patients who underwent a more demanding rehabilitation protocol.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Despite this, our study did not show a significant difference in psychological aspects during hospitalisation.</seg>
          <seg id="7">The greatest difficulties that occurred in the COVID-19 period were met by a greater commitment from medical staff, allowing the quality of life of head and neck cancer patients during post-operative rehabilitation to be maintained at a similar level to that before the pandemic.</seg>
          <seg id="8">In the future, there will be a need for technological solutions to bring the patient closer to family members.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc19">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">The aim of this retrospective cohort study was to evaluate the efficacy of Superficial Musculoaponeurotic System (SMAS) flap technique to prevent Frey's Syndrome (FS) and improve aesthetic outcomes following superficial parotidectomy. A total of 140 patients were treated between January 2003 and December 2018 at the Maxillofacial Unit of Magna Graecia University of Catanzaro with Superficial Parotidectomy (SP) for benign tumor and divided in two groups: Group 1 (78 patients) underwent SMAS flap reconstruction of the parotid lodge through a modified facelift incision and Group 2 (62 patients) underwent to SP without the use of SMAS interposition through a Redon type incision. Significant statistical difference concerning FS, transient facial nerve injury, facial paralysis, salivary fistula, haematoma and skin deepness were found between Group 1 and Group 2, (0,00% vs 6,45% [p &lt; 0,036], 2,56% vs 16,12% [p = 0,005], 0,00% vs 9,67% [p= 0,006], 1,28% vs 9,67% [p= 0,044], 1,28% vs 19,35% [p = 0,0002]) respectively. No significant statistical differences between the two groups were observed about wound infections (3,84% vs 8,06% [p= 0,466]).</seg>
          <seg id="2">SP represents the gold standard for the surgical treatment of benign tumors of the parotid gland greater than 3,5 cm in size involving superficial portion of the gland, for the low rate of recurrences over time and lower incidence of transient or permanent facial paralysis to which this technique leads.</seg>
          <seg id="3">However, SP is not free from other complications such as FS, haematoma, salivary fistula and aesthetic results like facial contour deformity due to surgical site depression and visible scar.</seg>
          <seg id="4">A reconstructive technique to reduce the impact of complications after SP is the SMAS flap because its preparation is easy, contextual to the parotidectomy and increases a little the surgical time.</seg>
          <seg id="5">This study highlights the advantages of SMAS flap technique in reducing complications following parotid surgery, particularly FS, and in improving the quality of life.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Frey's Syndrome, Minor test, Parotid benign tumor, SMAS flap, Superficial parotidectomy.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc9">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">To investigate the relationship between risk of Benign Paroxysmal Positional Vertigo (BPPV) recurrence and hypothyroidism treated with hormone replacement therapy (HRT).</seg>
          <seg id="2">797 patients with idiopathic BPPV were divided into two groups: 250 patients with recurrence of BPPV (R-BPPV) and 547 patients without recurrence (NR-BPPV).</seg>
          <seg id="3">Regarding patients with thyroid disease on HRT, we collected serum test results of thyroidstimulating hormone (TSH), free triiodothyronine f-T3, free thyroxine f-T4, thyroglobulin antibodies (TG-Ab) and thyroid peroxidase antibodies (TPO-Ab).</seg>
          <seg id="4">Hypothyroidism in long-term HRT was found in 61/250 (24.4%) patients of the RBPPV group vs 79/547 (14.4%) of the NR-BPPV-group (p = 0.0006).</seg>
          <seg id="5">Hashimoto thyroiditis (HT) was associated with recurrence (p &lt; 0.0001). A significant correlation was found between recurrence and level of serum TPO-Ab (p = 0.0117) and TG-Ab (p = 0.0025), but not with mean serum TSH, f-T3 and f-T4.</seg>
          <seg id="6">We assume that patients with hypothyroidism in HRT have an increased risk of BPPV recurrence, which is particularly strong for patients with HT and positive thyroid antibodies, suggesting an association between autoimmunity and recurrent vertigo.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc7">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">The application of laparoscopic partial tubal resection with end-to-end anastomosis can reduce the incidence of persistent ectopic pregnancy.</seg>
          <seg id="2">We aim to compare the therapeutic effects of laparoscopic fenestration and laparoscopic partial tubal resection with end-to-end anastomosis in the treatment of tubal ectopic pregnancy.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The patients were randomly divided into the observation group (the group treated with laparoscopic partial tubal resection with end-to-end anastomosis, n=238) and the control group (the group treated with laparoscopic fenestration, n=213).</seg>
          <seg id="4">The average operation time, intraoperative blood loss, postoperative exhaust time and hospital stay were observed to evaluate the clinical effect.</seg>
          <seg id="5">In addition, the time required for the β-HCG to drop to normal level, the patency of the fallopian tubes and the ovarian function were observed in the two groups after the operation.</seg>
          <seg id="6">There was no significant difference between observation group operation time, intraoperative hemorrhagic amount, blood β-HCG recovery time and hospital time and control group (P &gt; 0.05).</seg>
          <seg id="7">The postoperative fallopian tube patency rate in the observation group was 67.58%, significantly higher than the control group (P &lt; 0.05).</seg>
          <seg id="8">In addition, there was no significant difference in ovarian function between the two groups.</seg>
          <seg id="9">The method of laparoscopic partial tubal resection with end-to-end anastomosis is more effective in the treatment of tubal ectopic pregnancy, and has less impact on ovarian function, which can effectively improve the probability of normal pregnancy after the operation. Fallopian tube, Ectopic pregnancy, Laparoscopic fenestration, Laparoscopic partial tubal resection with end-to-end anastomosis.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc28">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Complete heart block ensuing from a metastatic small cell carcinoma: a case report</seg>
          <seg id="2">Introduction: Notwithstanding the diagnostic and therapeutic advancements, the incidence of cardiac metastases has increased in recent decades.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Lung cancers are the most common primary malignant neoplasms with cardiac metastasis potential.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The clinical presentation of cardiac metastases is either silent or vague, and largely depends on the infiltrated location and tumor burden.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Although arrhythmias are not uncommon in metastatic cardiac tumors, complete heart block is relatively a rare manifestation.</seg>
          <seg id="6">We present a case of complete heart block due to a metastatic small cell carcinoma in a 67-year-old male of African origin.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Case presentation: A 67-year-old male of African origin from rural Tanzania was referred to us for expert management.</seg>
          <seg id="8">He is a retired agromechanic with over 30 years exposure to asbestos-containing brake linings.</seg>
          <seg id="9">His past medical history was unremarkable, but the family-social history was evident for a heavy alcohol intake and chronic cigarette smoking.</seg>
          <seg id="10">He presented with a 24-week history of progressive shortness of breath and an 8-week history of recurrent syncopal attacks coupled with a significant weight loss.</seg>
          <seg id="11">He had normal echocardiographic findings, however, the electrocardiogram showed features of complete heart block.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Chest X-ray showed a homogeneous opacification on the right side and computed tomography scan revealed a solid right lung mass with metastases to the liver, heart, bowels, and bone.</seg>
          <seg id="13">He underwent bronchoscopy, which revealed an endobronchial mass obstructing the bronchus intermedius.</seg>
          <seg id="14">Histological examination of a section of lung biopsy taken during bronchoscopy confirmed the diagnosis of a small cell carcinoma.</seg>
          <seg id="15">The patient underwent dual chamber pacemaker implantation with successful sinus rhythm restoration.</seg>
          <seg id="16">He made an informed refusal of chemotherapy and inevitably died 18 months post pacing.</seg>
          <seg id="17">Conclusions: Despite the advancements in medical diagnostics and management, lung cancers are often diagnosed in advanced stages, with an inevitable grave prognosis.</seg>
          <seg id="18">Small cell carcinoma has the potential to metastasize to the heart, resulting in complete heart block.</seg>
          <seg id="19">A 67-year-old male of African origin from the Kilimanjaro region north of Tanzania was referred to us for expert management.</seg>
          <seg id="20">He is a retired agromechanic with over 30 years exposure to asbestos-containing brake linings.</seg>
          <seg id="21">His past medical history was unremarkable, but the family-social history was evident for a heavy alcohol intake (5 units/day) and chronic cigarette smoking (20 pack years).</seg>
          <seg id="22">He presented with a 24-week history of progressive shortness of breath and an 8-week history of recurrent syncopal attacks.</seg>
          <seg id="23">Such complaints were associated with awareness of heart beat, easy fatigability, light headedness, dry cough, and weight loss (∼15 kg in 6 months).</seg>
          <seg id="24">There was a negative history of fever, night sweats, chest pain, visual disturbances, recurrent headaches, bone pain, vomiting, or diarrhea.</seg>
          <seg id="25">General examination revealed a wasted (BMI 17.6 kg/m2) man.</seg>
          <seg id="26">He had a sinus bradycardia of 32 beats/minute and blood pressure of 117/66 mmHg on cardiovascular examination.</seg>
          <seg id="27">Respiratory examination revealed features suggestive of right lung consolidation.</seg>
          <seg id="28">Other systems were essentially normal.</seg>
          <seg id="29">He underwent a number of hematological, biochemical, and serological tests, which revealed a normocytic normochromic anemia [hemoglobin (Hb) 11.1 g/dL] but otherwise normal.</seg>
          <seg id="30">His echocardiography (ECHO) was essentially normal, however the electrocardiogram (ECG) showed features in keeping with the diagnosis of CHB, Fig. 1.</seg>
          <seg id="31">Chest X-ray (CXR) showed a homogeneous opacification on the right side, and CT scan revealed a solid right lung mass with metastases to the heart, liver, bowels, and bone; Figs. 2, 3, 4, 5 and 6.</seg>
          <seg id="32">Furthermore, he underwent bronchoscopy, which revealed an endobronchial mass occluding the bronchus intermedius.</seg>
          <seg id="33">Histological examination of a section of lung biopsy taken during bronchoscopy confirmed the diagnosis of small cell carcinoma, Fig. 7.</seg>
          <seg id="34">Correspondingly, a histological section of heart muscle tissue revealed similar findings to lung biopsy.</seg>
          <seg id="35">The patient underwent dual chamber pacemaker implantation with successful sinus rhythm restoration.</seg>
          <seg id="36">He made an informed refusal of chemotherapy and inevitably died in his home village 18 months post pacing.</seg>
          <seg id="37">We received the death information from his son via a phone call, and an autopsy was not practical.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc41">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Thyroid nodules with indeterminate cytology represent 20% of all thyroid nodules.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Inflammation plays an important role in cancer.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Lymphocyte-to-monocyte ratio (LMR), neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio (NLR) and platelet-to-lymphocyte ratio (PLR) are independent prognostic scores in numerous cancers, although no study has documented their role in cytology indeterminate nodules.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The aim of this study is to evaluate the role of LMR, NLR and PLR values as predictors of malignancy in patients with cytology indeterminate nodules.</seg>
          <seg id="5">This retrospective study analysed data from 298 patients with indeterminate thyroid nodule.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Anatomopathological and haematological data were analysed, dividing the population into two groups.</seg>
          <seg id="7">LMR, NLR and PLR values were determined using ROC curve and data were analysed using independent samples t-test, test of proportions, Fisher's exact test and univariate and multivariate logistic regression.</seg>
          <seg id="8">We found that a baseline LMR value ≥ 4.09 was indicative of benignity of indeterminate nodule.</seg>
          <seg id="9">The probability of malignancy in patients with LMR &lt; 4.09 was 26 times higher than patients with a LMR value ≥ 4.09.</seg>
          <seg id="10">This study showed that only LMR has shown a concrete probability to find a thyroid cancer in patients with indeterminate nodules. Further studies are necessary to implement tailored treatment.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc39">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Anthelmintic resistance (AR) of ruminant gastrointestinal nematodes (GINs) constitutes a major problem worldwide.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Among GINs, the abomasal blood-feeding parasite Haemonchus contortus is particularly pathogenic and may show resistance against all major anthelmintic substance classes.</seg>
          <seg id="3">In the present study, the death of a 1,5 year-old European bison (Bison bonasus) from a German wildlife park due to haemonchosis despite frequent anthelmintic treatment of the herd with fenbendazole as well as doramectin prompted an investigation regarding AR.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Pooled faecal samples were collected from four different bison groups as well as from mouflons (Ovis orientalis), elk (Alces alces), reindeer (Rangifer tarandus), sika deer (Cervus nippon), Persian fallow deer (Dama mesopotamica) and red deer (Cervus elaphus) housed by the wildlife park.</seg>
          <seg id="5">After coproscopical examination, faecal larval cultures were established.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Haemonchus contortus-positive larval cultures were further examined for genetic polymorphisms associated with benzimidazole resistance at codons 167 and 200 of the β-tubulin isotype 1 gene by real-time pyrosequencing.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Infections with H. contortus were detected in all four bison groups, as well as in mouflons.</seg>
          <seg id="8">In five samples, representing two bison groups and the mouflons, the frequency of the resistance-associated single-nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) at codon 200 was 100%.</seg>
          <seg id="9">In contrast, resistance-associated SNPs were not detected at codon 167.</seg>
          <seg id="10">In addition, faecal egg counts from two bison before and 14 days after parenteral doramectin treatment indicated possible macrocyclic lactone resistance.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Detection of anthelmintic resistant nematodes in these animals was especially concerning in the light of planned reintroduction into the wild.</seg>
          <seg id="12">As helminth control in zoological gardens and wildlife parks relies mostly on anthelmintic treatment due to restricted possibilities regarding management practices such as rotational grazing, care should be taken to avoid underdosing or unnecessary frequent treatments facilitating the development of AR.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc14">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">X-ray Reconstruction of Moving Morphology (XROMM) permits researchers to see beneath the skin, usually to see musculoskeletal movements.</seg>
          <seg id="2">These movements can be tracked and later used to provide information regarding the mechanics of movement.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Here, we discuss '&lt;i&gt;IK marker-guided rotoscoping&lt;/i&gt;'-a method that combines inverse kinematic solvers with that of traditional scientific rotoscoping methods to quickly and efficiently overlay 3D bone geometries with the X-ray shadows from XROMM data.</seg>
          <seg id="4">We use a case study of three Nile crocodiles' (&lt;i&gt;Crocodylus niloticus&lt;/i&gt;) forelimbs and hindlimbs to evaluate this method.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Within these limbs, different marker configurations were used: some configurations had six markers, others had five markers, and all forelimb data only had three markers.</seg>
          <seg id="6">To evaluate IK marker-guided rotoscoping, we systematically remove markers in the six-marker configuration and then test the magnitudes of deviation in translations and rotations of the rigged setup with fewer markers versus those of the six-marker configuration.</seg>
          <seg id="7">We establish that IK marker-guided rotoscoping is a suitable method for 'salvaging' data that may have too few markers.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc30">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">An oesophageal tube feeder was used to administer milk to six clinically healthy calves every 12 hours for a total of three feedings.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The calves were seven to nine days of age, and each feeding consisted of a volume of milk that was 6 % of the body weight of the calves.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The reticulum and abomasum were scanned ultrasonographically before, during and after drenching.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Blood samples for D-lactate determination and venous blood gas analysis were collected at -12, 0 (first drenching), 6, 12 (second drenching), 18, 24 (third drenching), 30 and 36 hours.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Ruminal fluid was collected for measurement of pH and D-lactate concentration at -12 and 36 hours.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Based on simultaneous ultrasonographic examinations of the reticulum and abomasum, some of the force-fed milk flowed into the reticulum and some directly into the abomasum; both organs contained milk immediately after drenching.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Drenching led to ruminal acidosis evidenced by a significant decrease in median pH from 7,0 (6,0 - 7,0) to 4,5 (3,0 - 5,0) and a 93-fold increase in median D-lactate concentration from 0,39 (0,14 - 1,33) to 36,3 (17,9 - 53,3) mmol/l but it did not cause metabolic acidosis.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Based on these findings, we concluded that milk administered to calves via an oesophageal tube feeder flows into the reticulum and abomasum simultaneously and three force feedings 12 hours apart cause acute ruminal acidosis, which was not accompanied by metabolic acidosis in the short term.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc23">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Cochlear fistula (CF) is a rare finding, usually associated with extensive middle ear cholesteatoma.</seg>
          <seg id="2">There is agreement on the fact that removing the cholesteatoma matrix on a CF exposes the ear to a high risk of sensorineural hearing loss or dead ear.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The aim of the study is to describe the presentation, possible treatment strategies and related outcomes for patients with CF in chronic otitis media (COM).</seg>
          <seg id="4">The study considers a retrospective case series of patients with CF diagnosis supported by CT-scan and intraoperative/otoscopic evidence.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Five cases of CF were identified, 4 associated with cholesteatoma and 1 associated with non-cholesteatomatous COM.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Two patients presenting with anacusis underwent a subtotal petrosectomy. Two patients with useful hearing underwent a radical mastoidectomy in order to preserve the cholesteatoma matrix on the promontorium.</seg>
          <seg id="7">One patient with good hearing and COM was treated conservatively.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Conservative management should be considered for rare cases of CF in COM with residual hearing.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Matrix preservation through radical/modified radical mastoidectomy is strongly advised in the presence of useful preoperative bone conduction.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Subtotal petrosectomy should be considered the preferred option in presence of cholesteatoma with preoperative profound hearing loss.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc21">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Oxaliplatin-induced thrombotic microangiopathy: a case report</seg>
          <seg id="2">Background: Oxaliplatin-based chemotherapy represents a standard of care in the treatment of metastatic colorectal cancer.</seg>
          <seg id="3">We report a rare case of fulminant oxaliplatin-induced thrombotic microangiopathy, clinically suggestive of hemolytic-uremic syndrome, occurring in a female patient with a prolonged history of exposure to oxaliplatin for the treatment of metastatic colon cancer.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Case presentation: A 73-year-old Caucasian female with a treatment history including several lines of chemotherapy for the management of metastatic colon cancer was reinitiated on chemotherapy with oxaliplatin, fluorouracil, and leucovorin with bevacizumab for disease progression.</seg>
          <seg id="5">She presented to the emergency department with malaise, headache, vomiting, and decreased urine output appearing a few hours after chemotherapy administration.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Clinical symptoms and laboratory findings were suggestive of thrombotic microangiopathy, with a triad of microangiopathic hemolytic anemia, pronounced thrombocytopenia, and acute renal failure.</seg>
          <seg id="7">The predominance of the severe renal failure was evocative of hemolytic-uremic syndrome.</seg>
          <seg id="8">The rapid development of the thrombotic microangiopathy was linked to exposure to oxaliplatin.</seg>
          <seg id="9">The patient was promptly managed with daily plasma exchange and high-dose corticosteroids, platelet, and red blood cell transfusions in conjunction with intermittent hemodialysis, and she recovered progressively.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Conclusion: Our case confirms the risk of hemolytic-uremic syndrome as a rare and life-threatening complication of oxaliplatin-based chemotherapy.</seg>
          <seg id="11">A dose-dependent, drug-induced toxicity mechanism is suggested.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Physicians need to maintain a high level of clinical suspicion to diagnose and treat this acute life-threatening disorder.</seg>
          <seg id="13">A 73-year-old Caucasian female, never smoker, with a past medical history of hypertension was diagnosed with stage IV colon adenocarcinoma with liver metastasis in October 2008.</seg>
          <seg id="14">She received chemotherapy with capecitabine, leucovorin, and oxaliplatin (XELOX) and bevacizumab for five cycles, then underwent a right hemicolectomy and a partial hepatectomy followed by maintenance therapy with bevacizumab.</seg>
          <seg id="15">In February 2011, she was initiated on fluorouracil, leucovorin, and irinotecan (FOLFIRI) and cetuximab for disease progression in the liver.</seg>
          <seg id="16">In May 2011, she underwent a resection of the new hepatic lesion followed by intra-arterial chemoembolization sessions for 3 months.</seg>
          <seg id="17">Three years later, in August 2014, a positron emission tomography–computed tomography (PET–CT) scan showed evidence of metastatic retroperitoneal lymphadenopathy, consistent with disease recurrence.</seg>
          <seg id="18">She was then initiated on mFOLFOX-6 with bevacizumab with a good imaging response, followed by a year of maintenance therapy with fluorouracil, leucovorin, and bevacizumab.</seg>
          <seg id="19">In December 2016, her treatment plan was switched to fluorouracil, leucovorin, and irinotecan (FOLFIRI) for disease progression to the lungs, followed by maintenance therapy with fluorouracil, leucovorin, and bevacizumab.</seg>
          <seg id="20">A few months later, in August 2017, a PET–CT scan showed a new lung nodule.</seg>
          <seg id="21">She was then shifted to mFOLFOX6 with panitumumab followed by maintenance therapy with fluorouracil and leucovorin.</seg>
          <seg id="22">In May 2018, the treatment protocol was changed to FOLFIRI with cetuximab, until a new disease progression in the lymph nodes, and then around the hepatic artery stent, occurred in January 2019.</seg>
          <seg id="23">The patient was then reinitiated on mFOLFOX6 with bevacizumab.</seg>
          <seg id="24">She received her first cycle on 21 February and later experienced an episode of neutropenia for which the second cycle was delayed.</seg>
          <seg id="25">On 11 March, she received her second cycle of chemotherapy with a 25% dose reduction.</seg>
          <seg id="26">On 13 March, she presented to the emergency department with fatigue, malaise, orbital headache, nausea and vomiting, mild abdominal pain, and chills.</seg>
          <seg id="27">She stated that her symptoms started hours after the chemotherapy infusion and reported a decrease in urine output and a darkening of urine.</seg>
          <seg id="28">On physical examination, the patient had jaundice with icteric sclera since a day ago.</seg>
          <seg id="29">Her vitals showed a temperature of 37.1 °C, a heart rate of 88 beats per minute, a respiratory rate of 18 breaths per minute, a blood pressure of 16.7/7.2 mmHg, and oxygen saturation of 100%.</seg>
          <seg id="30">A cardiac workup ruled out acute myocardial infarction.</seg>
          <seg id="31">The initial blood workup was significant for thrombocytopenia (platelet count 30.103 cells/mm3) and anemia (hemoglobin 8.1 mg/dL).</seg>
          <seg id="32">The anemia was defined as hemolytic by markedly increased bilirubin (total bilirubin 6.4 mg/dL, indirect bilirubin 3.3 mg/dL), high aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (1725 IU/L), high lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) (4866 IU/L), and low haptoglobin (&lt; 0.1 g/L).</seg>
          <seg id="33">The patient also showed signs of acute renal failure (serum creatinine had markedly increased from 0.9 to 5.5 mg/dL within a week, blood urea nitrogen (BUN) 78 mg/dL, and uric acid 10.6 mg/dL).</seg>
          <seg id="34">The blood film inspection showed signs of hemolysis with a slight anisopoikilocytosis, slight hypochromia, some ovalocytes and echinocytes, few schistocytes and helmet cells, rare teardrop red blood cells, and rare stomatocytes.</seg>
          <seg id="35">There were also occasional polychromatophilic red blood cells (reticulocytosis).</seg>
          <seg id="36">Antibody screening was negative, confirming the MAHA diagnosis.</seg>
          <seg id="37">The coagulation panel was normal.</seg>
          <seg id="38">Relevant laboratory parameters are documented in Table 1.</seg>
          <seg id="39">Her chronic medications included irbesartan/amlodipine and atenolol.</seg>
          <seg id="40">The clinical laboratory findings were consistent with thrombotic microangiopathy (TMA).</seg>
          <seg id="41">An ADAMTS13 activity test was performed to investigate a potential TTP, whereas the significant picture of the predominance of renal failure was more suggestive of HUS.</seg>
          <seg id="42">The occurrence of TMA after the chemotherapy session was suggestive of drug-induced thrombotic microangiopathy (DITMA), notably related to the administration of a chemotherapy agent.</seg>
          <seg id="43">Treatment was started promptly with daily plasma exchange and immunosuppression with methylprednisolone (1 mg/kg/day) until a diagnosis of TTP was ruled out, then tapered later on.</seg>
          <seg id="44">She also received packed red blood cell transfusions and platelet transfusions, and underwent daily intermittent hemodialysis.</seg>
          <seg id="45">Electrolyte imbalances were also managed.</seg>
          <seg id="46">Seven days later, the patient’s laboratory studies (Table 1) showed a stable hemoglobin level, a much-improved platelet count, and no clinical evidence of hemolysis.</seg>
          <seg id="47">Her platelet count normalized on day 12.</seg>
          <seg id="48">Daily plasma exchange was continued for eight consecutive days, and dialysis for eight consecutive days.</seg>
          <seg id="49">The patient was transferred to another medical center in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia (KSA) for continuity of care and possible treatment of the DITMA with eculizumab.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc10">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Development and validation of a confocal laser endomicroscopy (CLE) classification score for the larynx and pharynx.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Thirteen patients (154 video sequences, 9240 images) with laryngeal or pharyngeal SCC were included in this prospective study between October 2020 and February 2021.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Each CLE sequence was correlated with the gold standard of histopathological examination.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Based on a dataset of 94 video sequences (5640 images), a scoring system was developed.</seg>
          <seg id="5">In the remaining 60 sequences (3600 images), the score was validated by four CLE experts and four head and neck surgeons who were not familiar with CLE.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Tissue homogeneity, cell size, borders and clusters, capillary loops and the nucleus/cytoplasm ratio were defined as the scoring criteria.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Using this score, the CLE experts obtained an accuracy, sensitivity, and specificity of 90.8%, 95.1%, and 86.4%, respectively, and the CLE non-experts of 86.2%, 86.4%, and 86.1%.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Interobserver agreement Fleiss' kappa was 0.8 and 0.6, respectively.</seg>
          <seg id="9">CLE can be reliably evaluated based on defined and reproducible imaging features, which demonstrate a high diagnostic value.</seg>
          <seg id="10">CLE can be easily integrated into the intraoperative setting and generate real-time, in-vivo microscopic images to demarcate malignant changes.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc33">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">The aim of this study is to analyse clinical characteristics of FB ingestion and predictive factors for complications, in order to reduce mortality and morbidity.</seg>
          <seg id="2">A retrospective study of emergency surgical consultation records has been carried out from June 2005 through June 2015 yielded 201 episodes with the diagnosis of ingestion of foreign objects at the Surgical Unit of the University of Bari.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Natural Removal in 44,8% of cases; Endoscopic retrieval in 42,4%, Surgical Procedures 4,4%.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Statistical analysis was based on multivariate analysis and the model R2 of the Naegelkerke value.</seg>
          <seg id="5">First of all, the approach to ingestion should be endoscopic.</seg>
          <seg id="6">The second approach is surgical in selected cases.</seg>
          <seg id="7">The most frequent site of impaction were oesophagus, stomach and right colon.</seg>
          <seg id="8">An EGD proved to be the most used procedure with a no morbidity and no mortality.</seg>
          <seg id="9">The ingestion of foreign bodies is a frequent, complex and expensive condition to treat.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Observation and endoscopy are the most appropriate procedures to be considered to manage the ingestion of FB in Emergency Surgery Unit.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Emergency surgery, Foreign bodies, Ingestion.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc12">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Setaria tundra is known as a common parasite of sylvatic ungulates in Northern latitudes.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Although mostly considered of low pathogenicity, severe disease outbreaks and remarkable economic losses have been observed in reindeer (Rangifer tarandus tarandus).</seg>
          <seg id="3">Host density and climatic factors are major drivers of the expansion of Setaria spp.</seg>
          <seg id="4">facilitating their development and spread.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Five adult specimens of S. tundra were retrieved from a male roe deer in Bavaria, Germany.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) barcoding confirmed morphological identification.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Cyclooxygenase 1 gene sequences showed 98,73-99,68 % similarity to sequences of other S. tundra specimens found in deer (Cervidae) and mosquitoes (Culicidae).</seg>
          <seg id="8">The results raise awareness for the presence of S. tundra in a hitherto unkown endemic region and represent a starting point for broader investigations to understand the biology and distribution of this parasite in roe deer as well as other potential definitive hosts.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc36">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Appendicular schwannoma is a rare benign neoplastic proliferation of the appendicular Schwann cells.</seg>
          <seg id="2">It is often asymptomatic until it occludes the appendicular lumen thus causing appendicitis-like symptoms.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The neoplastic proliferation of the Schwann cells, although benign, may rarely degenerate into a malignant neoplasm, thus denoting the importance of diagnosis.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Some Authors in the Literature used the term 'neuroma' or 'neurinoma' to indicate either a hyperplastic proliferation of the Schwann cells or its neoplastic but benign proliferation, thus raising the important question of a probable mistaking of these two different histologic entities.</seg>
          <seg id="5">The hyperplastic proliferation is usually subsequent to a chronic appendicular inflammation, and it is a more common finding in specimen of appendectomy.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Aim of the study is to review the published scientific papers about the rare histologic entity of appendicular schwannoma and to define the not clear aspects of Schwann cell neoplasia versus hyperplasia.</seg>
          <seg id="7">A review of the Literature from Medline/Pubmed has been accomplished.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Forty-four studies from the Literature resulted suitable for our study.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Appendicular schwannoma has to be considered in patients with recurrent right lower quadrant pain, and may affect the patient's prognosis if it remains undiagnosed, since it may degenerate in malignancy.</seg>
          <seg id="10">There is a lack of clarity in the Literature about the distinction between the hyperplastic and the neoplastic benign Schwann cells proliferation, which must be clarified.</seg>
          <seg id="11">The meaning of the terms 'neuroma' and 'neurinoma' should be standardized, the first referring to the hyperplastic proliferation, and the second to the neoplastic but benign proliferation of the Schwann cells. Appendiciis, Appendectomy, Appendicular neuroma, Appendicular neurinoma, Appendicular schwannoma.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc32">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">We present the clinical observation of a female patient with cystic peritoneal malignant mesothelioma developed in the thickness of the abdominal wall.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The diagnosis included several steps: tumor classification as mesothelioma, tumor differentiation from reactive mesothelial hyperplasia, establishment of the malignant nature and differentiation from other malignant peritoneal tumors.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Relapse in about one year after surgery and about six months after the end of chemotherapy also claim malignancy of the tumor.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The particular tumor location in the thickness of the abdominal muscles, seemingly without involvement of the parietal peritoneum, in a patient with a history of caesarean operation, questions its development out of ectopic tissue embedded in scar from previous surgery. KEY WORDS: Abdominal wall, Caesarian operation Cystic malignant peritoneal mesothelioma, CK5/6, p53.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc43">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">The prevalence of methicillin-resistant Macrococcus spp.</seg>
          <seg id="2">in calves and pigs at slaughterhouses and in retail beef and pork meat was determined using samples taken in 2019 within the framework of the national monitoring of methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus in food producing animals in Switzerland.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The isolates were submitted to antimicrobial susceptibility testing of 19 antibiotics and to molecular techniques (e.g. PCR, microarray, WGS) for the identification of resistance genes, elements containing the methicillin resistance genes mec and sequence type (ST).</seg>
          <seg id="4">Methicillin-resistant Macrococcus spp. (M. caseolyticus (n=38), M. bohemicus (n=4) and Macrococcus spp. (n=2)) were isolated in 40 of 299 nasal swabs from calves representing a prevalence of 13,38 % (95 % CI, 9,98 % - 17,70 %), and in four of 303 nasal swabs from pigs [1,32 % (95 % CI, 0,36 % - 3,35 %)].</seg>
          <seg id="5">One of 311 samples of Swiss pork meat contained a Macrococcus sp. [0,32 % (95 % CI, 0,01 % - 1,78 %)], and four of 309 beef meat samples (260 domestic and 49 imported) contained M. caseolyticus [1,29 % (95 % CI, 0,35 % - 3,28 %)].</seg>
          <seg id="6">The M. caseolyticus strains belonged to diverse STs, with ST21 being the most common in both pigs and calves.</seg>
          <seg id="7">The mecD gene was located on Macrococcus resistance island mecD (McRImecD) in 42 strains and on staphylococcal cassette chromosome mec (SCCmecD) in three strains, while mecB was found on plasmids in four strains.</seg>
          <seg id="8">In addition to resistance to β-lactams, the strains also exhibited resistance to tetracycline (n=17; tet(L), tet(K), tet(M)), streptomycin (n=13; str, ant(6)-Ia, rpsL mutation [K56R in ribosomal protein S12]), kanamycin (n=10; aac(6')-Ie - aph(2'')-Ia, aph(2')-Ib, aph(2')-Ic, ant(4')-Ia), clindamycin (n=9; erm(B), erm(45)), erythromycin (n=9; erm(B), msr(G), erm(45)), fusidic acid (n=9; fusC) and gentamicin (n=1; aac(6')-Ie - aph(2'')-Ia).</seg>
          <seg id="9">This study represents the first national prevalence study of methicillin-resistant Macrococcus spp.</seg>
          <seg id="10">in pigs, calves, pork and beef meat in Switzerland and revealed a reservoir of genetically diverse strains carrying several resistance traits.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc38">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Work-related musculoskeletal disorders are among the main occupational health problems.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Substantial evidence has shown that work-related physical risk factors are the main source of low back complaints, particularly affecting heavy and repetitive manual lifting activities.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The aim of the study is, during load lifting tasks, to explore the correlation between the time domain features extracted from the acceleration and angular velocity signals of the performing subject and the load lifted, and to explore the feasibility of a multiple linear regression model to predict the lifted load.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The acceleration and angular velocity signals were acquired along the three directions of space by means of an inertial sensor placed on the subject's chest, during lifting activities with load gradually increased by 1 kg from 0 kg to 18 kg.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Successively three time-domain features (Root Mean Square, Standard Deviation and MinMax value) were extracted from the acquired signals.</seg>
          <seg id="6">First a correlation analysis was carried out between each individual feature and the load lifted (calculating r); then the time-domain features that proved most representative (strong correlation) were used to create a multiple linear regression model (calculating R-square).</seg>
          <seg id="7">The statistical analysis was carried out by means of the Pearson correlation and multiple linear regression model was fed with the most informative time-domain features according to the correlation analysis.</seg>
          <seg id="8">The correlation analysis showed a strong correlation (r &gt; 0,7) between six features (three extracted from z-axes acceleration and three extracted from y-axes angular velocity) and the lifted load.</seg>
          <seg id="9">The predictive multiple linear regression model, fed with these six features achieved a Rsquare greater than 0,9.The study demonstrated that the proposed combination of kinematic features and a multiple regression model represents a valid approach to automatically calculate the load lifted based on raw signals obtained by means of an inertial sensor placed on the chest.</seg>
          <seg id="10">The results confirm the potential application of this methodology to indirectly monitor the load lifted by workers during their activity.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc37">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Many factors that influence patient outcome in colorectal surgery are not editable, and these are related either the tumor, the patient and the treatment. The surgeon- and hospital-related factors are independent predictors of outcome for colorectal cancer surgery and these are supervision, teaching/training, specialization in colorectal surgery, high caseload, high hospital caseload. We evaluated the impact of the experience of 4 surgeons on the 5 years survival rate of patients with colon and rectal cancer and we valued if the surgeons' experience plays an equal role in both.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Four experienced surgeons operated 384 patients with colorectal cancer.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Surgeon with the major experience and colorectal-dedicated presented a slightly better total 5 years survival rate, comparing to other surgeons, although he had a considerably better 5 years survival rate in rectal operations.</seg>
          <seg id="4">We concluded that surgeon- and hospital-related factors directly influence the surgeon learning curve and are therefore rightly considered predictors of outcome in colorectal cancer surgery.</seg>
          <seg id="5">A low surgeon or hospital caseload may be compensated by intensified supervision or by improved training and teaching. Colon cancer, Colectomy, Surgeon volume.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc25">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Background and Aim. Starting from March 9, 2020, the Italian government has proclaimed a state of health emergency due to the epidemic, which later became a SARSCoV- 2 infection pandemic.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The present study aimed to perform differences and any potential risk factors in anxious and depressive symptoms in Italian nurses during the Covid-19 pandemic according to selected sociodemographic variables.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Methods.</seg>
          <seg id="4">In November 2020 an 'ad hoc' questionnaire was administered online to all Italian nurses.</seg>
          <seg id="5">In the first part, a whole series of socio-demographic variables relating to the reference sample were collected, as: gender, the department to which participants belonged, if the respondent suffered from pulmonary or cardiovascular diseases, if the nurse lived alone or with other cohabitants and whether during the pandemic the participant contracted the SARS-CoV-2 infection or not.</seg>
          <seg id="6">In the second part of the questionnaire, the Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale was administered to quickly and easily assess the anxiety and depression levels among the Italian nurses during the Covid-19 pandemic.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Results. 732 nurses agreed to participate to this survey.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Among participants, 479 (65.3%) recorded an anxious symptomatology and 267 (6.4%) a depressive one.</seg>
          <seg id="9">According to anxious symptoms, a significant difference was recorded between females and males (p min 0.001), as females recorded higher mild (24.04%), moderate (23.09%) and severe (13.39%) anxious symptom levels than males (Mild:1.50%; Moderate: 2.46%; Severe: 0.96%).</seg>
          <seg id="10">By considering depressive symptoms according to socio demographic variables, only nurses without cardiovascular diseases recorded higher frequencies in mild (21.58%), moderate (8.47%) and severe (2.46%) depressive symptoms than nurses who suffered from a cardiovascular disease (Mild:2.05%; Moderate: 1.64%; Severe: 0.27%).</seg>
          <seg id="11">Potential risk factors identified for anxious symptoms were: gender, both for mild (p min 0.001), moderate (p=.008) and severe (p=.003) anxious symptoms, and pulmonary diseases for severe anxious disorders (p=.014).</seg>
          <seg id="12">Potential risk factors identified for the onset of depressive symptoms were: gender (p=.026), pulmonary diseases (p=.021), domestic partnership (p=.035), for mild symptoms; the presence of cardiac diseases (p=.006) for moderate symptoms.</seg>
          <seg id="13">Conclusions.</seg>
          <seg id="14">It urged to begin to further implement all forms of psychological support for nurses and further implementation of university nursing training programs that aim at both the technical and psychological management of the future professional to cope with maxi emergencies.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc11">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Oral lichen planus (OLP) is a chronic inflammatory disease.</seg>
          <seg id="2">There are no markers that can be used to identify the risk of a malignant transformation of OLP to oral squamous cell carcinoma (OSCC).</seg>
          <seg id="3">Immunohistochemical staining was performed among 56 patients with OLP and 66 patients with OSCC for p53, HSP90 and E-cadherin expression and presence of HPV16/18.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Significant differences in p53 and HSP90 expression between OLP and OSCC were found (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.01 and &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.006, respectively).</seg>
          <seg id="5">A positive correlation between HSP90 and p53 expression was seen in OLP (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.017).</seg>
          <seg id="6">Univariate analysis identified HSP90 expression and HPV16/18 presence as prognostic factors for overall survival time (OS) (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.05).</seg>
          <seg id="7">In multivariate analysis, only HSP90 expression was an independent prediction factor for shorter OS of OSCC patients (&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; = 0.016).</seg>
          <seg id="8">The present study suggests that cooperation between p53 and HSP90 as well as between HPV16/18 and HSP90 exists in OLP and may affect the biological behaviour of OLP.</seg>
          <seg id="9">The observed expression of HSP90 and p53 in OLP and their increase in OSCC suggests that these proteins participate in the malignant transformation of OLP.</seg>
          <seg id="10">HSP90 may be a potential independent prognostic biomarker that can predict poor prognosis in OSCC.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc22">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">The development of acute pancreatitis is multifactorial requiring predisposition and relevant injury.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Viral acute pancreatitis has been described in other viral infections.</seg>
          <seg id="3">However, pancreatic involvement in SARS-CoV-2 infection is still poorly defined.</seg>
          <seg id="4">The present comparative study reports the patients with acute pancreatitis during the COVID-19 pandemic and last year covering the same period to appraise the link between COVID-19 and acute biliary pancreatitis.</seg>
          <seg id="5">The retrospective observational study was conducted in acute biliary pancreatitis patients from 13.03.19to13.09.19 and from 13.03.20to13.09.20 respectively. The study included 181patients(105patients in 2019;76 patients in 2020(during COVID-19 pandemic)).The patients were named as Group A(Normal period)and GroupB(Pandemic period),respectively.</seg>
          <seg id="6">The groups were found to be comparable as there was no significant difference between the mean age, sex, comorbidities, cholecystectomized, and recurrency.</seg>
          <seg id="7">There is no significant difference in the laboratory and radiological findings of GroupA and GroupB. However, there is a significant difference between the COVID-19 positive and negative patients in GroupB in terms of Glucose levels(p=0,025)and the presence of edema or necrosis in radiological images(p=0,046).There is a significant difference between the patients' number with abdominal pain of acute biliary pancreatitis in 2019and2020.(p=0)The length of stay was statistically significant in COVID-19 positive patients.(p= 0,013) CONCLUSIONS: Clinicians involved in the management of acute pancreatitis should be aware of its existence in the context of COVID-19.Understanding of the disease process and clinical manifestations of COVID-19 is still developing.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Awareness of these issues and addressing them adequately will be crucial for the management.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Acute Biliary Pancreatitis, Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2).</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc40">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Early diagnosis of cochlear implant failures (CIF) is a critical part of post-implantation follow-up.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Diagnosis is challenging and time consuming.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Our study aimed to describe diagnoses of CIF with emphasis on soft failures (SF), focusing on symptoms, time from symptoms to replacement, and differences between SF and hard failures (HF).</seg>
          <seg id="4">A retrospective review of medical records in a tertiary care referral paediatric medical centre including all patients who experienced CIF during 2000-2020.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Of 1004 CI surgeries, 72 (7.2%) cases of CIF were included, of which 60 CIF were in children (mean age 3.1 years).</seg>
          <seg id="6">Twenty-five cases were due to HF, 26 SF, and 21 due to medical reasons.</seg>
          <seg id="7">Patients with SF were more likely to present with headache, dizziness, or tinnitus compared with those with HF.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Facial stimulation and disconnections were more common in implants from Advanced Bionics, dizziness and tinnitus in Cochlear, and poor progression in Med-El.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Mean time from symptoms to implant replacement surgery was longer in cases with SF compared to HF.</seg>
          <seg id="10">SF poses a diagnostic challenge.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Symptoms such as headache, dizziness, and tinnitus are common.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Diagnosis of failure should often be based on assessments of the implant and rehabilitation teams.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc2">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">The relationship between chronic rhinosinusitis, asthma and allergic rhinitis is well known, but only recently has the scientific community started to evaluate these as different manifestations of a common pathogenic phenomenon, considering them as a unified airway disease.</seg>
          <seg id="2">Twenty-two patients with chronic rhinosinusitis treated with endoscopic sinus surgery (ESS) were included in the study. Sino-nasal assessment questionnaire (SNAQ) investigating subjective evaluation of sino-nasal state was administered to patients, while objective evaluations included nasal endoscopy, sinonasal CT, skin prick tests, nasal cytology, spirometry, bronchodilator responsiveness testing and sputum eosinophil count. All tests were performed before surgery.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Two months after surgery, SNAQ questionnaire, nasal endoscopy, spirometry and bronchodilator responsiveness testing were repeated.</seg>
          <seg id="4">All patients had significant improvement of subjective status: mean SNAQ score decreased in all from 99.31 to 16.04. Mean Forced Expiratory Volume in the 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; second (FEV&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;) significantly improved after surgery from 3.23 to 3.45 L/s.</seg>
          <seg id="5">ESS achieved a beneficial effect on upper and lower airway status in patients with chronic rhinosinusitis with or without lower airway diseases.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc34">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">We describe the case of a 54-year-old man with a 20mm splenic aneurysm, who underwent laparoscopic aneurysmectomy, without splenic removal.</seg>
          <seg id="2">The residual splenic blood supply was assessed by using indocyanine green i.v. administration.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The patient presented at ED with abdominal pain, syncopal episode, and tachycardia.</seg>
          <seg id="4">A CT scan with contrast showed hemoperitoneum with a 20mm splenic aneurysm, which was located at the bifurcation of the splenic and left gastroepiploic artery.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Treatment and Outcome Laparoscopic surgery was then warranted. Abdominal exploration revealed a serohemorrhagic collection without active source of bleeding.</seg>
          <seg id="6">After opening the gastro-colic ligament and obtaining vascular control of the splenic artery, the aneurysm was clipped and resected.</seg>
          <seg id="7">No macroscopic modifications occurred to the spleen.</seg>
          <seg id="8">This finding was confirmed by intravenous administration of indocyanine green.</seg>
          <seg id="9">The operating time was 265 minutes. During the postoperative course, a grade A pancreatic fistula occurred.</seg>
          <seg id="10">The patient was discharged on postoperative day seventh. The management of true splenic artery aneurysms should be patient-tailored, considering the location of the aneurysm, operative risks and the patient's age, life expectancy and clinical status. The use of ICG in splenic surgery helps delineate the splenic parenchyma and evaluate residual splenic vascularization. Indocyanine Green, Laparoscopy, Mini-invasive Surgery, Splenic Artery Aneurysm.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc42">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Treatment of severe neutropenia with high-dose pyridoxine in a patient with chronic graft versus host disease and squamous cell carcinoma: a case report</seg>
          <seg id="2">Introduction: The differential diagnosis of neutropenia includes medications, infections, autoimmune diseases, and deficiencies of Vitamin B12 and folate.</seg>
          <seg id="3">The association of Vitamin B6 deficiency with severe neutropenia is a rare finding.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Case presentation: A 51-year-old Caucasian woman presented with fever and profound neutropenia (48 neutrophils/uL).</seg>
          <seg id="5">Her clinical history included non-Hodgkin lymphoma, in remission following treatment with allogeneic bone marrow transplantation, quiescent chronic graft-versus-host disease, and squamous cell carcinoma of the skin metastatic to cervical lymph nodes.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Medications included atenolol, topical clobetasol, Ditropan (oxybutynin), prophylactic voriconazole, prophylactic valganciclovir, Soriatane (acitretin), and Carac (fluorouracil) cream.</seg>
          <seg id="7">The bone marrow was hypocellular without metastatic cancer or myelodysplasia.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Neutropenia did not respond to stopping medications that have been associated with neutropenia (valganciclovir, voriconazole and Soriatane) or treatment with antibiotics or granulocyte colony stimulating factor.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Blood tests revealed absence of antineutrophil antibodies, normal folate and B12 levels, moderate zinc deficiency and severe Vitamin B6 deficiency.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Replacement therapy with oral Vitamin B6 restored blood vitamin levels to the normal range and corrected the neutropenia.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Her cervical adenopathy regressed clinically and became negative on scintography following Vitamin B6 therapy and normalization of the blood neutrophil count.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Conclusion: Severe pyridoxine deficiency can lead to neutropenia.</seg>
          <seg id="13">Screening for Vitamin B6 deficiency, along with folate and Vitamin B12 levels, is recommended in patients with refractory neutropenia, especially those with possible malabsorption syndromes, or a history of chronic-graft-versus host disease.</seg>
          <seg id="14">Severe neutropenia may facilitate progression of squamous cell carcinoma.</seg>
          <seg id="15">The patient was a 51-year-old Caucasian woman with relapsed non-Hodgkin lymphoma treated four years earlier with an allogeneic stem cell transplant.</seg>
          <seg id="16">Her lymphoma was in remission.</seg>
          <seg id="17">Complications of her allogeneic transplant included a history of chronic extensive graft-versus-host disease (GvHD) involving the skin and dermal squamous cell carcinoma.</seg>
          <seg id="18">Immunosuppression with cyclosporine had been discontinued two months earlier due to the development of squamous cell carcinoma and the absence of active GvHD.</seg>
          <seg id="19">She had no history of smoking, alcohol, or drug abuse.</seg>
          <seg id="20">She presented with fever and profound neutropenia; serial blood counts showed that the neutropenia had been present for more than a month (Figure 1).</seg>
          <seg id="21">Her examination showed moderate cachexia, long-standing sclerodermatous changes and hyper-pigmentation of the skin consistent with quiescent GvHD, palpable 2.5 cm left cervical and submandibular adenopathy that was flurodeoxy glucose (FDG) avid on positron emission tomography/computerized tomography (PET/CT) scan.</seg>
          <seg id="22">She had a non-focal neurological examination.</seg>
          <seg id="23">A complete blood count showed a normal total leukocyte count (4,600/uL) with 2% granulocytes (48 neutrophils/uL) together with 84% lymphocytes and 14% monocytes.</seg>
          <seg id="24">Red blood cells were 4.24 × 10E12/L, hemoglobin was 12.4 g/dL, hematocrit was 0.37, and the platelet count was 113 × 10E9/L.</seg>
          <seg id="25">Medications included atenolol, topical clobetasol, Ditropan (oxybutynin), prophylactic voriconazole, prophylactic valganciclovir, Soriatane (acitretin), and Carac (fluorouracil) cream.</seg>
          <seg id="26">Blood cultures showed a micrococcus species.</seg>
          <seg id="27">Her iron level was 330 mcg/L with 20% saturation.</seg>
          <seg id="28">Folate, vitamin B1, vitamin B12, copper, vitamin D levels, thyroid function tests, creatinine, bilirubin, liver enzymes and lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) were normal.</seg>
          <seg id="29">Her blood zinc level was borderline low at 49 mcg/dL.</seg>
          <seg id="30">Antineutrophil antibodies were absent (&lt;1:10 titer).</seg>
          <seg id="31">PCR tests for cytomegalovirus (CMV) and Epstein Barr virus (EBV) in the blood were negative, and had remained negative on prophylactic doses of valganciclovir following CMV reactivation five months earlier.</seg>
          <seg id="32">Her vitamin B6 level was very low at 0.5 ng/mL (reference range 5 to 30 ng/mL).</seg>
          <seg id="33">Serum IgG was polyclonally elevated at 3720 mg/dL as were blood T-cells (4580 cells/uL) and CD8+ T-cells (2836 cells/uL) with normal numbers of CD4+ T-cells, B-cells and natural killer (NK) cells.</seg>
          <seg id="34">Her fever resolved with a course of vancomycin, without identifying a site of infection.</seg>
          <seg id="35">Histological examination of the marrow demonstrated marked hypocellularity without specific megaloblastic or myelodysplastic findings, metastatic cancer, or features to suggest immune-mediated thrombocytopenia.</seg>
          <seg id="36">Cytogenetic analysis showed 100% donor (male) cells without any clonotypic abnormalities.</seg>
          <seg id="37">Biopsy of a cervical lymph node showed poorly differentiated carcinoma, consistent with metastatic squamous cell carcinoma.</seg>
          <seg id="38">Valganciclovir, voriconazole, and Soriatane (acitretin) were discontinued (as potential causes of neutropenia) and prophylactic fluconazole and acyclovir were started.</seg>
          <seg id="39">Granulocyte colony stimulating factor (G-CSF; 300 ug subcutaneously every other day) was administered for four doses in mid February 2010 without any improvement in her neutropenia.</seg>
          <seg id="40">Following daily supplementation with 150 mg Vitamin B6, blood B6 levels normalized concomitant with resolution of the neutropenia (Figure 1).</seg>
          <seg id="41">Following correction of the B6 deficiency and neutropenia, the cervical adenopathy completely regressed by clinical examination and became scintographically negative by PET/CT.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc5">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Increased risk for thromboembolic events from combination of a gynecologic malignancy with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 infection: a case report</seg>
          <seg id="2">Purpose: During the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 pandemic, several patient groups are at particular risk.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Mortality is higher among cancer patients and may be increased further by thromboembolic events, which are more common in coronavirus 2019 patients according to recent publications.</seg>
          <seg id="4">We discuss the association of gynecologic malignancies, Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2, and thromboembolism by reporting a case study and summarizing available literature.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Case report: A 71-year-old Caucasian patient with ovarian cancer receiving first-line chemotherapy was diagnosed with deep vein thrombosis and pulmonary embolism.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Routine screening revealed infection with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 in absence of specific symptoms.</seg>
          <seg id="7">After uneventful recovery, oncologic treatment could be continued a few weeks later.</seg>
          <seg id="8">Methods: We performed a systematic review of the literature on PubMed following Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic reviews and Meta-Analyses guidelines.</seg>
          <seg id="9">The search included articles ahead of print, published between 1 December 2019 and 1 June 2020.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Cross-searches were conducted on all relevant articles.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Results: We identified five articles meeting the defined criteria, including two retrospective studies, a review, a position paper, as well as a letter to the editor.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Conclusion: Cancer patients infected with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 have a relatively poor outcome, which may partially be due to a higher rate of thromboembolic events.</seg>
          <seg id="13">Thromboprophylaxis is recommended, and scoring systems are helpful in early detection.</seg>
          <seg id="14">In cancer patients with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2, individual risk for thromboembolic events should be taken into account when considering interruption versus continuation of antitumoral therapy.</seg>
          <seg id="15">However, further data and studies are required.</seg>
          <seg id="16">A 71-year-old Caucasian woman, gravida 2/para 2, presented with pain in her lower left leg accompanied by progressive dyspnea in April 2020.</seg>
          <seg id="17">She had already received dabigatran prescribed by her general practitioner for suspected deep vein thrombosis (DVT) one day prior to her admittance.</seg>
          <seg id="18">The patient was undergoing multimodal treatment at our clinic for HGSOC FIGO IIIC.</seg>
          <seg id="19">Up to that point, she had received debulking surgery with macroscopic complete tumor resection in February 2020, including bilateral adnexectomy, hysterectomy, peritonectomy, infragastric omentectomy, pelvic and paraaortic lymphadenectomy, partial liver resection, and rectosigmoid resection.</seg>
          <seg id="20">Secondary wound closure could be achieved after treatment of wound dehiscence in March 2020.</seg>
          <seg id="21">First-line chemotherapy was initiated with carboplatin AUC 5 and paclitaxel 175 mg/m2 every 3 weeks.</seg>
          <seg id="22">After completion of the first course, we switched to weekly application of carboplatin AUC 2 and paclitaxel 80 mg/m2 to improve tolerability.</seg>
          <seg id="23">Three weekly courses of chemotherapy were administered without complications.</seg>
          <seg id="24">Initiation of bevacizumab was postponed due to delayed wound healing.</seg>
          <seg id="25">The patient reported a general feeling of weakness since surgery but was otherwise in a good state of health.</seg>
          <seg id="26">Her medical history included papillary thyroid cancer, successfully treated in 2008 by total thyroidectomy, and catheter ablation of the AV node because of atrioventricular nodal reentry tachycardia in 2015.</seg>
          <seg id="27">No other relevant cardiovascular or pulmonal diseases were known.</seg>
          <seg id="28">She had an uneventful gynecological and obstetrical history.</seg>
          <seg id="29">BRCA testing was negative, and there was no family history of gynecologic malignancies.</seg>
          <seg id="30">The patient did not smoke or drink alcohol regularly.</seg>
          <seg id="31">She was taking L-thyroxin, pantoprazole, and vitamin D as regular medication.</seg>
          <seg id="32">At current presentation, she was routinely asked for symptoms and risk factors for COVID-19 and negated symptoms such as fever, cough, headaches, loss of taste or smell, or recent international travel.</seg>
          <seg id="33">Her only contacts were close relatives as well as her general practitioner.</seg>
          <seg id="34">Clinical examination showed normal clinical conditions as well as normal vital functions (blood pressure 123/75 mmHg, temperature 36.9 °C, heart rate 87 /minute, oxygen saturation 98 %) but a slightly elevated respiratory rate (22 /minute).</seg>
          <seg id="35">Besides chronic anemia (hemoglobin 9.0 g/dl) and elevated infection parameters (C-reactive protein 8.1 mg/dl, ferritin 470 ng/ml), blood testing showed no relevant changes; especially, renal and hepatic function were normal.</seg>
          <seg id="36">Sonography revealed a mild urinary stasis on the left side.</seg>
          <seg id="37">For further diagnosis, we referred the patient to the angiology department of our clinic, where DVT of the left lower leg as well as a thrombophlebitis of the right great saphenous vein and venous thrombosis of the right gastrocnemius muscle vein were confirmed via color Duplex sonography.</seg>
          <seg id="38">We ordered chest computed tomography due to complaints of progressive dyspnea, revealing segmental PE in one central lung artery as well as in several subsegmental arteries (Fig. 1a).</seg>
          <seg id="39">No infiltrates, especially no changes typical for COVID-19, were seen (Fig. 1b).</seg>
          <seg id="40">We performed a nasopharyngeal swab as a routine screening test for SARS-CoV-2 upon hospitalization.</seg>
          <seg id="41">Surprisingly, it revealed infection with SARS-CoV-2 via reverse-transcription polymerase chain reaction (PCR) testing on the following day.</seg>
          <seg id="42">The woman was therefore isolated and transferred to the infectiology department of our clinic, where she was treated for ten more days.</seg>
          <seg id="43">As the patient was in a stable cardiopulmonal condition with no signs of right heart overload in echocardiography, conservative treatment with low-molecular-weight heparins (LMWH) at a therapeutic dosage and compression stockings was continued.</seg>
          <seg id="44">Respiratory parameters were sufficient with no need for oxygen therapy or further medication at any time.</seg>
          <seg id="45">An incidental urinary tract infection with Klebsiella pneumonia was sufficiently treated with cefpodoxim 400 mg per day for 10 days.</seg>
          <seg id="46">A repeat PCR test before discharge was negative.</seg>
          <seg id="47">The patient was quarantined at home for 14 more days.</seg>
          <seg id="48">Anticoagulant treatment was continued with apixaban for 6 months.</seg>
          <seg id="49">No further thromboembolic events occurred meanwhile.</seg>
          <seg id="50">With a therapeutic gap of 5 weeks, we continued chemotherapy with the weekly regimen.</seg>
          <seg id="51">For the next 2 courses, dose reduction to 75% was performed; full doses of carboplatin AUC 2 and paclitaxel 80 mg/m2 were resumed thereafter and well tolerated.</seg>
          <seg id="52">A lymphocele of the left lower abdomen which had caused progressive urinary stasis was drained complication-free 5 months later.</seg>
          <seg id="53">As bevacizumab was contraindicated because of prior VTE, oncologic maintenance therapy with niraparib 200 mg per day followed afterwards.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc15">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">Toxoplasmosis is a worldwide occurring zoonosis caused by the obligate intracellular parasite Toxoplasma gondii (T. gondii).</seg>
          <seg id="2">All warm-blooded species, including humans, serve as intermediate hosts.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Definitive hosts are exclusively cats.</seg>
          <seg id="4">Farm poultry can become infected with oocysts from contaminated feed or directly from the ground, or by pecking of e.g. infected rodents.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Outdoor or free-range housing of poultry increases the risk of infection with length of time.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Poulty meat must be seen as a potential source of infection for humans with the increasing popularity of humane animal husbandry practices in poultry farming.</seg>
          <seg id="7">This short literature review attempts to assess the current epidemiological situation in farmed poultry and to assess the possible relevance of toxoplasmosis of poultry meat and poultry meat products for human consumption.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
    <doc origlang="en" id="doc18">
      <src lang="en">
        <p>
          <seg id="1">This paper retrospectively reviews our experience with endovascular and hybrid treatments for subclavian artery aneurysms (SAA).</seg>
          <seg id="2">Seventeen patients with SAAs were treated at our center between July 2011 and October 2018.</seg>
          <seg id="3">Clinical and follow-up data were extracted from the hospital records and retrospectively reviewed.</seg>
          <seg id="4">We routinely use endovascular treatments and stenting or axillary-axillary bypass to treat SAA if vertebral artery blood flow requires restoration.</seg>
          <seg id="5">Patients were followed up at 3, 6, and 12 months after their operations and yearly thereafter.</seg>
          <seg id="6">Median follow-up was 30.5 months.</seg>
          <seg id="7">In 6 patients, the SAAs involved the ipsilateral vertebral artery. Simple coil embolization was performed for 1 patient; endovascular covered stenting and coil embolization for 4 patients; and hybrid treatment for 1 patient.</seg>
          <seg id="8">In 11 patients, the SAAs did not involve the ipsilateral vertebral artery.</seg>
          <seg id="9">Hybrid treatment was performed for 1 patient; thoracic aortic stent implantation with coil embolization for 1 patient; and covered stent placement in the subclavian artery for 9 patients.</seg>
          <seg id="10">Among the 9 patients who were symptomatic at presentation, 8 had relief of symptoms.</seg>
          <seg id="11">Leakage was observed in 1 patient, but it stopped spontaneously.</seg>
          <seg id="12">Stent occlusion occurred in 33% (3/9), but all were asymptomatic, and no interventions were necessary.</seg>
          <seg id="13">Endovascular and hybrid treatments appear to be effective for SAAs with few complications and good clinical outcomes. Covered stent, Coil embolization, Endovascular treatment, Hybrid, Subclavian artery aneurysm.</seg>
        </p>
      </src>
    </doc>
  </collection>
</dataset>
